export const data = [
  {
    Sheet2: [
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " Database",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " True",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " End Users",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " HTML",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " User-centered",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " Attribute",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " Constraint",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " Information Management System",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " SDM",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " entity",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " Data Redundance",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " True",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " account-no",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " Data Inconsistency",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " True",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " Entity set",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " Thing in real world",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " Attribute",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " Role",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " Composite attribute",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " Desciptive",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " Physical Level",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " Entity Relationship Model",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " entities",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above":
          " Storage space is wasted & Changing the data in one spot will cause data inconsistency",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above":
          " Is the recorded history of operations performed on a file",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " Database",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " High speed, large capacity disk",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above":
          " There is common sharing of data among the various applications",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " Metadata",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " All of the mentioned",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " Metadata",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " Data Dictionary",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " Instance",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " Tablespace",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " Segments",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " Extent",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " Database Block",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " Data dictionary",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " Database",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " Specification and body",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " Message digest",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " Three",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " Limited flexibility in accessing data",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " Primary key",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " Data independence",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " Hierarchical",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " Relational database",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " How tables are related in the database",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " MAX",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " DELETE",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " TRUNCATE",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " UPDATE",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " ROLLBACK and SAVEPOINT",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " SCL",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " ASC",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above":
          " DELETE does not free the space containing the table and TRUNCATE free the space containing the table",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above":
          " The AS SQL clause is used to change the name of a column in the result set or to assign a name to a derived column",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " Data Manipulation language",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName LIKE ‘%a’",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " SELECT * FROM Persons ORDER BY FirstName DESC",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " SELECT COUNT() FROM Persons",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above":
          " The SQL ALTER TABLE clause modifies a table definition by altering, adding, or deleting table columns and/or constraints",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " Update more than one row at a time",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " SELECT clause only",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " SELECT DISTINCT",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " ORDER BY",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above":
          " UPDATE Persons SET LastName=’Nilsen’ WHERE LastName=’Hansen’",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " COMMIT",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " ROLLBACK",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " SELECT city FROM weather WHERE humidity = 95",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above":
          " SELECT city, temperature FROM weather ORDER BY city",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " Feature has two 0’s in it, at any position",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " First",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " Eliminate all hidden dependencies",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above":
          " Lossless, dependency-preserving decomposition into BCNF is always possible",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " Key",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " Normalization",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " 3NF",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " 4NF",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " 3NF",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " 2NF and hence also in 1NF",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " Armstrong’s axioms",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " Pseudotransitivity rule",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " None of the mentioned",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " Both Lossy and Lossy-join decomposition",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " A->BC",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": 10,
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " Both I and II",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " 0 <= m <= min(r,s)",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " B, C",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " All of the above",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above":
          " Output specified attributes from all rows of the input relation and remove duplicate tuples from the output",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " Both the statements are true",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " On",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " Right outer join",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " 4 NF",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " Equality-generating dependencies",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " superkey",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " candidate keys",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " sorting",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " all of the options",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " domain",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " null<>0",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " database schema",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " database instance",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " union",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " project",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above":
          " it takes a list of values and returns a single value as a result",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " option a and b",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " drop table",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " select",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " composite attribute",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " atomicity, consistency, isolation, durability",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " third normal form",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " all of the options",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " unified modeling language",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " create information table in the database",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above":
          " every foreign-key value must match a primary-key value in an associated table",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " query",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " open database connection",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " generalized selection",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " drop table",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "Answer",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " left to right",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " functional dependency",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " all of the options",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " fourth",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " schema",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " candidate key",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " top – down approach",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " data integrity",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " all of the options",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " field-level lock",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " sub query",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " where data is placed on the screen",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above":
          " both storage space is wasted and changing the data in one spot will cause data inconsistency",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " all of the options",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " all of the above",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above":
          " is the recorded history of operations performed on a file",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " codasyl specification",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above":
          " both retrieve information from files and answer queries",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " it allows a many-to-many relationship",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above":
          " can be used to extract information stored in a computer file",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " db/dc dictionary",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " to collect and organize input data",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " modify",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " SQL",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " all of the options",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " separate files",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " bit-byte-field-record-file-database",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " look-up",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " reflex",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " hierarchical schema",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " oracle 7",
        Column3: 1,
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " data base",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " centralized mis structure",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " processing functions",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above":
          " there is common sharing of data among the various applications",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " none of the options",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " database",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " keeps its physical structure hidden from users",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above":
          " is generally stored on disk in an ASCII text format",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " all of the options",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " all of the options",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " dml",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " all of the options",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " in the MySQL database MySQL",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " auto_increment",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " tables",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " all options are correct",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " critical level",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " all options are correct",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " entity sets",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " schema",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " candidate key",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " second",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " transitive dependency",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " user view",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " top – down approach",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " data integrity",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " all of the above",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " field-level lock",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " sub query",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " committed",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " tuple",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " superkey",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " candidate keys",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " sorting",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " all of the above",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " all of the above",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " e",
        Column3: "f",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " domain",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " database schema",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " database instance",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " union",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " project",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above":
          " it takes a list of values and returns a single value as a result",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above":
          " select empid where empid = 1009 and lastname = ‘geller’;",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " virtual private database (VPD)",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " intention-exclusive (IX) mode",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " trim",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " row-level authorization",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " shared and intention-exclusive (SIX) mode",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " encryption",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " validation protocol",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " u",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " dictionary attacks",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " w-timestamp(q)",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " common",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " none of the mentioned",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " sql 2016",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " union all",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " symmetric key",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " is null",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " degree",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " dictionary attacks",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " database-level lock",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " having",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " advanced encryption standard",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " deadlock",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " inner",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " challenge–response system",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " like predicate",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " rollback",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " users see the data in one global schema",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " no-force",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " atomic",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " datafiles",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " no-force",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " committed",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " centralized mis structure",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " steal",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " flashback",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " oracle 7",
        Column3: 1,
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " dirty block",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " rollback",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " codasyl specification",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " prom chips",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " positive",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " data base",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " semiconductor",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " assertion",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above":
          " is the recorded history of operations performed on a file",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " intel 4004",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above":
          " create assertion 'assertion-name' check 'predicate';",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " database",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " magnetic bubble memory",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above":
          " improve the quality of data entered for a specific property (i",
        Column3: "e",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above":
          " there is common sharing of data among the various applications",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " registers",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " yyyy/mm/dd",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " child node can have any number of parent nodes",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " archival",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " index",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " object-relational data model",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " SQL",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " blob",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " metadata",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " fuzzy",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " create type",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " all of the mentioned",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " log number",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " cast",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " database application and the database",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " physiological redo",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " create table ",
        4: 2,
        Column5: " as",
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " metadata",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " dirty page table",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " catalogs, schemas",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " data dictionary",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " fuzzy-checkpoint",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " all of the mentioned",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " instance",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " attributes",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " superkey",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " candidate keys",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " sorting",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " all of the options",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " domain",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " null<>0",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " database schema",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " database instance",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " union",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " project",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above":
          " it takes a list of values and return a single values as result",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " option a and b",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " drop table",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " select",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " composite attribute",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " atomicity, consistency, isolation, durability",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " third normal form",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " all of the options",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " unified modeling language",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " create information table in the database",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above":
          " every foreign-key value must match a primary-key value in an associated table",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " query",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " open database connection",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " generalized selection",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " drop table",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "A",
        " all of the above": " left to right",
        4: 1,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " functional dependency",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " all of the options",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " fourth",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " schema",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " candidate key",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " top – down approach",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " data integrity",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "D",
        " all of the above": " all of the options",
        4: 4,
      },
      {
        D: "C",
        " all of the above": " field-level lock",
        4: 3,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " sub query",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above": " where data is placed on the screen",
        4: 2,
      },
      {
        D: "B",
        " all of the above":
          " both storage space is wasted and changing the data in one spot will cause data inconsistency",
        4: 2,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    Sheet3: [
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) Maximizing network throughput",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) Shortest Job First",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) Indexed allocation",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) Establishing, managing, and terminating sessions",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "A) The CPU is allocated to the process for a limited time.",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) A program in execution",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "A) Semaphore",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) Faster communication between threads",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) Each process is given a fixed time to execute, called a quantum",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "D) To translate virtual addresses into physical addresses",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) The division of memory into blocks that may cause wasted space",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) The address visible to the user",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) To manage computer hardware and software resources",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) Excessive paging causing a significant slowdown",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) To manage the data stored on disk drives",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "D) Both A and B",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) To determine the order of disk access requests",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) It allows multiple users to use the computer at the same time.",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) To allow user applications to request services from the operating system",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) To interpret and execute user commands",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) Air traffic control systems",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) File System",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) Simultaneous Peripheral Operations Online - managing data sent to devices like printers",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) The process of storing and restoring the state of a CPU so that a process can resume execution from the same point later",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) A kernel where all services run in kernel space",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) The process of starting up the operating system when the computer is turned on",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) To allow the operating system to communicate with hardware devices",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) Application development",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) Kernel mode allows direct hardware access, while user mode does not",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) Organizing and providing access to data files",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) A technique to simulate more memory than physically available using disk space",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) User passwords",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) The core part of the operating system that manages system resources",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) To reorganize fragmented data to improve file reading and writing speed",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) A method of dividing the memory into fixed-size blocks",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) The process spends more time doing input/output than computations",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) Protecting data from unauthorized access",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) Controlling the operations of an industrial robot",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "D) To allocate CPU time to various functions and processes",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) An interface for programs to interact with the operating system",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) Bit",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) A technique to allow multiple users or processes to use the system concurrently",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) The relative importance or urgency of a process in terms of CPU time",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) Round Robin (RR)",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) It replaces the page that has been used least recently",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) Basic Input Output System: It is responsible for initializing hardware and loading the operating system",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) A background process running on the system",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) The ability of the operating system to perform and manage multiple tasks at the same time",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "D) Hard Link is a mirror copy, Soft Link is a shortcut",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) To provide extra memory by using disk space",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) A small, modular kernel with minimal services in kernel space",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) RAM (Random Access Memory)",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) A situation where the behavior of software is dependent on the sequence or timing of other uncontrollable events",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "D) To hold all the processes that are ready to run or are waiting to run",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) ext4",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) The ability to run multiple threads within a single process",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) It loads pages into memory only when they are needed",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) The properties of Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Durability",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) To provide a standard interface for different file systems",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "A) Distributing work evenly across all available CPUs",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) A process that has completed execution but still has an entry in the process table",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) NTFS",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) Managing and preventing deadlock situations",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) To define who can read, write, or execute a file",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) Creates a new child process",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) When a process is unable to get necessary system resources due to other high priority processes",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "C) A non-recoverable system error detected by the kernel",
      },
      {
        "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system":
          "B) Redirecting the output of one command as input to another",
      },
    ],
  },
];

export const sheet1 = [
  {
    Question: "What is a semaphore in the context of operating systems?",
    "Option A": "A memory segment",
    "Option B":
      "A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system",
    "Option C": "A type of scheduling algorithm",
    "Option D": "A signal for process communication",
    Answer:
      "B) A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is NOT a goal of file management in operating systems?",
    "Option A": "Ensuring data consistency",
    "Option B": "Maximizing network throughput",
    "Option C": "Providing security and access rights",
    "Option D": "Organizing storage space efficiently",
    Answer: "B) Maximizing network throughput",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "In the context of CPU scheduling, what does SJF stand for?",
    "Option A": "System Job First",
    "Option B": "Shortest Job First",
    "Option C": "Sequential Job Filing",
    "Option D": "Shortest Journey First",
    Answer: "B) Shortest Job First",
    Topic: "CPU Scheduling",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following allocation methods is used in file systems for large files to minimize fragmentation?",
    "Option A": "Linked allocation",
    "Option B": "Contiguous allocation",
    "Option C": "Indexed allocation",
    "Option D": "Stack allocation",
    Answer: "C) Indexed allocation",
    Topic: "File Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the primary role of the session layer in the OSI model?",
    "Option A": "Encrypting data",
    "Option B": "Establishing, managing, and terminating sessions",
    "Option C": "Routing data between nodes",
    "Option D": "Data compression",
    Answer: "B) Establishing, managing, and terminating sessions",
    Topic: "OSI Model",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is a characteristic of preemptive scheduling?",
    "Option A": "The CPU is allocated to the process for a limited time.",
    "Option B": "Processes are executed on a first-come, first-serve basis.",
    "Option C": "Once a process starts, it runs to completion.",
    "Option D": "The user manually switches between processes.",
    Answer: "A) The CPU is allocated to the process for a limited time.",
    Topic: "CPU Scheduling",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is a 'Process' in the context of operating systems?",
    "Option A": "A thread of a program",
    "Option B": "A program in execution",
    "Option C": "A function call within the program",
    "Option D": "A segment of the hard disk",
    Answer: "B) A program in execution",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is a common synchronization mechanism?",
    "Option A": "Semaphore",
    "Option B": "Debugger",
    "Option C": "Compiler",
    "Option D": "Linker",
    Answer: "A) Semaphore",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In a multithreading environment, what is the benefit of threads sharing the same memory space?",
    "Option A": "Increased security",
    "Option B": "Faster communication between threads",
    "Option C": "More efficient use of disk space",
    "Option D": "Simplified code complexity",
    Answer: "B) Faster communication between threads",
    Topic: "Multithreading",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is a characteristic of Round Robin scheduling?",
    "Option A": "Unpredictable execution order",
    "Option B": "No context switching is involved",
    "Option C":
      "Each process is given a fixed time to execute, called a quantum",
    "Option D": "It's a non-preemptive scheduling algorithm",
    Answer:
      "C) Each process is given a fixed time to execute, called a quantum",
    Topic: "CPU Scheduling",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the primary function of the Memory Management Unit (MMU) in an operating system?",
    "Option A": "To increase the processing speed",
    "Option B": "To manage the computer's file system",
    "Option C": "To handle the swapping of pages between RAM and disk",
    "Option D": "To translate virtual addresses into physical addresses",
    Answer: "D) To translate virtual addresses into physical addresses",
    Topic: "Memory Management",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is fragmentation in the context of memory management?",
    "Option A": "The process of compressing data to fit into memory",
    "Option B": "The division of the hard disk into sectors and tracks",
    "Option C":
      "The division of memory into blocks that may cause wasted space",
    "Option D": "The process of increasing the size of the memory",
    Answer: "C) The division of memory into blocks that may cause wasted space",
    Topic: "Memory Management",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following best describes 'Logical Address'?",
    "Option A": "The actual location on the hard disk",
    "Option B": "The address visible to the user",
    "Option C": "The address used by the CPU to access memory",
    "Option D": "The address used by the network devices",
    Answer: "B) The address visible to the user",
    Topic: "Memory Management",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the main purpose of an operating system?",
    "Option A": "To provide a platform for only gaming applications",
    "Option B": "To manage computer hardware and software resources",
    "Option C": "To facilitate networking only",
    "Option D": "To provide security against internet threats only",
    Answer: "B) To manage computer hardware and software resources",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following best describes 'Thrashing'?",
    "Option A": "Optimal memory usage",
    "Option B": "High CPU usage by a single process",
    "Option C": "Excessive paging causing a significant slowdown",
    "Option D": "Rapid execution of processes",
    Answer: "C) Excessive paging causing a significant slowdown",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the role of the file system in an operating system?",
    "Option A": "To manage network protocols",
    "Option B": "To control user access to the system",
    "Option C": "To manage the data stored on disk drives",
    "Option D": "To optimize CPU performance",
    Answer: "C) To manage the data stored on disk drives",
    Topic: "File Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In operating systems, what is the difference between preemptive and non-preemptive scheduling?",
    "Option A":
      "Preemptive scheduling allows the operating system to control CPU access, while non-preemptive does not",
    "Option B":
      "Non-preemptive scheduling allows the process to execute entirely without interruption",
    "Option C":
      "Preemptive scheduling is only used in batch systems, while non-preemptive is used in interactive systems",
    "Option D": "Both A and B",
    Answer: "D) Both A and B",
    Topic: "CPU Scheduling",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the main purpose of a Disk Scheduling Algorithm?",
    "Option A": "To ensure data is encrypted on the disk",
    "Option B": "To manage the creation of files on the disk",
    "Option C": "To determine the order of disk access requests",
    "Option D": "To speed up the network connection",
    Answer: "C) To determine the order of disk access requests",
    Topic: "File Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is true about a multi-user operating system?",
    "Option A":
      "It allows multiple users to use the computer but not at the same time.",
    "Option B": "It allows only one user to use the computer at any time.",
    "Option C":
      "It allows multiple users to use the computer at the same time.",
    "Option D": "It is used exclusively for network servers.",
    Answer: "C) It allows multiple users to use the computer at the same time.",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the purpose of system calls in operating systems?",
    "Option A": "To enhance the graphical user interface",
    "Option B":
      "To allow user applications to request services from the operating system",
    "Option C": "To increase the speed of the processor",
    "Option D": "To manage user profiles and settings",
    Answer:
      "B) To allow user applications to request services from the operating system",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the primary function of the command interpreter in an operating system?",
    "Option A": "To manage the CPU",
    "Option B": "To interpret and execute user commands",
    "Option C": "To render the user interface",
    "Option D": "To control network access",
    Answer: "B) To interpret and execute user commands",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is a common real-time operating system application?",
    "Option A": "Word processing software",
    "Option B": "Database management systems",
    "Option C": "Air traffic control systems",
    "Option D": "Email servers",
    Answer: "C) Air traffic control systems",
    Topic: "Real-Time Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which component of the operating system is responsible for managing files and directories?",
    "Option A": "Kernel",
    "Option B": "Shell",
    "Option C": "File System",
    "Option D": "Command Interpreter",
    Answer: "C) File System",
    Topic: "File Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is meant by 'Spooling' in the context of operating systems?",
    "Option A": "Speeding up the processor",
    "Option B": "Storing temporary data in a buffer",
    "Option C":
      "Simultaneous Peripheral Operations Online - managing data sent to devices like printers",
    "Option D": "Sorting files in alphabetical order",
    Answer:
      "C) Simultaneous Peripheral Operations Online - managing data sent to devices like printers",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is 'Context Switching' in an operating system?",
    "Option A": "Switching between different user accounts",
    "Option B": "Changing the graphical user interface",
    "Option C":
      "The process of storing and restoring the state of a CPU so that a process can resume execution from the same point later",
    "Option D": "Updating the operating system to a new version",
    Answer:
      "C) The process of storing and restoring the state of a CPU so that a process can resume execution from the same point later",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following describes a 'Monolithic Kernel'?",
    "Option A": "A kernel that runs on a single type of processor",
    "Option B": "A type of kernel that provides file system services",
    "Option C": "A kernel where all services run in kernel space",
    "Option D": "A kernel used exclusively in embedded systems",
    Answer: "C) A kernel where all services run in kernel space",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In operating systems, what does the term 'Bootstrapping' refer to?",
    "Option A": "Removing malware from the system",
    "Option B":
      "The process of starting up the operating system when the computer is turned on",
    "Option C": "Optimizing the system for better performance",
    "Option D": "Upgrading the system to the latest version",
    Answer:
      "B) The process of starting up the operating system when the computer is turned on",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following best describes the purpose of a 'Device Driver'?",
    "Option A": "To increase the device's speed",
    "Option B": "To provide a security check for devices",
    "Option C":
      "To allow the operating system to communicate with hardware devices",
    "Option D": "To monitor the performance of the system",
    Answer:
      "C) To allow the operating system to communicate with hardware devices",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is NOT a function of an operating system?",
    "Option A": "Resource allocation",
    "Option B": "Networking control",
    "Option C": "Application development",
    "Option D": "Security management",
    Answer: "C) Application development",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the main difference between 'Kernel Mode' and 'User Mode' in operating systems?",
    "Option A":
      "User mode allows direct hardware access, while kernel mode does not",
    "Option B":
      "Kernel mode allows direct hardware access, while user mode does not",
    "Option C":
      "Kernel mode is only for administrators, while user mode is for all users",
    "Option D": "User mode is faster than kernel mode",
    Answer:
      "B) Kernel mode allows direct hardware access, while user mode does not",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which is a primary function of the operating system's file management feature?",
    "Option A": "Enhancing the speed of the CPU",
    "Option B": "Organizing and providing access to data files",
    "Option C": "Controlling user access to the internet",
    "Option D": "Managing the email system",
    Answer: "B) Organizing and providing access to data files",
    Topic: "File Management",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is 'Virtual Memory' in an operating system?",
    "Option A": "Additional RAM added to the system",
    "Option B":
      "A technique to simulate more memory than physically available using disk space",
    "Option C": "Memory used by the BIOS",
    "Option D":
      "The part of the hard drive that stores temporary internet files",
    Answer:
      "B) A technique to simulate more memory than physically available using disk space",
    Topic: "Virtual Memory",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is NOT a typical resource managed by an operating system?",
    "Option A": "CPU cycles",
    "Option B": "Network bandwidth",
    "Option C": "User passwords",
    "Option D": "Memory",
    Answer: "C) User passwords",
    Topic: "Resource Management",
  },
  {
    Question: "What does the term 'Kernel' refer to in operating systems?",
    "Option A": "A type of computer virus",
    "Option B":
      "The core part of the operating system that manages system resources",
    "Option C": "The user interface",
    "Option D": "The initial screen seen when the computer boots up",
    Answer:
      "B) The core part of the operating system that manages system resources",
    Topic: "Kernel",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the main purpose of a Disk Defragmenter?",
    "Option A": "To clean the disk from viruses",
    "Option B":
      "To reorganize fragmented data to improve file reading and writing speed",
    "Option C": "To format the disk",
    "Option D": "To increase the disk's storage capacity",
    Answer:
      "B) To reorganize fragmented data to improve file reading and writing speed",
    Topic: "File Management",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is 'Paging' in the context of memory management?",
    "Option A": "A networking technique to send messages",
    "Option B": "A method of dividing the memory into fixed-size blocks",
    "Option C": "A power-saving mode for computers",
    "Option D": "A tool for personal information management",
    Answer: "B) A method of dividing the memory into fixed-size blocks",
    Topic: "Memory Management",
  },
  {
    Question: "What does 'I/O Bound' mean in terms of process execution?",
    "Option A": "The process is heavily dependent on the processor's speed",
    "Option B":
      "The process spends more time doing input/output than computations",
    "Option C": "The process is bound to one input/output device",
    "Option D": "The process can only perform input or output operations",
    Answer:
      "B) The process spends more time doing input/output than computations",
    Topic: "Process Execution",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is a function of the operating system's security management?",
    "Option A": "Accelerating the processor's speed",
    "Option B": "Organizing files on the disk",
    "Option C": "Protecting data from unauthorized access",
    "Option D": "Creating graphical interfaces for applications",
    Answer: "C) Protecting data from unauthorized access",
    Topic: "Security Management",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In which of the following scenarios would a real-time operating system be most necessary?",
    "Option A": "Managing a personal blog",
    "Option B": "Writing a report on word processing software",
    "Option C": "Controlling the operations of an industrial robot",
    "Option D": "Watching a video online",
    Answer: "C) Controlling the operations of an industrial robot",
    Topic: "Real-Time Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the primary role of an operating system's scheduler?",
    "Option A": "To protect the system from viruses",
    "Option B": "To manage the system's users and permissions",
    "Option C": "To organize files on the hard drive",
    "Option D": "To allocate CPU time to various functions and processes",
    Answer: "D) To allocate CPU time to various functions and processes",
    Topic: "Process Scheduling",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is a 'System Call' in the context of operating systems?",
    "Option A": "A function call to terminate the system",
    "Option B": "A user request to reboot the computer",
    "Option C":
      "An interface for programs to interact with the operating system",
    "Option D": "A call between two different operating systems",
    Answer:
      "C) An interface for programs to interact with the operating system",
    Topic: "System Calls",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following terms describes the smallest unit of data in a computer system?",
    "Option A": "Byte",
    "Option B": "Bit",
    "Option C": "Block",
    "Option D": "Buffer",
    Answer: "B) Bit",
    Topic: "Computer Data Units",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is 'Time Sharing' in the context of operating systems?",
    "Option A": "Dividing the computer's time equally between all users",
    "Option B": "Allowing users to set time limits for their computer usage",
    "Option C":
      "A technique to allow multiple users or processes to use the system concurrently",
    "Option D": "Sharing time-related information between different systems",
    Answer:
      "C) A technique to allow multiple users or processes to use the system concurrently",
    Topic: "Time-Sharing",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is meant by 'Process Priority' in an operating system?",
    "Option A": "The order in which files are accessed by the process",
    "Option B": "The amount of memory allocated to the process",
    "Option C":
      "The relative importance or urgency of a process in terms of CPU time",
    "Option D": "The number of tasks a process can perform",
    Answer:
      "C) The relative importance or urgency of a process in terms of CPU time",
    Topic: "Process Management",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is an example of a preemptive scheduling algorithm?",
    "Option A": "First-Come, First-Served (FCFS)",
    "Option B": "Shortest Job Next (SJN)",
    "Option C": "Round Robin (RR)",
    "Option D": "Last-In, First-Out (LIFO)",
    Answer: "C) Round Robin (RR)",
    Topic: "Scheduling Algorithms",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following best describes the 'Least Recently Used (LRU)' page replacement algorithm?",
    "Option A": "It replaces the page that has been in memory the longest.",
    "Option B":
      "It replaces the page that will not be used for the longest period in the future.",
    "Option C": "It replaces the page that has been used least recently.",
    "Option D": "It randomly selects a page for replacement.",
    Answer: "C) It replaces the page that has been used least recently",
    Topic: "Page Replacement Algorithms",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In a computer system, what does 'BIOS' stand for and what is its role?",
    "Option A":
      "Best Input Output System: It is responsible for handling the inputs and outputs of the computer.",
    "Option B":
      "Basic Input Output System: It is responsible for initializing hardware and loading the operating system.",
    "Option C":
      "Binary Input Output System: It is responsible for managing data in binary form.",
    "Option D":
      "Buffer Input Output System: It manages the temporary storage of data.",
    Answer:
      "B) Basic Input Output System: It is responsible for initializing hardware and loading the operating system",
    Topic: "BIOS (Basic Input Output System)",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is a 'Daemon' in the context of Unix/Linux operating systems?",
    "Option A": "A graphical interface provided by the system",
    "Option B": "A virus or malware program",
    "Option C": "A background process running on the system",
    "Option D": "A tool for system administrators to configure system settings",
    Answer: "C) A background process running on the system",
    Topic: "Unix/Linux Daemons",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is 'Multitasking' in an operating system?",
    "Option A": "Performing a single task multiple times",
    "Option B": "Running multiple applications on a single core processor",
    "Option C":
      "The ability of the operating system to perform and manage multiple tasks at the same time",
    "Option D": "A user doing multiple tasks simultaneously",
    Answer:
      "C) The ability of the operating system to perform and manage multiple tasks at the same time",
    Topic: "Multitasking",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the main difference between 'Hard Link' and 'Soft Link' in Unix/Linux?",
    "Option A":
      "Hard Link is a direct link to the physical data, Soft Link is a link to another link",
    "Option B": "Hard Link can cross file systems, Soft Link cannot",
    "Option C": "Hard Link is a shortcut, Soft Link is a mirror copy",
    "Option D": "Hard Link is a mirror copy, Soft Link is a shortcut",
    Answer: "D) Hard Link is a mirror copy, Soft Link is a shortcut",
    Topic: "File Links in Unix/Linux",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the function of the 'Swap Space' in a Linux system?",
    "Option A": "To store temporary user files",
    "Option B": "To provide extra memory by using disk space",
    "Option C": "To enhance the CPU speed",
    "Option D": "To hold the system configuration files",
    Answer: "B) To provide extra memory by using disk space",
    Topic: "Linux Swap Space",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following best describes a 'Microkernel' approach?",
    "Option A": "A type of kernel that provides file system services",
    "Option B": "A kernel where all services run in kernel space",
    "Option C": "A small, modular kernel with minimal services in kernel space",
    "Option D": "A kernel used exclusively in microcomputers",
    Answer: "C) A small, modular kernel with minimal services in kernel space",
    Topic: "Kernel Design",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which type of memory is volatile and requires power to maintain the stored information?",
    "Option A": "Hard Drive",
    "Option B": "SSD (Solid State Drive)",
    "Option C": "RAM (Random Access Memory)",
    "Option D": "ROM (Read-Only Memory)",
    Answer: "C) RAM (Random Access Memory)",
    Topic: "Computer Memory",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is a 'Race Condition' in the context of concurrent programming?",
    "Option A":
      "When two processes attempt to finish their execution as quickly as possible",
    "Option B":
      "When a process is racing against time to avoid a system timeout",
    "Option C":
      "A situation where the behavior of software is dependent on the sequence or timing of other uncontrollable events",
    "Option D":
      "A competitive scenario where multiple programs are competing for the user's attention",
    Answer:
      "C) A situation where the behavior of software is dependent on the sequence or timing of other uncontrollable events",
    Topic: "Concurrent Programming",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the purpose of a 'Job Queue' in an operating system?",
    "Option A": "To collect all the print jobs",
    "Option B": "To store all the user passwords",
    "Option C": "To list all the jobs that are currently running on the system",
    "Option D":
      "To hold all the processes that are ready to run or are waiting to run",
    Answer:
      "D) To hold all the processes that are ready to run or are waiting to run",
    Topic: "Job Queue",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following file system types is most commonly used in Linux systems?",
    "Option A": "FAT32",
    "Option B": "NTFS",
    "Option C": "ext4",
    "Option D": "HFS+",
    Answer: "C) ext4",
    Topic: "File Systems in Linux",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is 'Multithreading' in the context of operating systems?",
    "Option A": "Using multiple CPUs to perform different tasks",
    "Option B":
      "Breaking down a task into smaller tasks to be performed simultaneously",
    "Option C": "The ability to run multiple threads within a single process",
    "Option D": "Connecting multiple computers to share the workload",
    Answer: "C) The ability to run multiple threads within a single process",
    Topic: "Multithreading",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the primary advantage of using 'Demand Paging' in virtual memory systems?",
    "Option A": "It increases the physical memory size",
    "Option B": "It reduces the total number of pages used in memory",
    "Option C": "It loads pages into memory only when they are needed",
    "Option D": "It enhances the processing speed of the system",
    Answer: "C) It loads pages into memory only when they are needed",
    Topic: "Virtual Memory Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "In the context of databases, what is 'ACID' used to describe?",
    "Option A":
      "The harmful effect of a corrupt database on system performance",
    "Option B": "A cleaning process to ensure data integrity",
    "Option C":
      "The properties of Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Durability",
    "Option D": "Types of databases that are prone to errors",
    Answer:
      "C) The properties of Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Durability",
    Topic: "Database Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the function of the 'Virtual File System (VFS)' in operating systems?",
    "Option A": "To format and partition the hard drive",
    "Option B": "To manage the temporary files created by the system",
    "Option C": "To provide a standard interface for different file systems",
    "Option D": "To increase the storage capacity virtually",
    Answer: "C) To provide a standard interface for different file systems",
    Topic: "Virtual File",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following best describes 'Load Balancing' in the context of operating systems?",
    "Option A": "Distributing work evenly across all available CPUs",
    "Option B": "Balancing the electrical load of the computer",
    "Option C": "Distributing data evenly across multiple hard drives",
    "Option D": "Managing the load of user requests on a web server",
    Answer: "A) Distributing work evenly across all available CPUs",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is a 'Zombie Process' in Unix/Linux systems?",
    "Option A": "A process that is currently running and consuming CPU time",
    "Option B":
      "A process that has completed execution but still has an entry in the process table",
    "Option C": "A process that is starting up and initializing its variables",
    "Option D": "A malicious process that damages system files",
    Answer:
      "B) A process that has completed execution but still has an entry in the process table",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following file system types is most commonly used in Windows systems?",
    "Option A": "FAT32",
    "Option B": "NTFS",
    "Option C": "ext4",
    "Option D": "HFS+",
    Answer: "B) NTFS",
    Topic: "File Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is 'Banker's Algorithm' used for in operating systems?",
    "Option A": "Optimizing CPU usage",
    "Option B": "Managing and preventing deadlock situations",
    "Option C": "Balancing the memory allocation",
    "Option D": "Scheduling of processes",
    Answer: "B) Managing and preventing deadlock situations",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the main purpose of 'File Permissions' in Unix/Linux systems?",
    "Option A": "To determine how files are compressed and expanded",
    "Option B": "To control the way the operating system handles system errors",
    "Option C": "To define who can read, write, or execute a file",
    "Option D": "To manage the network access for files",
    Answer: "C) To define who can read, write, or execute a file",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "What does 'Fork' do in Unix/Linux systems?",
    "Option A": "Merges two or more files into one",
    "Option B": "Splits the screen into multiple terminals",
    "Option C": "Creates a new child process",
    "Option D": "Deletes temporary files to free space",
    Answer: "C) Creates a new child process",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is 'Starvation' in the context of process scheduling?",
    "Option A": "When the system runs out of CPU resources",
    "Option B":
      "When a process is unable to get necessary system resources due to other high priority processes",
    "Option C": "When a system is overloaded with too many user requests",
    "Option D": "When a process is terminated unexpectedly",
    Answer:
      "B) When a process is unable to get necessary system resources due to other high priority processes",
    Topic: "CPU Scheduling",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is 'Kernel Panic' in Unix/Linux systems?",
    "Option A": "A security feature that protects the kernel from attacks",
    "Option B": "A condition where the system gradually slows down",
    "Option C": "A non-recoverable system error detected by the kernel",
    "Option D": "An event where the system runs out of memory",
    Answer: "C) A non-recoverable system error detected by the kernel",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is 'Pipe' used for in Unix/Linux systems?",
    "Option A": "Connecting to the internet",
    "Option B": "Redirecting the output of one command as input to another",
    "Option C": "Increasing the system's memory capacity",
    "Option D": "Authenticating user logins",
    Answer: "B) Redirecting the output of one command as input to another",
    Topic: "Operating Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is a Data Model?",
    "Option A": "entity-relationship model",
    "Option B": "relational data model",
    "Option C": "object-based data model",
    "Option D": "all of the above",
    Answer: "D. all of the above",
    Topic: "Data Model",
  },
  {
    Question: "A collection of related data.",
    "Option A": "Information",
    "Option B": "Valuable information",
    "Option C": "Database",
    "Option D": "Metadata",
    Answer: "C. Database",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "DBMS is software.",
    "Option A": true,
    "Option B": false,
    "Option C": "none",
    "Option D": "all",
    Answer: "A. True",
    Topic: "DBMS",
  },
  {
    Question: "DBMS manages the interaction between __________ and database.",
    "Option A": "Users",
    "Option B": "Clients",
    "Option C": "End Users",
    "Option D": "Stake Holders",
    Answer: "C. End Users",
    Topic: "DBMS",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not involved in DBMS?",
    "Option A": "End Users",
    "Option B": "Data",
    "Option C": "Application Request",
    "Option D": "HTML",
    Answer: "D. HTML",
    Topic: "DBMS",
  },
  {
    Question: "Database is generally __________",
    "Option A": "System-centered",
    "Option B": "User-centered",
    "Option C": "Company-centered",
    "Option D": "Data-centered",
    Answer: "B. User-centered",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "A characteristic of an entity.",
    "Option A": "Relation",
    "Option B": "Attribute",
    "Option C": "Parameter",
    "Option D": "Constraint",
    Answer: "B. Attribute",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "The restrictions placed on the data.",
    "Option A": "Relation",
    "Option B": "Attribute",
    "Option C": "Parameter",
    "Option D": "Constraint",
    Answer: "D. Constraint",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "IMS stands for?",
    "Option A": "Information Mastering System",
    "Option B": "Instruction Management System",
    "Option C": "Instruction Manipulating System",
    "Option D": "Information Management System",
    Answer: "D. Information Management System",
    Topic: "DBMS",
  },
  {
    Question: "A model developed by Hammer and Mc Leod in 1981.",
    "Option A": "SDM",
    "Option B": "OODBM",
    "Option C": "DDM",
    "Option D": "RDM",
    Answer: "A. SDM",
    Topic: "Data Model",
  },
  {
    Question: "Object=_________+relationships.",
    "Option A": "data",
    "Option B": "attributes",
    "Option C": "entity",
    "Option D": "constraints",
    Answer: "C. entity",
    Topic: "Data Model",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Duplication of data at several places is called as _______________.",
    "Option A": "Data Inconsistency",
    "Option B": "Data Isolation",
    "Option C": "Atomicity Problem",
    "Option D": "Data Redundance",
    Answer: "D. Data Redundance",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Data Redundancy increases the cost of storing and retrieving data.",
    "Option A": false,
    "Option B": true,
    "Option C": "none",
    "Option D": "all",
    Answer: "B. True",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the information is not redundant.",
    "Option A": "name",
    "Option B": "mobile",
    "Option C": "account-no",
    "Option D": "address",
    Answer: "C. account-no",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If in redundant file common fields are not matching then it results in _____________.",
    "Option A": "Data Inconsistency",
    "Option B": "Data Integrity Problem",
    "Option C": "Data Isolation",
    "Option D": "Data Redundancy",
    Answer: "A. Data Inconsistency",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "It is difficult to access conventional file system than Database System.",
    "Option A": true,
    "Option B": false,
    "Option C": "none",
    "Option D": "all",
    Answer: "A. True",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "An ________ is a set of entities of the same type that share the same properties, or attributes.",
    "Option A": "Entity set",
    "Option B": "Attribute set",
    "Option C": "Relation set",
    "Option D": "Entity model",
    Answer: "A. Entity set",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "Entity is a _________",
    "Option A": "Object of relation",
    "Option B": "Present working model",
    "Option C": "Thing in real world",
    "Option D": "Model of relation",
    Answer: "C. Thing in real world",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The descriptive property possessed by each entity set is _________",
    "Option A": "Entity",
    "Option B": "Attribute",
    "Option C": "Relation",
    "Option D": "Model",
    Answer: "B. Attribute",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The function that an entity plays in a relationship is called that entity’s _____________",
    "Option A": "Participation",
    "Option B": "Position",
    "Option C": "Role",
    "Option D": "Instance",
    Answer: "C. Role",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The attribute name could be structured as an attribute consisting of first name, middle initial, and last name. This type of attribute is called",
    "Option A": "Simple attribute",
    "Option B": "Composite attribute",
    "Option C": "Multivalued attribute",
    "Option D": "Derived attribute",
    Answer: "B. Composite attribute",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In a relation between the entities the type and condition of the relation should be specified. That is called as______attribute.",
    "Option A": "Desciptive",
    "Option B": "Derived",
    "Option C": "Recursive",
    "Option D": "Relative",
    Answer: "A. Desciptive",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Object based logical model(s) are used to describe data at - [Select Appropriate Option(s)]",
    "Option A": "View Level",
    "Option B": "Logical Level",
    "Option C": "Physical Level",
    "Option D": "None of these",
    Answer: "C. Physical Level",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is example of Object based logical model ?",
    "Option A": "Relational Model",
    "Option B": "Hierarchical Model",
    "Option C": "Network Model",
    "Option D": "Entity Relationship Model",
    Answer: "D. Entity Relationship Model",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Entity Relationship model consists of collection of basic objects called _________ and relationship among these objects.",
    "Option A": "functions",
    "Option B": "models",
    "Option C": "None of these",
    "Option D": "entities",
    Answer: "D. entities",
    Topic: "Data Model",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If a piece of data is stored in two places in the database, then",
    "Option A": "Storage space is wasted",
    "Option B": "Changing the data in one spot will cause data inconsistency",
    "Option C": "It can be more easily accessed",
    "Option D":
      "Storage space is wasted & Changing the data in one spot will cause data inconsistency",
    Answer:
      "D. Storage space is wasted & Changing the data in one spot will cause data inconsistency",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "An audit trail ___________",
    "Option A": "Is used to make backup copies",
    "Option B": "Is the recorded history of operations performed on a file",
    "Option C": "Can be used to restore lost information",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. Is the recorded history of operations performed on a file",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "Large collection of files are called ____________",
    "Option A": "Fields",
    "Option B": "Records",
    "Option C": "Database",
    "Option D": "Sectors",
    Answer: "C. Database",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following hardware component is the most important to the operation of a database management system?",
    "Option A": "High resolution video display",
    "Option B": "Printer",
    "Option C": "High speed, large capacity disk",
    "Option D": "Mouse",
    Answer: "C. High speed, large capacity disk",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is not true of the traditional approach to information processing",
    "Option A":
      "There is common sharing of data among the various applications",
    "Option B": "It is file-oriented",
    "Option C": "Programs are dependent on the file",
    "Option D": "It is inflexible",
    Answer: "A. There is common sharing of data among the various applications",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "The information about data in a database is called _______",
    "Option A": "Metadata",
    "Option B": "Hyper data",
    "Option C": "Tera data",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. Metadata",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "A data dictionary is a special file that contains?",
    "Option A": "The names of all fields in all files",
    "Option B": "The data types of all fields in all files",
    "Option C": "The widths of all fields in all files",
    "Option D": "All of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. All of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A relational database system needs to maintain data about the relations, such as the schema of the relations. This is called",
    "Option A": "Metadata",
    "Option B": "Catalog",
    "Option C": "Log",
    "Option D": "Dictionary",
    Answer: "A. Metadata",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Relational schemas and other metadata about relations are stored in a structure called the ____________",
    "Option A": "Metadata",
    "Option B": "Catalog",
    "Option C": "Log",
    "Option D": "Data Dictionary",
    Answer: "D. Data Dictionary",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "___________ is the collection of memory structures and Oracle background processes that operates against an Oracle database.",
    "Option A": "Database",
    "Option B": "Instance",
    "Option C": "Tablespace",
    "Option D": "Segment",
    Answer: "B. Instance",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A ________ is a logical grouping of database objects, usually to facilitate security, performance, or the availability of database objects such as tables and indexes.",
    "Option A": "Tablespace",
    "Option B": "Segments",
    "Option C": "Extents",
    "Option D": "Blocks",
    Answer: "A. Tablespace",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "A tablespace is further broken down into ________",
    "Option A": "Tablespace",
    "Option B": "Segments",
    "Option C": "Extents",
    "Option D": "Blocks",
    Answer: "B. Segments",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "__________ is a contiguous group of blocks allocated for use as part of a table, index, and so forth.",
    "Option A": "Tablespace",
    "Option B": "Segment",
    "Option C": "Extent",
    "Option D": "Block",
    Answer: "C. Extent",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "________ is the smallest unit of allocation in an Oracle database.",
    "Option A": "Database",
    "Option B": "Instance",
    "Option C": "Tablespace",
    "Option D": "Database Block",
    Answer: "D. Database Block",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "An Oracle __________ is a set of tables and views that are used as a read-only reference about the database.",
    "Option A": "Database dictionary",
    "Option B": "Dictionary table",
    "Option C": "Data dictionary",
    "Option D": "Dictionary",
    Answer: "C. Data dictionary",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "A data dictionary is created when a __________ created.",
    "Option A": "Instance",
    "Option B": "Segment",
    "Option C": "Database",
    "Option D": "Dictionary",
    Answer: "C. Database",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "An Oracle object type has two parts the _________ and__________",
    "Option A": "Instance and body",
    "Option B": "Segment and blocks",
    "Option C": "Specification and body",
    "Option D": "Body and segment",
    Answer: "C. Specification and body",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A(n) _________ can be used to preserve the integrity of a document or a message.",
    "Option A": "Message digest",
    "Option B": "Message summary",
    "Option C": "Encrypted message",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. Message digest",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "A hash function must meet ________ criteriA:)",
    "Option A": "Two",
    "Option B": "Three",
    "Option C": "Four",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. Three",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the main limitation of Hierarchical Databases?",
    "Option A": "Limited capacity (unable to hold much data)",
    "Option B": "Limited flexibility in accessing data",
    "Option C": "Overhead associated with maintaining indexes",
    "Option D": "The performance of the database is poor",
    Answer: "B. Limited flexibility in accessing data",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The property (or set of properties) that uniquely defines each row in a table is called the:",
    "Option A": "Identifier",
    "Option B": "Index",
    "Option C": "Primary key",
    "Option D": "Symmetric key",
    Answer: "C. Primary key",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The separation of the data definition from the program is known as:",
    "Option A": "Data dictionary",
    "Option B": "Data independence",
    "Option C": "Data integrity",
    "Option D": "Referential integrity",
    Answer: "B. Data independence",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The traditional storage of data that is organized by customer, stored in separate folders in filing cabinets is an example of what type of ‘database’ system?",
    "Option A": "Hierarchical",
    "Option B": "Network",
    "Option C": "Object-oriented",
    "Option D": "Relational",
    Answer: "A. Hierarchical",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The database design that consists of multiple tables that are linked together through matching data stored in each table is called",
    "Option A": "Hierarchical database",
    "Option B": "Network database",
    "Option C": "Object-oriented database",
    "Option D": "Relational database",
    Answer: "D. Relational database",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "The association role defines:",
    "Option A": "How tables are related in the database",
    "Option B":
      "The relationship between the class diagram and the tables in the database",
    "Option C": "The tables that each attribute is contained",
    "Option D": "Which attribute is the table’s primary key",
    Answer: "A. How tables are related in the database",
    Topic: "Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which SQL keyword is used to retrieve a maximum value?",
    "Option A": "MOST",
    "Option B": "TOP",
    "Option C": "MAX",
    "Option D": "UPPER",
    Answer: "C. MAX",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following SQL clauses is used to DELETE tuples from a database table?",
    "Option A": "DELETE",
    "Option B": "REMOVE",
    "Option C": "DROP",
    "Option D": "CLEAR",
    Answer: "A. DELETE",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "___________ removes all rows from a table without logging the individual row deletions.",
    "Option A": "DELETE",
    "Option B": "REMOVE",
    "Option C": "DROP",
    "Option D": "TRUNCATE",
    Answer: "D. TRUNCATE",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not a DDL command?",
    "Option A": "UPDATE",
    "Option B": "TRUNCATE",
    "Option C": "ALTER",
    "Option D": "None of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "A. UPDATE",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following are TCL commands?",
    "Option A": "UPDATE and TRUNCATE",
    "Option B": "SELECT and INSERT",
    "Option C": "GRANT and REVOKE",
    "Option D": "ROLLBACK and SAVEPOINT",
    Answer: "D. ROLLBACK and SAVEPOINT",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "________________ is not a category of SQL command.",
    "Option A": "TCL",
    "Option B": "SCL",
    "Option C": "DCL",
    "Option D": "DDL",
    Answer: "B. SCL",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If you don’t specify ASC or DESC after a SQL ORDER BY clause, the following is used by default ______________",
    "Option A": "ASC",
    "Option B": "DESC",
    "Option C": "There is no default value",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. ASC",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following statement is true?",
    "Option A":
      "DELETE does not free the space containing the table and TRUNCATE free the space containing the table",
    "Option B": "Both DELETE and TRUNCATE free the space containing the table",
    "Option C":
      "Both DELETE and TRUNCATE do not free the space containing the table",
    "Option D":
      "DELETE free the space containing the table and TRUNCATE does not free the space containing the table",
    Answer:
      "A. DELETE does not free the space containing the table and TRUNCATE free the space containing the table",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the purpose of the SQL AS clause?",
    "Option A":
      "The AS SQL clause is used to change the name of a column in the result set or to assign a name to a derived column",
    "Option B": "The AS clause is used with the JOIN clause only",
    "Option C": "The AS clause defines a search condition",
    "Option D": "All of the mentioned",
    Answer:
      "A. The AS SQL clause is used to change the name of a column in the result set or to assign a name to a derived column",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "What does DML stand for?",
    "Option A": "Different Mode Level",
    "Option B": "Data Model Language",
    "Option C": "Data Mode Lane",
    "Option D": "Data Manipulation language",
    Answer: "D. Data Manipulation language",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "With SQL, how do you select all the records from a table named “Persons” where the value of the column “FirstName” ends with an “a”?",
    "Option A": "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName=’a’",
    "Option B": "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName LIKE ‘a%’",
    "Option C": "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName LIKE ‘%a’",
    "Option D": "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName=’%a%’",
    Answer: "C. SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName LIKE ‘%a’",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "With SQL, how can you return all the records from a table named “Persons” sorted descending by “FirstName”?",
    "Option A": "SELECT * FROM Persons SORT BY ‘FirstName’ DESC",
    "Option B": "SELECT * FROM Persons ORDER FirstName DESC",
    "Option C": "SELECT * FROM Persons SORT ‘FirstName’ DESC",
    "Option D": "SELECT * FROM Persons ORDER BY FirstName DESC",
    Answer: "D. SELECT * FROM Persons ORDER BY FirstName DESC",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "With SQL, how can you return the number of not null records in the “Persons” table?",
    "Option A": "SELECT COUNT() FROM Persons",
    "Option B": "SELECT COLUMNS() FROM Persons",
    "Option C": "SELECT COLUMNS(*) FROM Persons",
    "Option D": "SELECT COUNT(*) FROM Persons",
    Answer: "A. SELECT COUNT() FROM Persons",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "What does the ALTER TABLE clause do?",
    "Option A":
      "The SQL ALTER TABLE clause modifies a table definition by altering, adding, or deleting table columns and/or constraints",
    "Option B":
      "The SQL ALTER TABLE clause is used to insert data into a database table",
    "Option C": "THE SQL ALTER TABLE deletes data from the database table",
    "Option D": "The SQL ALTER TABLE clause is used to delete a database table",
    Answer:
      "A. The SQL ALTER TABLE clause modifies a table definition by altering, adding, or deleting table columns and/or constraints",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "The UPDATE SQL clause can _____________",
    "Option A": "Update only one row at a time",
    "Option B": "Update more than one row at a time",
    "Option C": "Delete more than one row at a time",
    "Option D": "Delete only one row at a time",
    Answer: "B. Update more than one row at a time",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "The UNION SQL clause can be used with _____________",
    "Option A": "SELECT clause only",
    "Option B": "DELETE and UPDATE clauses",
    "Option C": "UPDATE clause only",
    "Option D": "All of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. SELECT clause only",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which SQL statement is used to return only different values?",
    "Option A": "SELECT DIFFERENT",
    "Option B": "SELECT UNIQUE",
    "Option C": "SELECT DISTINCT",
    "Option D": "SELECT ALL",
    Answer: "C. SELECT DISTINCT",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which SQL keyword is used to sort the result-set?",
    "Option A": "ORDER BY",
    "Option B": "SORT",
    "Option C": "ORDER",
    "Option D": "SORT BY",
    Answer: "A. ORDER BY",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "How can you change “Hansen” into “Nilsen” in the “LastName” column in the Persons table?",
    "Option A": "UPDATE Persons SET LastName=’Hansen’ INTO LastName=’Nilsen’",
    "Option B": "MODIFY Persons SET LastName=’Nilsen’ WHERE LastName=’Hansen’",
    "Option C": "MODIFY Persons SET LastName=’Hansen’ INTO LastName=’Nilsen’",
    "Option D": "UPDATE Persons SET LastName=’Nilsen’ WHERE LastName=’Hansen’",
    Answer: "D. UPDATE Persons SET LastName=’Nilsen’ WHERE LastName=’Hansen’",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following command makes the updates performed by the transaction permanent in the database?",
    "Option A": "ROLLBACK",
    "Option B": "COMMIT",
    "Option C": "TRUNCATE",
    "Option D": "DELETE",
    Answer: "B. COMMIT",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which TCL command undoes all the updates performed by the SQL in the transaction?",
    "Option A": "ROLLBACK",
    "Option B": "COMMIT",
    "Option C": "TRUNCATE",
    "Option D": "DELETE",
    Answer: "A. ROLLBACK",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "SQL query to find all the cities whose humidity is 95.",
    "Option A": "SELECT city WHERE humidity = 95",
    "Option B": "SELECT city FROM weather WHERE humidity = 95",
    "Option C": "SELECT humidity = 89 FROM weather",
    "Option D": "SELECT city FROM weather",
    Answer: "B. SELECT city FROM weather WHERE humidity = 95",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "SQL query to find the temperature in increasing order of all cities.",
    "Option A": "SELECT city FROM weather ORDER BY temperature",
    "Option B": "SELECT city, temperature FROM weather",
    "Option C": "SELECT city, temperature FROM weather ORDER BY temperature",
    "Option D": "SELECT city, temperature FROM weather ORDER BY city",
    Answer: "D. SELECT city, temperature FROM weather ORDER BY city",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the meaning of LIKE ‘%0%0%’?",
    "Option A": "Feature begins with two 0’s",
    "Option B": "Feature ends with two 0’s",
    "Option C": "Feature has more than two 0’s",
    "Option D": "Feature has two 0’s in it, at any position",
    Answer: "D. Feature has two 0’s in it, at any position",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In the __________ normal form, a composite attribute is converted to individual attributes.",
    "Option A": "First",
    "Option B": "Second",
    "Option C": "Third",
    "Option D": "Fourth",
    Answer: "A. First",
    Topic: "Database Normalization",
  },
  {
    Question: "Tables in second normal form (2NF):",
    "Option A": "Eliminate all hidden dependencies",
    "Option B": "Eliminate the possibility of insertion anomalies",
    "Option C": "Have a composite key",
    "Option D": "Have all non-key fields depend on the whole primary key",
    Answer: "A. Eliminate all hidden dependencies",
    Topic: "Database Normalization",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which-one of the following statements about normal forms is FALSE?",
    "Option A": "BCNF is stricter than 3NF",
    "Option B":
      "Lossless, dependency-preserving decomposition into 3NF is always possible",
    "Option C":
      "Lossless, dependency-preserving decomposition into BCNF is always possible",
    "Option D": "Any relation with two attributes is BCNF",
    Answer:
      "C. Lossless, dependency-preserving decomposition into BCNF is always possible",
    Topic: "Database Normalization",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Functional Dependencies are the types of constraints that are based on______",
    "Option A": "Key",
    "Option B": "Key revisited",
    "Option C": "Superset key",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. Key",
    Topic: "Functional Dependencies",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which is a bottom-up approach to database design that design by examining the relationship between attributes:",
    "Option A": "Functional dependency",
    "Option B": "Database modeling",
    "Option C": "Normalization",
    "Option D": "Decomposition",
    Answer: "C. Normalization",
    Topic: "Database Design",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which forms simplifies and ensures that there are minimal data aggregates and repetitive groups:",
    "Option A": "1NF",
    "Option B": "2NF",
    "Option C": "3NF",
    "Option D": "All of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. 3NF",
    Topic: "Normalization",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which forms has a relation that possesses data about an individual entity:",
    "Option A": "2NF",
    "Option B": "3NF",
    "Option C": "4NF",
    "Option D": "5NF",
    Answer: "C. 4NF",
    Topic: "Normalization",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which forms are based on the concept of functional dependency:",
    "Option A": "1NF",
    "Option B": "2NF",
    "Option C": "3NF",
    "Option D": "4NF",
    Answer: "C. 3NF",
    Topic: "Normalization",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Empdt1(empcode, name, street, Credit, street, city, salary). For any pincode, there is only one city and state. Also, for the given street, city, and state, there is just one pincode. In normalization terms, empdt1 is a relation in",
    "Option A": "1NF only",
    "Option B": "2NF and hence also in 1NF",
    "Option C": "3NF and hence also in 2NF and 1NF",
    "Option D": "BCNF and hence also in 3NF, 2NF, and 1NF",
    Answer: "B. 2NF and hence also in 1NF",
    Topic: "Database Normalization",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "We can use the following three rules to find logically implied functional dependencies. This collection of rules is called",
    "Option A": "Axioms",
    "Option B": "Armstrong’s axioms",
    "Option C": "Armstrong",
    "Option D": "Closure",
    Answer: "B. Armstrong’s axioms",
    Topic: "Functional Dependencies",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not Armstrong’s Axiom?",
    "Option A": "Reflexivity rule",
    "Option B": "Transitivity rule",
    "Option C": "Pseudotransitivity rule",
    "Option D": "Augmentation rule",
    Answer: "C. Pseudotransitivity rule",
    Topic: "Functional Dependencies",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The relation employee(ID,name,street,Credit,street,city,salary) is decomposed into employee1 (ID, name) employee2 (name, street, city, salary) This type of decomposition is called",
    "Option A": "Lossless decomposition",
    "Option B": "Lossless-join decomposition",
    "Option C": "All of the mentioned",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. None of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Decomposition",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Inst_dept (ID, name, salary, dept name, building, budget) is decomposed into instructor (ID, name, dept name, salary) department (dept name, building, budget) This comes under",
    "Option A": "Lossy-join decomposition",
    "Option B": "Lossy decomposition",
    "Option C": "Lossless-join decomposition",
    "Option D": "Both Lossy and Lossy-join decomposition",
    Answer: "D. Both Lossy and Lossy-join decomposition",
    Topic: "Decomposition",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "There are two functional dependencies with the same set of attributes on the left side of the arrow: A->BC A->B This can be combined as",
    "Option A": "A->BC",
    "Option B": "A->B",
    "Option C": "B->C",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. A->BC",
    Topic: "Functional Dependencies",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider a relation R(A,B,C,D,E) with the following functional dependencies: ABC -> DE and D -> AB The number of superkeys of R is:",
    "Option A": 2,
    "Option B": 7,
    "Option C": 10,
    "Option D": 12,
    Answer: "C. 10",
    Topic: "Functional Dependencies",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which, if any, of the two queries above will correctly (in SQL2) get the desired set of employee ID’s?",
    "Option A": "Both I and II",
    "Option B": "I only",
    "Option C": "II only",
    "Option D": "Neither I nor II",
    Answer: "A. Both I and II",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Suppose now that R(A,B:) and S(A,B:) are two relations with r and s tuples, respectively (again, not necessarily distinct). If m is the number of (not necessarily distinct) tuples in the result of the SQL query: R intersect S; Then which of the following is the most restrictive, correct condition on the value of m?",
    "Option A": "m = min(r,s)",
    "Option B": "0 <= m <= r + s",
    "Option C": "min(r,s) <= m <= max(r,s)",
    "Option D": "0 <= m <= min(r,s)",
    Answer: "D. 0 <= m <= min(r,s)",
    Topic: "SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not a key?",
    "Option A": "A",
    "Option B": "E",
    "Option C": "B, C",
    "Option D": "D",
    Answer: "C. B, C",
    Topic: "Database Normalization",
  },
  {
    Question: "If a relation is in BCNF, then it is also in",
    "Option A": "1 NF",
    "Option B": "2 NF",
    "Option C": "3 NF",
    "Option D": "All of the above",
    Answer: "D. All of the above",
    Topic: "Database Normalization",
  },
  {
    Question: "What action does ⋈ operator perform in relational algebra",
    "Option A":
      "Output specified attributes from all rows of the input relation and remove duplicate tuples from the output",
    "Option B":
      "Outputs pairs of rows from the two input relations that have the same value on all attributes that have the same name",
    "Option C":
      "Output all pairs of rows from the two input relations (regardless of whether or not they have the same values on common attributes)",
    "Option D": "Return rows of the input relation that satisfy the predicate",
    Answer:
      "A. Output specified attributes from all rows of the input relation and remove duplicate tuples from the output",
    Topic: "Relational Algebra",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Statement 1: A tuple is a row in a relation Statement 2: Existence of multiple foreign keys in a same relation is possible",
    "Option A": "Both the statements are true",
    "Option B": "Statement 1 is correct but Statement 2 is false",
    "Option C": "Statement 1 is false but Statement 2 is correct",
    "Option D": "Both the statements are false",
    Answer: "A. Both the statements are true",
    Topic: "Database Concepts",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The____condition allows a general predicate over the relations being joined.",
    "Option A": "On",
    "Option B": "Using",
    "Option C": "Set",
    "Option D": "Where",
    Answer: "A. On",
    Topic: "SQL Joins",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the join operations do not preserve non-matched tuples?",
    "Option A": "Left outer join",
    "Option B": "Right outer join",
    "Option C": "Inner join",
    "Option D": "Natural join",
    Answer: "B. Right outer join",
    Topic: "SQL Joins",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The normal form which satisfies multivalued dependencies and which is in BCNF is",
    "Option A": "4 NF",
    "Option B": "3 NF",
    "Option C": "2 NF",
    "Option D": "All of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. 4 NF",
    Topic: "Database Normalization",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is a tuple-generating dependencies?",
    "Option A": "Functional dependency",
    "Option B": "Equality-generating dependencies",
    "Option C": "Multivalued dependencies",
    "Option D": "Non-functional dependency",
    Answer: "B. Equality-generating dependencies",
    Topic: "Dependencies in DBMS",
  },
  {
    Question: "_______ allow us to identify uniquely a tuple in the relation.",
    "Option A": "schema",
    "Option B": "superkey",
    "Option C": "domain",
    "Option D": "attribute",
    Answer: "B. superkey",
    Topic: "Database Concepts",
  },
  {
    Question: "Minimal Superkeys are called",
    "Option A": "schema keys",
    "Option B": "attribute keys",
    "Option C": "candidate keys",
    "Option D": "domain keys",
    Answer: "C. candidate keys",
    Topic: "Database Concepts",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not Modification of the Database",
    "Option A": "updating",
    "Option B": "sorting",
    "Option C": "deletion",
    "Option D": "insertion",
    Answer: "B. sorting",
    Topic: "Database Operations",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following in not Outer join?",
    "Option A": "left outer join",
    "Option B": "full outer join",
    "Option C": "all of the options",
    "Option D": "right outer join",
    Answer: "C. all of the options",
    Topic: "SQL Joins",
  },
  {
    Question: "Set of permitted values of each attribute is called",
    "Option A": "tuple",
    "Option B": "schema",
    "Option C": "domain",
    "Option D": "relation",
    Answer: "C. domain",
    Topic: "Database Concepts",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is true regarding Null Value?",
    "Option A": "null<0",
    "Option B": "null=0",
    "Option C": "null<>0",
    "Option D": "null>0",
    Answer: "C. null<>0",
    Topic: "Null Values in Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "Logical design of the database is called",
    "Option A": "all of the options",
    "Option B": "database schema",
    "Option C": "database instance",
    "Option D": "database snapshot",
    Answer: "B. database schema",
    Topic: "Database Design",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Snapshot of the data in the database at a given instant of time is called",
    "Option A": "database instance",
    "Option B": "all of the options",
    "Option C": "database schema",
    "Option D": "database snapshot",
    Answer: "A. database instance",
    Topic: "Database Design",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not Unary operation?",
    "Option A": "rename",
    "Option B": "union",
    "Option C": "select",
    "Option D": "project",
    Answer: "B. union",
    Topic: "Relational Algebra",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not binary operation?",
    "Option A": "union",
    "Option B": "set difference",
    "Option C": "cartesian product",
    "Option D": "project",
    Answer: "D. project",
    Topic: "Relational Algebra",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is correct regarding Aggregate functions?",
    "Option A":
      "it takes a single value and returns a single value as a result",
    "Option B":
      "it takes a list of values and returns a single value as a result",
    "Option C":
      "it takes a list of values and returns a list of values as a result",
    "Option D":
      "it takes a single value and returns a list of values as a result",
    Answer:
      "B. it takes a list of values and returns a single value as a result",
    Topic: "Aggregate Functions in SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "The Primary key must be",
    "Option A": "non-null",
    "Option B": "unique",
    "Option C": "option a or b",
    "Option D": "option a and b",
    Answer: "D. option a and b",
    Topic: "Database Design",
  },
  {
    Question: "A command to remove a relation from an SQL database",
    "Option A": "delete table",
    "Option B": "erase table",
    "Option C": "alter table",
    "Option D": "drop table",
    Answer: "D. drop table",
    Topic: "SQL Commands",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not an Aggregate function?",
    "Option A": "select",
    "Option B": "avg",
    "Option C": "min",
    "Option D": "max",
    Answer: "A. select",
    Topic: "Aggregate Functions in SQL",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The attribute that can be divided into other attributes is called",
    "Option A": "composite attribute",
    "Option B": "derived attribute",
    "Option C": "simple attribute",
    "Option D": "multi-valued attribute",
    Answer: "A. composite attribute",
    Topic: "Database Concepts",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is ACID properties of Transactions?",
    "Option A": "atomicity, consistency, isolation, database",
    "Option B": "automatically, concurrency, isolation, durability",
    "Option C": "atomicity, consistency, isolation, durability",
    "Option D": "atomicity, consistency, inconsistent, durability",
    Answer: "C. atomicity, consistency, isolation, durability",
    Topic: "ACID Properties of Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If every non-key attribute is functionally dependent on the primary key, the relation will be in",
    "Option A": "fourth formal form",
    "Option B": "third normal form",
    "Option C": "first normal form",
    "Option D": "second normal form",
    Answer: "B. third normal form",
    Topic: "Database Normalization",
  },
  {
    Question: "Database locking concept is used to solve the problem of",
    "Option A": "inconsistent data",
    "Option B": "all of the options",
    "Option C": "lost update",
    "Option D": "uncommitted dependency",
    Answer: "B. all of the options",
    Topic: "Database Locking",
  },
  {
    Question: "UML is stands for",
    "Option A": "universal modeling language",
    "Option B": "united modeling language",
    "Option C": "uni modeling language",
    "Option D": "unified modeling language",
    Answer: "D. unified modeling language",
    Topic: "UML (Unified Modeling Language)",
  },
  {
    Question: "Data Manipulation Language (DML) is not to",
    "Option A": "insertion of new information into the database",
    "Option B": "modification of information in the database",
    "Option C": "create information table in the database",
    "Option D": "deletion of information in the database",
    Answer: "C. create information table in the database",
    Topic: "Data Manipulation Language (DML)",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is true regarding Referential Integrity?",
    "Option A":
      "every primary-key value must match a primary-key value in an associated table",
    "Option B":
      "every primary-key value must match a foreign-key value in an associated table",
    "Option C":
      "every foreign-key value must match a foreign-key value in an associated table",
    "Option D":
      "every foreign-key value must match a primary-key value in an associated table",
    Answer:
      "D. every foreign-key value must match a primary-key value in an associated table",
    Topic: "Referential Integrity",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following options is used for the retrieval of data?",
    "Option A": "stack",
    "Option B": "data structure",
    "Option C": "linked list",
    "Option D": "query",
    Answer: "D. query",
    Topic: "Database Concepts",
  },
  {
    Question: "ODBC stands for ______",
    "Option A": "none of above",
    "Option B": "open database connection",
    "Option C": "offline database connection",
    "Option D": "oriented database connection",
    Answer: "B. open database connection",
    Topic: "ODBC (Open Database Connectivity)",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is a unary operation?",
    "Option A": "selection operation",
    "Option B": "primitive operation",
    "Option C": "projection operation",
    "Option D": "generalized selection",
    Answer: "D. generalized selection",
    Topic: "Relational Algebra",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which SQL Query is used to remove a table and all its data from the database?",
    "Option A": "none of these",
    "Option B": "drop table",
    "Option C": "create table",
    "Option D": "alter table",
    Answer: "B. drop table",
    Topic: "SQL Commands",
  },
  {
    Question: "Question",
    "Option A": "Option A",
    "Option B": "Option B",
    "Option C": "Option C",
    "Option D": "Option D",
    Answer: "Answer",
    Topic: "Topic",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In precedence of set operators the expression is evaluated from:",
    "Option A": "left to right",
    "Option B": "right to left",
    "Option C": "left to left",
    "Option D": "right to right",
    Answer: "A. left to right",
    Topic: "Set Operators in SQL",
  },
  {
    Question: "In DBMS, FD stands for _______",
    "Option A": "facilitate data",
    "Option B": "functional data",
    "Option C": "facilitate dependency",
    "Option D": "functional dependency",
    Answer: "D. functional dependency",
    Topic: "Database Concepts",
  },
  {
    Question: "How many types of keys in Database Design?",
    "Option A": "foreign key",
    "Option B": "all of the options",
    "Option C": "candidate key",
    "Option D": "primary key",
    Answer: "B. all of the options",
    Topic: "Database Design",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is based on Multi Valued Dependency?",
    "Option A": "third",
    "Option B": "fourth",
    "Option C": "first",
    "Option D": "second",
    Answer: "B. fourth",
    Topic: "Database Normalization",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is the structure of the Database?",
    "Option A": "table",
    "Option B": "none of these",
    "Option C": "schema",
    "Option D": "relation",
    Answer: "C. schema",
    Topic: "Database Concepts",
  },
  {
    Question: "The minimal set of super key is called",
    "Option A": "primary key",
    "Option B": "secondary key",
    "Option C": "foreign key",
    "Option D": "candidate key",
    Answer: "D. candidate key",
    Topic: "Database Design",
  },
  {
    Question: "_____________ is a classical approach to database design?",
    "Option A": "bottom – up approach",
    "Option B": "top – down approach",
    "Option C": "left – right approach",
    "Option D": "right – left approach",
    Answer: "B. top – down approach",
    Topic: "Database Design",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "___________ refers to the correctness and completeness of the data in a database?",
    "Option A": "data independence",
    "Option B": "data integrity",
    "Option C": "data security",
    "Option D": "data constraint",
    Answer: "B. data integrity",
    Topic: "Database Concepts",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A table that displays data redundancies yields ____________ anomalies",
    "Option A": "insertion",
    "Option B": "deletion",
    "Option C": "update",
    "Option D": "all of the options",
    Answer: "D. all of the options",
    Topic: "Database Anomalies",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A lock that allows concurrent transactions to access different rows of the same table is known as a",
    "Option A": "row-level lock",
    "Option B": "database-level lock",
    "Option C": "field-level lock",
    "Option D": "table-level lock",
    Answer: "C. field-level lock",
    Topic: "Database Locking",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A type of query that is placed within a WHERE or HAVING clause of another query is called",
    "Option A": "multi-query",
    "Option B": "sub query",
    "Option C": "super query",
    "Option D": "master query",
    Answer: "B. sub query",
    Topic: "SQL Subqueries",
  },
  {
    Question: "A form defined",
    "Option A": "none of the options",
    "Option B": "where data is placed on the screen",
    "Option C": "the width of each field",
    "Option D":
      "both where data is placed on the screen and the width of each field",
    Answer: "B. where data is placed on the screen",
    Topic: "Database Forms",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If a piece of data is stored in two places in the database, then",
    "Option A": "it can be more easily accessed",
    "Option B":
      "both storage space is wasted and changing the data in one spot will cause data inconsistency",
    "Option C": "storage space is wasted",
    "Option D": "changing the data in one spot will cause data inconsistency",
    Answer:
      "B. both storage space is wasted and changing the data in one spot will cause data inconsistency",
    Topic: "Database Redundancy",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is a problem of file management system?",
    "Option A": "data redundancy and program dependence",
    "Option B": "all of the options",
    "Option C": "difficult to update",
    "Option D": "lack of data independence",
    Answer: "B. all of the options",
    Topic: "File Management System Issues",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is not an advantage of the database approach",
    "Option A": "elimination of data redundancy",
    "Option B": "ability to associate deleted data",
    "Option C": "increased security and program/data independence",
    "Option D": "all of the above",
    Answer: "D. all of the above",
    Topic: "Database Approach",
  },
  {
    Question: "An audit trail",
    "Option A": "none of the options",
    "Option B": "is the recorded history of operations performed on a file",
    "Option C": "is used to make backup copies",
    "Option D": "can be used to restore lost information",
    Answer: "B. is the recorded history of operations performed on a file",
    Topic: "Database Audit Trail",
  },
  {
    Question: "One approach to standardization storing of data?",
    "Option A": "codasyl specification",
    "Option B": "none of the options",
    "Option C": "MIS",
    "Option D": "structured programming",
    Answer: "A. codasyl specification",
    Topic: "Database Standardization",
  },
  {
    Question: "Report generators are used to",
    "Option A": "store data input by a user",
    "Option B": "answer queries",
    "Option C": "both retrieve information from files and answer queries",
    "Option D": "retrieve information from files",
    Answer: "C. both retrieve information from files and answer queries",
    Topic: "Report Generators",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is true of a network structure?",
    "Option A": "it will be the dominant database of the future",
    "Option B": "it allows a many-to-many relationship",
    "Option C": "it is a physical representation of the data",
    "Option D": "it is conceptually simple",
    Answer: "B. it allows a many-to-many relationship",
    Topic: "Network Database Structure",
  },
  {
    Question: "A record management system",
    "Option A": "can handle many files of information at a time",
    "Option B": "always uses a list as its model",
    "Option C":
      "both can handle many files of information at a time and always uses a list as its model",
    "Option D": "can be used to extract information stored in a computer file",
    Answer: "D. can be used to extract information stored in a computer file",
    Topic: "Record Management System",
  },
  {
    Question: "One data dictionary software package is called",
    "Option A": "db/dc dictionary",
    "Option B": "datapac",
    "Option C": "total",
    "Option D": "access",
    Answer: "A. db/dc dictionary",
    Topic: "Data Dictionary Software",
  },
  {
    Question: "The function of a database is ...",
    "Option A": "to check all input data",
    "Option B": "to output data",
    "Option C": "to collect and organize input data",
    "Option D": "to check all spelling",
    Answer: "C. to collect and organize input data",
    Topic: "Database Function",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A command that lets you change one or more fields in a record is",
    "Option A": "none of the options",
    "Option B": "modify",
    "Option C": "insert",
    "Option D": "lookup",
    Answer: "B. modify",
    Topic: "Database Record Modification",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the language used by most of the DBMSs for helping their users to access data?",
    "Option A": "high-level language",
    "Option B": "4GL",
    "Option C": "query language",
    "Option D": "SQL",
    Answer: "D. SQL",
    Topic: "Database Query Language",
  },
  {
    Question: "Information can be transferred between the DBMS and a",
    "Option A": "spreadsheet program",
    "Option B": "word processor program",
    "Option C": "graphics program",
    "Option D": "all of the options",
    Answer: "D. all of the options",
    Topic: "Data Transfer in DBMS",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The relational database environment has all of the following components except",
    "Option A": "users",
    "Option B": "database",
    "Option C": "query languages",
    "Option D": "separate files",
    Answer: "D. separate files",
    Topic: "Relational Database Environment",
  },
  {
    Question: "The ascending order of a data hierarchy is:",
    "Option A": "bit-byte-file-record-field-database",
    "Option B": "bit-byte-field-record-file-database",
    "Option C": "bit-byte-record-field-file-database",
    "Option D": "byte-bit-field-record-file-database",
    Answer: "B. bit-byte-field-record-file-database",
    Topic: "Data Hierarchy",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Primitive operations common to all record management system include",
    "Option A": "look-up",
    "Option B": "all of the options",
    "Option C": "print",
    "Option D": "sort",
    Answer: "A. look-up",
    Topic: "Primitive Operations in Record Management System",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not a relational database?",
    "Option A": "dbase iv",
    "Option B": "foxpro",
    "Option C": "reflex",
    "Option D": "4th dimension",
    Answer: "C. reflex",
    Topic: "Relational Databases",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A top-to-bottom relationship among the items in a database is established by a",
    "Option A": "hierarchical schema",
    "Option B": "all of the options",
    "Option C": "network schema",
    "Option D": "relational schema",
    Answer: "A. hierarchical schema",
    Topic: "Database Hierarchy",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Choose the RDBMS which supports full-fledged client-server application development",
    "Option A": "dbase v",
    "Option B": "ingress",
    "Option C": "oracle 7.1",
    "Option D": "foxpro 2.1",
    Answer: "C. oracle 7.1",
    Topic: "RDBMS for Client-Server Application Development",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The highest level in the hierarchy of data organization is called",
    "Option A": "data base",
    "Option B": "data record",
    "Option C": "data bank",
    "Option D": "data file",
    Answer: "A. data base",
    Topic: "Data Organization Hierarchy",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The management information system (MIS) structure with one main computer system is called a",
    "Option A": "decentralized mis structure",
    "Option B": "centralized mis structure",
    "Option C": "hierarchical mis structure",
    "Option D": "distributed mis structure",
    Answer: "B. centralized mis structure",
    Topic: "MIS Structure",
  },
  {
    Question: "In the DBMS approach, application programs perform the",
    "Option A": "storage function",
    "Option B": "access control",
    "Option C": "all of the options",
    "Option D": "processing functions",
    Answer: "D. processing functions",
    Topic: "DBMS Approach",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is not true of the traditional approach to information processing",
    "Option A": "it is file-oriented",
    "Option B": "it is inflexible",
    "Option C":
      "there is common sharing of data among the various applications",
    "Option D": "programs are dependent on the file",
    Answer: "C. there is common sharing of data among the various applications",
    Topic: "Traditional Information Processing",
  },
  {
    Question: "Batch processing is appropriate if",
    "Option A": "only a few transactions are involved",
    "Option B": "none of the options",
    "Option C": "large computer system is available",
    "Option D": "only a small computer system is available",
    Answer: "B. none of the options",
    Topic: "Batch Processing",
  },
  {
    Question: "Large collections of files are called",
    "Option A": "sectors",
    "Option B": "database",
    "Option C": "fields",
    "Option D": "records",
    Answer: "B. database",
    Topic: "Large Collection of Files",
  },
  {
    Question: "A transparent DBMS",
    "Option A":
      "both cannot hide sensitive information from users and keep its logical structure hidden from users",
    "Option B": "keeps its physical structure hidden from users",
    "Option C": "cannot hide sensitive information from users",
    "Option D": "keeps its logical structure hidden from users",
    Answer: "B. keeps its physical structure hidden from users",
    Topic: "Transparent DBMS",
  },
  {
    Question: "A file produced by a spreadsheet",
    "Option A": "none of the options",
    "Option B": "is generally stored on disk in an ASCII text format",
    "Option C": "can be used as is by the DBMS",
    "Option D":
      "both is generally stored on disk in an ASCII text format and can be used as is by the DBMS",
    Answer: "B. is generally stored on disk in an ASCII text format",
    Topic: "Spreadsheet Files",
  },
  {
    Question: "The model for a record management system might be",
    "Option A": "all of the options",
    "Option B": "a business form",
    "Option C": "handwritten list",
    "Option D": "a Rolodex card file",
    Answer: "A. all of the options",
    Topic: "Record Management System Model",
  },
  {
    Question: "Database management systems are intended to",
    "Option A": "eliminate data redundancy",
    "Option B": "establish relationships among records in different files",
    "Option C": "manage file access and maintain data integrity",
    "Option D": "all of the options",
    Answer: "D. all of the options",
    Topic: "Database Management Systems",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The language used application programs to request data from the DBMS is referred to as the",
    "Option A": "ddl",
    "Option B": "all of the options",
    "Option C": "dml",
    "Option D": "query language",
    Answer: "C. dml",
    Topic: "Database Query Language",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A set of programs that handle a firm's database responsibilities is called",
    "Option A": "database management system (DBMS)",
    "Option B": "data management system (DMS)",
    "Option C": "all of the options",
    "Option D": "database processing system (DBPS)",
    Answer: "C. all of the options",
    Topic: "Programs for Database Responsibilities",
  },
  {
    Question: "Where is metadata stored in MySQL?",
    "Option A": "in the MySQL database meta",
    "Option B": "in the MySQL database metasql",
    "Option C": "in the MySQL database metadata",
    "Option D": "in the MySQL database MySQL",
    Answer: "D. in the MySQL database MySQL",
    Topic: "MySQL Metadata Storage",
  },
  {
    Question: "What MySQL property is used to create a surrogate key in MySQL?",
    "Option A": "identical",
    "Option B": "unique",
    "Option C": "auto_increment",
    "Option D": "sequence",
    Answer: "C. auto_increment",
    Topic: "MySQL Surrogate Key",
  },
  {
    Question: "A relational database consists of a collection of",
    "Option A": "keys",
    "Option B": "records",
    "Option C": "tables",
    "Option D": "fields",
    Answer: "C. tables",
    Topic: "Relational Database Components",
  },
  {
    Question: "A Database Management System (DBMS) is:",
    "Option A": "collection of data describing one particular enterprise",
    "Option B": "collection of programs to access data",
    "Option C": "all options are correct",
    "Option D": "collection of interrelated data",
    Answer: "C. all options are correct",
    Topic: "Database Management System (DBMS)",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not a level of data abstraction?",
    "Option A": "view level",
    "Option B": "physical level",
    "Option C": "logical level",
    "Option D": "critical level",
    Answer: "D. critical level",
    Topic: "Data Abstraction Levels",
  },
  {
    Question: "Disadvantages of File systems to store data are:",
    "Option A": "data isolation",
    "Option B": "data redundancy and inconsistency",
    "Option C": "difficulty in accessing data",
    "Option D": "all options are correct",
    Answer: "D. all options are correct",
    Topic: "Disadvantages of File Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "In an Entity Relationship Diagram Rectangles represent",
    "Option A": "tables",
    "Option B": "attributes",
    "Option C": "database",
    "Option D": "entity sets",
    Answer: "D. entity sets",
    Topic: "Entity Relationship Diagram Elements",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is the structure of the Database?",
    "Option A": "table",
    "Option B": "schema",
    "Option C": "relation",
    "Option D": "none of these",
    Answer: "B. schema",
    Topic: "Database Structure",
  },
  {
    Question: "The minimal set of super key is called",
    "Option A": "primary key",
    "Option B": "secondary key",
    "Option C": "candidate key",
    "Option D": "foreign key",
    Answer: "C. candidate key",
    Topic: "Minimal Set of Super Key",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A relation that has no partial dependencies is in which normal form",
    "Option A": "first",
    "Option B": "second",
    "Option C": "third",
    "Option D": "BCNF",
    Answer: "B. second",
    Topic: "Normal Form",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A functional dependency between two or more non-key attributes is called",
    "Option A": "transitive dependency",
    "Option B": "partial transitive dependency",
    "Option C": "functional dependency",
    "Option D": "partial functional dependency",
    Answer: "A. transitive dependency",
    Topic: "Functional Dependency",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A logical description of some portion of the database that is required by a user to perform a task is called as",
    "Option A": "system view",
    "Option B": "user view",
    "Option C": "logical view",
    "Option D": "data view",
    Answer: "B. user view",
    Topic: "Logical Description of Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "______________ is a classical approach to database design?",
    "Option A": "left – right approach",
    "Option B": "right – left approach",
    "Option C": "top – down approach",
    "Option D": "bottom – up approach",
    Answer: "C. top – down approach",
    Topic: "Classical Approach to Database Design",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "_____________ refers to the correctness and completeness of the data in a database?",
    "Option A": "data security",
    "Option B": "data integrity",
    "Option C": "data constraint",
    "Option D": "data independence",
    Answer: "B. data integrity",
    Topic: "Data Integrity",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A table that displays data redundancies yields ____________ anomalies",
    "Option A": "insertion",
    "Option B": "deletion",
    "Option C": "update",
    "Option D": "all of the above",
    Answer: "D. all of the above",
    Topic: "Redundancy Anomalies",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A lock that allows concurrent transactions to access different rows of the same table is known as a",
    "Option A": "field-level lock",
    "Option B": "row-level lock",
    "Option C": "table-level lock",
    "Option D": "database-level lock",
    Answer: "A. field-level lock",
    Topic: "Field-Level Lock",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A type of query that is placed within a WHERE or HAVING clause of another query is called",
    "Option A": "super query",
    "Option B": "sub query",
    "Option C": "master query",
    "Option D": "multi-query",
    Answer: "B. sub query",
    Topic: "Sub Query",
  },
  {
    Question: "A transaction completes its execution is said to be",
    "Option A": "saved",
    "Option B": "loaded",
    "Option C": "rolled",
    "Option D": "committed",
    Answer: "D. committed",
    Topic: "Transaction Completion",
  },
  {
    Question: "In mathematical term Row is referred to as",
    "Option A": "relation",
    "Option B": "attribute",
    "Option C": "tuple",
    "Option D": "domain",
    Answer: "C. tuple",
    Topic: "Mathematical Term: Row",
  },
  {
    Question: "_______ allow us to identify uniquely a tuple in the relation.",
    "Option A": "superkey",
    "Option B": "domain",
    "Option C": "attribute",
    "Option D": "schema",
    Answer: "A. superkey",
    Topic: "Identification of Tuple",
  },
  {
    Question: "Minimal Superkeys are called",
    "Option A": "schema keys",
    "Option B": "candidate keys",
    "Option C": "domain keys",
    "Option D": "attribute keys",
    Answer: "B. candidate keys",
    Topic: "Minimal Superkeys",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not Modification of the Database",
    "Option A": "deletion",
    "Option B": "insertion",
    "Option C": "sorting",
    "Option D": "updating",
    Answer: "C. sorting",
    Topic: "Modification of Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is Relation-algebra Operation",
    "Option A": "select",
    "Option B": "union",
    "Option C": "rename",
    "Option D": "all of the above",
    Answer: "D. all of the above",
    Topic: "Relation-Algebra Operation",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following in not Outer join?",
    "Option A": "left outer join",
    "Option B": "right outer join",
    "Option C": "full outer join",
    "Option D": "all of the above",
    Answer: "D. all of the above",
    Topic: "Outer Join",
  },
  {
    Question: "Who proposed the relational model?",
    "Option A": "bill gates",
    "Option B": "e.f. codd",
    "Option C": "herman hollerith",
    "Option D": "charles babbage",
    Answer: "B. e.f. codd",
    Topic: "Proposer of Relational Model",
  },
  {
    Question: "Set of permitted values of each attribute is called",
    "Option A": "domain",
    "Option B": "tuple",
    "Option C": "relation",
    "Option D": "schema",
    Answer: "A. domain",
    Topic: "Set of Permitted Values",
  },
  {
    Question: "Logical design of the database is called",
    "Option A": "database instance",
    "Option B": "database snapshot",
    "Option C": "database schema",
    "Option D": "all of the above",
    Answer: "C. database schema",
    Topic: "Logical Design of Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Snapshot of the data in the database at a given instant of time is called",
    "Option A": "database schema",
    "Option B": "database instance",
    "Option C": "database snapshot",
    "Option D": "all of the above",
    Answer: "B. database instance",
    Topic: "Snapshot of Database Data",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not Unary operation?",
    "Option A": "select",
    "Option B": "project",
    "Option C": "rename",
    "Option D": "union",
    Answer: "D. union",
    Topic: "Unary Operation",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not binary operation?",
    "Option A": "union",
    "Option B": "project",
    "Option C": "set difference",
    "Option D": "cartesian product",
    Answer: "B. project",
    Topic: "Non-Binary Operation",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is correct regarding Aggregate functions?",
    "Option A":
      "it takes a list of values and returns a single value as a result",
    "Option B":
      "it takes a list of values and returns a list of values as a result",
    "Option C":
      "it takes a single value and returns a list of values as a result",
    "Option D":
      "it takes a single value and returns a single value as a result",
    Answer:
      "A. it takes a list of values and returns a single value as a result",
    Topic: "Aggregate Functions",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following statements contains an error?",
    "Option A": "select * from emp where empid = 10003;",
    "Option B": "select empid from emp where empid = 10006;",
    "Option C": "select empid from emp;",
    "Option D": "select empid where empid = 1009 and lastname = ‘geller’;",
    Answer: "D. select empid where empid = 1009 and lastname = ‘geller’;",
    Topic: "SQL Statement Error",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "allows a system administrator to associate a function with a relation; the function returns a predicate that must be added to any query that uses the relation.",
    "Option A": "openid",
    "Option B": "single-site system",
    "Option C": "security assertion markup language (SAML)",
    "Option D": "virtual private database (VPD)",
    Answer: "D. virtual private database (VPD)",
    Topic: "Database Security",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If a node is locked in ____________ then explicit locking is being done at a lower level, with exclusive-mode or shared-mode locks.",
    "Option A": "intention lock modes",
    "Option B": "intention-shared-exclusive mode",
    "Option C": "intention-exclusive (IX) mode",
    "Option D": "intention-shared (IS) mode",
    Answer: "C. intention-exclusive (IX) mode",
    Topic: "Explicit Locking",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In SQL the spaces at the end of the string are removed by __________ function.",
    "Option A": "upper",
    "Option B": "string",
    "Option C": "trim",
    "Option D": "lower",
    Answer: "C. trim",
    Topic: "SQL String Operation",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "VPD provides authorization at the level of specific tuples, or rows, of a relation, and is therefore said to be a ______________ mechanism.",
    "Option A": "row-level authorization",
    "Option B": "column-level authentication",
    "Option C": "row-type authentication",
    "Option D": "authorization security",
    Answer: "A. row-level authorization",
    Topic: "VPD Authentication Mechanism",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If a node is locked in _______________ the subtree rooted by that node is locked explicitly in shared mode, and that explicit locking is being done at a lower level with exclusive-mode locks.",
    "Option A": "intention lock modes",
    "Option B": "shared and intention-exclusive (SIX) mode",
    "Option C": "intention-exclusive (IX) mode",
    "Option D": "intention-shared (IS) mode",
    Answer: "B. shared and intention-exclusive (SIX) mode",
    Topic: "Explicit Locking",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "____________ is widely used today for protecting data in transit in a variety of applications such as data transfer on the Internet, and on cellular phone networks.",
    "Option A": "encryption",
    "Option B": "data mining",
    "Option C": "internet security",
    "Option D": "architectural security",
    Answer: "A. encryption",
    Topic: "Data Encryption",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The ____________ requires that each transaction Ti executes in two or three different phases in its lifetime, depending on whether it is a read-only or an update transaction.",
    "Option A": "validation protocol",
    "Option B": "validation-based protocol",
    "Option C": "timestamp protocol",
    "Option D": "timestamp-ordering protocol",
    Answer: "A. validation protocol",
    Topic: "Transaction Validation",
  },
  {
    Question: "The union operation is represented by",
    "Option A": "∩",
    "Option B": "u",
    "Option C": "–",
    "Option D": "*",
    Answer: "B. u",
    Topic: "Union Operation",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In a database where encryption is applied, the data cannot be handled by the unauthorized user without",
    "Option A": "dictionary attacks",
    "Option B": "database attacks",
    "Option C": "minor attacks",
    "Option D": "random attacks",
    Answer: "A. dictionary attacks",
    Topic: "Encryption of Small Values",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "___________ denotes the largest timestamp of any transaction that executed write(Q) successfully.",
    "Option A": "w-timestamp(q)",
    "Option B": "r-timestamp(q)",
    "Option C": "rw-timestamp(q)",
    "Option D": "wr-timestamp(q)",
    Answer: "A. w-timestamp(q)",
    Topic: "Transaction Timestamp",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The intersection operator is used to get the ___________ tuples.",
    "Option A": "diﬀerent",
    "Option B": "common",
    "Option C": "all",
    "Option D": "repeating",
    Answer: "B. common",
    Topic: "Intersection Operator",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is not a property of a good encryption technique?",
    "Option A":
      "relatively simple for authorized users to encrypt and decrypt data",
    "Option B":
      "decryption key is extremely diﬃcult for an intruder to determine",
    "Option C":
      "encryption depends on a parameter of the algorithm called the encryption key",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. none of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Good Encryption Technique",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The most recent version of standard SQL prescribed by the American National Standards Institute is",
    "Option A": "sql 2016",
    "Option B": "sql 2002",
    "Option C": "sql – 4",
    "Option D": "sql2",
    Answer: "A. sql 2016",
    Topic: "ANSI-Standard SQL",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If we want to retain all duplicates, we must write _______________ in place of union.",
    "Option A": "union all",
    "Option B": "union some",
    "Option C": "intersect all",
    "Option D": "intersect some",
    Answer: "A. union all",
    Topic: "Retaining Duplicates in Union",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In which of the following encryption key is used to encrypt and decrypt the data?",
    "Option A": "public key",
    "Option B": "private key",
    "Option C": "symmetric key",
    "Option D": "asymmetric key",
    Answer: "C. symmetric key",
    Topic: "Encryption Key",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "ANSI-standard SQL allows the use of special operators in conjunction with the WHERE clause. A special operator used to check whether an attribute value is null is",
    "Option A": "between",
    "Option B": "is null",
    "Option C": "like",
    "Option D": "in",
    Answer: "B. is null",
    Topic: "NULL Predicate",
  },
  {
    Question: "The number of attributes in relation is called as its",
    "Option A": "cardinality",
    "Option B": "degree",
    "Option C": "tuples",
    "Option D": "entity",
    Answer: "B. degree",
    Topic: "Attributes in Relation",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Encryption of small values, such as identifiers or names, is made complicated by the possibility of ________________.",
    "Option A": "dictionary attacks",
    "Option B": "database attacks",
    "Option C": "minor attacks",
    "Option D": "random attacks",
    Answer: "A. dictionary attacks",
    Topic: "Encryption of Small Values",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A lock that prevents the use of any tables in the database from one transaction while another transaction is being processed is called a",
    "Option A": "database-level lock",
    "Option B": "table-level lock",
    "Option C": "page-level lock",
    "Option D": "row-level lock",
    Answer: "A. database-level lock",
    Topic: "Database-Level Lock",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "_____________ clause is an additional filter that is applied to the result.",
    "Option A": "select",
    "Option B": "group-by",
    "Option C": "having",
    "Option D": "order by",
    Answer: "C. having",
    Topic: "HAVING Clause",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which one of the following uses a 128-bit round key to encrypt the data using XOR and use it in reverse to decrypt it?",
    "Option A": "round key algorithm",
    "Option B": "public key algorithm",
    "Option C": "advanced encryption standard",
    "Option D": "asymmetric key algorithm",
    Answer: "C. advanced encryption standard",
    Topic: "Advanced Encryption Standard",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A condition that occurs when two transactions wait for each other to unlock data is known as a(n)",
    "Option A": "shared lock",
    "Option B": "exclusive lock",
    "Option C": "binary lock",
    "Option D": "deadlock",
    Answer: "D. deadlock",
    Topic: "Deadlock",
  },
  {
    Question: "_______________ joins are SQL server default",
    "Option A": "outer",
    "Option B": "inner",
    "Option C": "equi",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. inner",
    Topic: "Inner Join",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following requires no password travel across the internet?",
    "Option A": "readable system",
    "Option B": "manipulation system",
    "Option C": "challenge–response system",
    "Option D": "response system",
    Answer: "C. challenge–response system",
    Topic: "Challenge–Response System",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The ______________ is essentially used to search for patterns in the target string.",
    "Option A": "like predicate",
    "Option B": "null predicate",
    "Option C": "in predicate",
    "Option D": "out predicate",
    Answer: "A. like predicate",
    Topic: "LIKE Predicate",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In case of any shut down during the transaction before commit, which of the following statements is done automatically?",
    "Option A": "view",
    "Option B": "commit",
    "Option C": "rollback",
    "Option D": "flashback",
    Answer: "C. rollback",
    Topic: "Transaction Rollback",
  },
  {
    Question: "What are the correct features of a distributed database?",
    "Option A": "is always connected to the internet",
    "Option B": "always requires more than three machines",
    "Option C": "users see the data in one global schema.",
    "Option D":
      "have to specify the physical location of the data when an update is done",
    Answer: "C. users see the data in one global schema.",
    Topic: "Distributed Database Features",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The ____________ policy allows a transaction to commit even if it has modified some blocks that have not yet been written back to disk.",
    "Option A": "force",
    "Option B": "no-force",
    "Option C": "steal",
    "Option D": "no-steal",
    Answer: "B. no-force",
    Topic: "Write Policy in Transaction",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In order to maintain consistency during transactions, the database provides",
    "Option A": "commit",
    "Option B": "atomic",
    "Option C": "flashback",
    "Option D": "retain",
    Answer: "B. atomic",
    Topic: "Consistency in Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Each tablespace in an Oracle database consists of one or more files called",
    "Option A": "files",
    "Option B": "name space",
    "Option C": "datafiles",
    "Option D": "pfile",
    Answer: "C. datafiles",
    Topic: "Oracle Tablespace",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The ____________ policy allows multiple updates to accumulate on a block before it is output to stable storage, which can reduce the number of output operations greatly for frequently updated blocks.",
    "Option A": "force",
    "Option B": "no-force",
    "Option C": "steal",
    "Option D": "no-steal",
    Answer: "B. no-force",
    Topic: "Write Policy in Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question: "A transaction completes its execution is said to be",
    "Option A": "committed",
    "Option B": "aborted",
    "Option C": "rolled back",
    "Option D": "failed",
    Answer: "A. committed",
    Topic: "Transaction Completion",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The management information system (MIS) structure with one main computer system is called a",
    "Option A": "hierarchical mis structure",
    "Option B": "distributed mis structure",
    "Option C": "centralized mis structure",
    "Option D": "decentralized mis structure",
    Answer: "C. centralized mis structure",
    Topic: "Management Information System Structure",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The ____________ policy allows the system to write modified blocks to disk even if the transactions that made those modifications have not all committed.",
    "Option A": "force",
    "Option B": "no-force",
    "Option C": "steal",
    "Option D": "no-steal",
    Answer: "C. steal",
    Topic: "Write Policy in Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is used to get back all the transactions back after rollback?",
    "Option A": "commit",
    "Option B": "rollback",
    "Option C": "flashback",
    "Option D": "redo",
    Answer: "C. flashback",
    Topic: "Transaction Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Choose the RDBMS which supports full-fledged client-server application development",
    "Option A": "dbase v",
    "Option B": "oracle 7.1",
    "Option C": "foxpro 2.1",
    "Option D": "ingress",
    Answer: "B. oracle 7.1",
    Topic: "RDBMS for Client-Server Development",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The _______________ contains a list of blocks that have been updated in the database buffer.",
    "Option A": "latches",
    "Option B": "swap space",
    "Option C": "dirty block",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. dirty block",
    Topic: "Database Buffer Management",
  },
  {
    Question: "____________ will undo all statements up to commit?",
    "Option A": "transaction",
    "Option B": "flashback",
    "Option C": "rollback",
    "Option D": "abort",
    Answer: "C. rollback",
    Topic: "Undoing Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question: "One approach to standardization storing of data?",
    "Option A": "mis",
    "Option B": "structured programming",
    "Option C": "codasyl specification",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. codasyl specification",
    Topic: "Standardization in Data Storage",
  },
  {
    Question: "The silicon chips used for data processing are called",
    "Option A": "ram chips",
    "Option B": "rom chips",
    "Option C": "microprocessors",
    "Option D": "prom chips",
    Answer: "D. prom chips",
    Topic: "Silicon Chips for Data Processing",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not an integrity constraint?",
    "Option A": "not null",
    "Option B": "positive",
    "Option C": "unique",
    "Option D": "check 'predicate'",
    Answer: "B. positive",
    Topic: "Integrity Constraint",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The highest level in the hierarchy of data organization is called",
    "Option A": "data bank",
    "Option B": "data base",
    "Option C": "data file",
    "Option D": "data record",
    Answer: "B. data base",
    Topic: "Hierarchy in Data Organization",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is used for manufacturing chips?",
    "Option A": "control bus",
    "Option B": "control unit",
    "Option C": "parity unit",
    "Option D": "semiconductor",
    Answer: "D. semiconductor",
    Topic: "Manufacturing Chips",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Domain constraints, functional dependency, and referential integrity are special forms of",
    "Option A": "foreign key",
    "Option B": "primary key",
    "Option C": "assertion",
    "Option D": "referential constraint",
    Answer: "C. assertion",
    Topic: "Data Constraints",
  },
  {
    Question: "An audit trail",
    "Option A": "is used to make backup copies",
    "Option B": "is the recorded history of operations performed on a file",
    "Option C": "can be used to restore lost information",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. is the recorded history of operations performed on a file",
    Topic: "Audit Trail",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What was the name of the first commercially available microprocessor chip?",
    "Option A": "intel 308",
    "Option B": "intel 33",
    "Option C": "intel 4004",
    "Option D": "motorola 639",
    Answer: "C. intel 4004",
    Topic: "First Microprocessor Chip",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is the right syntax for the assertion?",
    "Option A": "create assertion 'assertion-name' check 'predicate';",
    "Option B": "create assertion check 'predicate' 'assertion-name';",
    "Option C": "create assertions 'predicates';",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. create assertion 'assertion-name' check 'predicate';",
    Topic: "Assertion Syntax",
  },
  {
    Question: "Large collection of files are called",
    "Option A": "fields",
    "Option B": "records",
    "Option C": "database",
    "Option D": "sectors",
    Answer: "C. database",
    Topic: "Large Collection of Files",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The magnetic storage chip used to provide non-volatile direct access storage of data and that have no moving parts are known as",
    "Option A": "magnetic core memory",
    "Option B": "magnetic tape memory",
    "Option C": "magnetic disk memory",
    "Option D": "magnetic bubble memory",
    Answer: "D. magnetic bubble memory",
    Topic: "Non-volatile Direct Access Storage",
  },
  {
    Question: "Data integrity constraints are used to:",
    "Option A": "control who is allowed access to the data",
    "Option B": "ensure that duplicate records are not entered into the table",
    "Option C":
      "improve the quality of data entered for a specific property (i.e., table column)",
    "Option D": "prevent users from changing the values stored in the table",
    Answer:
      "C. improve the quality of data entered for a specific property (i.e., table column)",
    Topic: "Data Integrity Constraints",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is not true of the traditional approach to information processing?",
    "Option A":
      "there is common sharing of data among the various applications",
    "Option B": "it is file oriented",
    "Option C": "programs are dependent on the file",
    "Option D": "it is inflexible",
    Answer: "A. there is common sharing of data among the various applications",
    Topic: "Traditional Approach to Information Processing",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The ALU of a computer normally contains a number of high-speed storage elements called",
    "Option A": "semiconductor memory",
    "Option B": "registers",
    "Option C": "hard disks",
    "Option D": "magnetic disk",
    Answer: "B. registers",
    Topic: "ALU in Computer",
  },
  {
    Question: "Dates must be specified in the format",
    "Option A": "mm/dd/yy",
    "Option B": "yyyy/mm/dd",
    "Option C": "dd/mm/yy",
    "Option D": "yy/dd/mm",
    Answer: "B. yyyy/mm/dd",
    Topic: "Date Format",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of these is not a feature of the Hierarchical model?",
    "Option A": "organizes the data in a tree-like structure",
    "Option B": "parent node can have any number of child nodes",
    "Option C": "root node does not have any parent",
    "Option D": "child node can have any number of parent nodes",
    Answer: "D. child node can have any number of parent nodes",
    Topic: "Features of Hierarchical Model",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A dump of the database contents is also referred to as an _______________ dump.",
    "Option A": "archival",
    "Option B": "fuzzy",
    "Option C": "SQL",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. archival",
    Topic: "Database Dump",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A ____________ on an attribute of a relation is a data structure that allows the database system to find those tuples in the relation that have a specified value for that attribute efficiently, without scanning through all the tuples of the relation.",
    "Option A": "index",
    "Option B": "reference",
    "Option C": "assertion",
    "Option D": "timestamp",
    Answer: "A. index",
    Topic: "Index in Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of these data models is an extension of the relational data model?",
    "Option A": "object-oriented data model",
    "Option B": "object-relational data model",
    "Option C": "semi-structured data model",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. object-relational data model",
    Topic: "Extension of Relational Data Model",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "______________ dump, writes out SQL DDL statements and SQL insert statements to a file, which can then be reexecuted to re-create the database.",
    "Option A": "archival",
    "Option B": "fuzzy",
    "Option C": "SQL",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. SQL",
    Topic: "Database Dump Schemes",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is used to store movie and image files?",
    "Option A": "clob",
    "Option B": "blob",
    "Option C": "binary",
    "Option D": "image",
    Answer: "B. blob",
    Topic: "Storage for Movie and Image Files",
  },
  {
    Question: "The information about data in a database is called",
    "Option A": "metadata",
    "Option B": "hyper data",
    "Option C": "tera data",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. metadata",
    Topic: "Information About Data in a Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "____________ dump schemes have been developed that allow transactions to be active while the dump is in progress.",
    "Option A": "archival",
    "Option B": "fuzzy",
    "Option C": "SQL",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. fuzzy",
    Topic: "Fuzzy Dump Schemes",
  },
  {
    Question: "The user-defined data type can be created using",
    "Option A": "create datatype",
    "Option B": "create data",
    "Option C": "create definetype",
    "Option D": "create type",
    Answer: "D. create type",
    Topic: "User-Defined Data Type Creation",
  },
  {
    Question: "A data dictionary is a special file that contains?",
    "Option A": "the names of all fields in all files",
    "Option B": "the data types of all fields in all files",
    "Option C": "the widths of all fields in all files",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Data Dictionary",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "ARIES uses a ____________ to identify log records, and stores it in database pages.",
    "Option A": "log sequence number",
    "Option B": "log number",
    "Option C": "lock number",
    "Option D": "sequence",
    Answer: "B. log number",
    Topic: "ARIES Log Identification",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Values of one type can be converted to another domain using which of the following?",
    "Option A": "cast",
    "Option B": "drop type",
    "Option C": "alter type",
    "Option D": "convert",
    Answer: "A. cast",
    Topic: "Type Conversion",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The DBMS acts as an interface between what two components of an enterprise-class database system?",
    "Option A": "database application and the database",
    "Option B": "data and the database",
    "Option C": "the user and the database application",
    "Option D": "database application and SQL",
    Answer: "A. database application and the database",
    Topic: "DBMS Interface",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "ARIES supports ______________ operations, which are physical in that the affected page is physically identified but can be logical within the page.",
    "Option A": "physiological redo",
    "Option B": "physiological undo",
    "Option C": "logical redo",
    "Option D": "logical undo",
    Answer: "A. physiological redo",
    Topic: "ARIES Operations",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following closely resembles Create view?",
    "Option A": "create table ...like",
    "Option B": "create table ... as",
    "Option C": "with data",
    "Option D": "create view as",
    Answer: "B. create table ... as",
    Topic: "View Creation Syntax",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A relational database system needs to maintain data about the relations, such as the schema of the relations. This is called",
    "Option A": "metadata",
    "Option B": "catalog",
    "Option C": "log",
    "Option D": "data dictionary",
    Answer: "A. metadata",
    Topic: "Relational Database System Information",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "______________ is used to minimize unnecessary redos during recovery.",
    "Option A": "dirty page table",
    "Option B": "page table",
    "Option C": "dirty redo",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. dirty page table",
    Topic: "Minimizing Redos during Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In contemporary databases, the top level of the hierarchy consists of ____________ each of which can contain _____________.",
    "Option A": "catalogs, schemas",
    "Option B": "schemas, catalogs",
    "Option C": "environment, schemas",
    "Option D": "schemas, environment",
    Answer: "A. catalogs, schemas",
    Topic: "Contemporary Database Hierarchy",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Relational schemas and other metadata about relations are stored in a structure called the",
    "Option A": "metadata",
    "Option B": "catalog",
    "Option C": "log",
    "Option D": "data dictionary",
    Answer: "D. data dictionary",
    Topic: "Storage of Relational Schemas",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "____________ scheme that records only information about dirty pages and associated information and does not even require writing dirty pages to disk.",
    "Option A": "fuzzy logic",
    "Option B": "checkpoints",
    "Option C": "fuzzy-checkpoint",
    "Option D": "logical checkpoint",
    Answer: "C. fuzzy-checkpoint",
    Topic: "Fuzzy Checkpoint Scheme",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The database administrator who authorizes all the new users, modifies the database, and takes grants privilege is",
    "Option A": "super user",
    "Option B": "administrator",
    "Option C": "operator of operating system",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Database Administrator Role",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "______________ is the collection of memory structures and Oracle background processes that operate against an Oracle database.",
    "Option A": "database",
    "Option B": "instance",
    "Option C": "tablespace",
    "Option D": "segment",
    Answer: "B. instance",
    Topic: "Components of Oracle Database System",
  },
  {
    Question: "Column header is referred to as",
    "Option A": "table",
    "Option B": "domain",
    "Option C": "attributes",
    "Option D": "relation",
    Answer: "C. attributes",
    Topic: "Column Header Terminology",
  },
  {
    Question: "_______ allows us to identify uniquely a tuple in the relation.",
    "Option A": "schema",
    "Option B": "superkey",
    "Option C": "domain",
    "Option D": "attribute",
    Answer: "B. superkey",
    Topic: "Identifying Tuples in a Relation",
  },
  {
    Question: "Minimal Superkeys are called",
    "Option A": "schema keys",
    "Option B": "attribute keys",
    "Option C": "candidate keys",
    "Option D": "domain keys",
    Answer: "C. candidate keys",
    Topic: "Minimal Superkeys",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not a Modification of the Database",
    "Option A": "updating",
    "Option B": "sorting",
    "Option C": "deletion",
    "Option D": "insertion",
    Answer: "B. sorting",
    Topic: "Modification of the Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not an Outer join?",
    "Option A": "left outer join",
    "Option B": "full outer join",
    "Option C": "all of the options",
    "Option D": "right outer join",
    Answer: "C. all of the options",
    Topic: "Outer Joins",
  },
  {
    Question: "Set of permitted values of each attribute is called",
    "Option A": "tuple",
    "Option B": "schema",
    "Option C": "domain",
    "Option D": "relation",
    Answer: "C. domain",
    Topic: "Set of Permitted Values",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is true regarding Null Value?",
    "Option A": "null<0",
    "Option B": "null=0",
    "Option C": "null<>0",
    "Option D": "null>0",
    Answer: "C. null<>0",
    Topic: "Null Value Comparison",
  },
  {
    Question: "Logical design of the database is called",
    "Option A": "all of the options",
    "Option B": "database schema",
    "Option C": "database instance",
    "Option D": "database snapshot",
    Answer: "B. database schema",
    Topic: "Logical Design of Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Snapshot of the data in the database at a given instant of time is called",
    "Option A": "database instance",
    "Option B": "all of the options",
    "Option C": "database schema",
    "Option D": "database snapshot",
    Answer: "A. database instance",
    Topic: "Snapshot of Data in Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not a Unary operation?",
    "Option A": "rename",
    "Option B": "union",
    "Option C": "select",
    "Option D": "project",
    Answer: "B. union",
    Topic: "Unary Operation",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not a binary operation?",
    "Option A": "union",
    "Option B": "set difference",
    "Option C": "cartesian product",
    "Option D": "project",
    Answer: "D. project",
    Topic: "Non-Binary Operation",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is correct regarding Aggregate functions?",
    "Option A": "it takes a single value and returns a single value as result",
    "Option B":
      "it takes a list of values and return a single values as result",
    "Option C":
      "it takes a list of values and return a list of values as result",
    "Option D":
      "it takes a single value and returns a list of values as result",
    Answer: "B. it takes a list of values and return a single values as result",
    Topic: "Aggregate Functions",
  },
  {
    Question: "The Primary key must be",
    "Option A": "non-null",
    "Option B": "unique",
    "Option C": "option a or b",
    "Option D": "option a and b",
    Answer: "D. option a and b",
    Topic: "Primary Key Characteristics",
  },
  {
    Question: "A command to remove a relation from an SQL database",
    "Option A": "delete table",
    "Option B": "erase table",
    "Option C": "alter table",
    "Option D": "drop table",
    Answer: "D. drop table",
    Topic: "Removing a Relation in SQL Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not an Aggregate function?",
    "Option A": "select",
    "Option B": "avg",
    "Option C": "min",
    "Option D": "max",
    Answer: "A. select",
    Topic: "Non-Aggregate Function",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The attribute that can be divided into other attributes is called",
    "Option A": "composite attribute",
    "Option B": "derived attribute",
    "Option C": "simple attribute",
    "Option D": "multi-valued attribute",
    Answer: "A. composite attribute",
    Topic: "Divisible Attributes",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is ACID properties of Transactions?",
    "Option A": "atomicity, consistency, isolation, database",
    "Option B": "automatically, concurrency, isolation, durability",
    "Option C": "atomicity, consistency, isolation, durability",
    "Option D": "atomicity, consistency, inconsistent, durability",
    Answer: "C. atomicity, consistency, isolation, durability",
    Topic: "ACID Properties of Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If every non-key attribute is functionally dependent on the primary key, the relation will be in",
    "Option A": "fourth formal form",
    "Option B": "third normal form",
    "Option C": "first normal form",
    "Option D": "second normal form",
    Answer: "B. third normal form",
    Topic: "Normal Form of a Relation",
  },
  {
    Question: "Database locking concept is used to solve the problem of",
    "Option A": "inconsistent data",
    "Option B": "all of the options",
    "Option C": "lost update",
    "Option D": "uncommitted dependency",
    Answer: "B. all of the options",
    Topic: "Database Locking Purpose",
  },
  {
    Question: "UML is stands for",
    "Option A": "universal modeling language",
    "Option B": "united modeling language",
    "Option C": "uni modeling language",
    "Option D": "unified modeling language",
    Answer: "D. unified modeling language",
    Topic: "UML",
  },
  {
    Question: "Data Manipulation Language (DML) is not to",
    "Option A": "insertion of new information into the database",
    "Option B": "modification of information in the database",
    "Option C": "create information table in the database",
    "Option D": "deletion of information in the database",
    Answer: "C. create information table in the database",
    Topic: "DML Purpose",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is true regarding Referential Integrity?",
    "Option A":
      "every primary-key value must match a primary-key value in an associated table",
    "Option B":
      "every primary-key value must match a foreign-key value in an associated table",
    "Option C":
      "every foreign-key value must match a foreign-key value in an associated table",
    "Option D":
      "every foreign-key value must match a primary-key value in an associated table",
    Answer:
      "D. every foreign-key value must match a primary-key value in an associated table",
    Topic: "Referential Integrity",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following options is used for the retrieval of data?",
    "Option A": "stack",
    "Option B": "data structure",
    "Option C": "linked list",
    "Option D": "query",
    Answer: "D. query",
    Topic: "Retrieval of Data",
  },
  {
    Question: "ODBC stands for ______",
    "Option A": "none of above",
    "Option B": "open database connection",
    "Option C": "offline database connection",
    "Option D": "oriented database connection",
    Answer: "B. open database connection",
    Topic: "ODBC",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is a unary operation?",
    "Option A": "selection operation",
    "Option B": "primitive operation",
    "Option C": "projection operation",
    "Option D": "generalized selection",
    Answer: "D. generalized selection",
    Topic: "Unary Operation",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which SQL Query is used to remove a table and all its data from the database?",
    "Option A": "none of these",
    "Option B": "drop table",
    "Option C": "create table",
    "Option D": "alter table",
    Answer: "B. drop table",
    Topic: "Removing a Table and Its Data",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In the precedence of set operators, the expression is evaluated from:",
    "Option A": "left to right",
    "Option B": "right to left",
    "Option C": "left to left",
    "Option D": "right to right",
    Answer: "A. left to right",
    Topic: "Precedence of Set Operators",
  },
  {
    Question: "In DBMS, FD stands for _______",
    "Option A": "facilitate data",
    "Option B": "functional data",
    "Option C": "facilitate dependency",
    "Option D": "functional dependency",
    Answer: "D. functional dependency",
    Topic: "FD in DBMS",
  },
  {
    Question: "How many types of keys in Database Design?",
    "Option A": "foreign key",
    "Option B": "all of the options",
    "Option C": "candidate key",
    "Option D": "primary key",
    Answer: "B. all of the options",
    Topic: "Types of Keys in Database Design",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is based on Multi Valued Dependency?",
    "Option A": "third",
    "Option B": "fourth",
    "Option C": "first",
    "Option D": "second",
    Answer: "B. fourth",
    Topic: "Multi Valued Dependency",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is the structure of the Database?",
    "Option A": "table",
    "Option B": "none of these",
    "Option C": "schema",
    "Option D": "relation",
    Answer: "C. schema",
    Topic: "Structure of the Database",
  },
  {
    Question: "The minimal set of super key is called",
    "Option A": "primary key",
    "Option B": "secondary key",
    "Option C": "foreign key",
    "Option D": "candidate key",
    Answer: "D. candidate key",
    Topic: "Minimal Set of Super Key",
  },
  {
    Question: "_____________ is a classical approach to database design?",
    "Option A": "bottom – up approach",
    "Option B": "top – down approach",
    "Option C": "left – right approach",
    "Option D": "right – left approach",
    Answer: "B. top – down approach",
    Topic: "Classical Approach to Database Design",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "_____________ refers to the correctness and completeness of the data in a database?",
    "Option A": "data independence",
    "Option B": "data integrity",
    "Option C": "data security",
    "Option D": "data constraint",
    Answer: "B. data integrity",
    Topic: "Database Correctness and Completeness",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A table that displays data redundancies yields ____________ anomalies",
    "Option A": "insertion",
    "Option B": "deletion",
    "Option C": "update",
    "Option D": "all of the options",
    Answer: "D. all of the options",
    Topic: "Redundancy-Induced Anomalies",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A lock that allows concurrent transactions to access different rows of the same table is known as a",
    "Option A": "row-level lock",
    "Option B": "database-level lock",
    "Option C": "field-level lock",
    "Option D": "table-level lock",
    Answer: "C. field-level lock",
    Topic: "Type of Database Lock",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A type of query that is placed within a WHERE or HAVING clause of another query is called",
    "Option A": "multi-query",
    "Option B": "sub query",
    "Option C": "super query",
    "Option D": "master query",
    Answer: "B. sub query",
    Topic: "Query Placement within Another Query",
  },
  {
    Question: "A form defined",
    "Option A": "none of the options",
    "Option B": "where data is placed on the screen",
    "Option C": "the width of each field",
    "Option D":
      "both where data is placed on the screen and the width of each field",
    Answer: "B. where data is placed on the screen",
    Topic: "Form Definition",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If a piece of data is stored in two places in the database, then",
    "Option A": "in can be more easily accessed",
    "Option B":
      "both storage space is wasted and changing the data in one spot will cause data inconsistency",
    "Option C": "storage space is wasted",
    "Option D": "changing the data in one spot will cause data inconsistency",
    Answer:
      "B. both storage space is wasted and changing the data in one spot will cause data inconsistency",
    Topic: "Data Redundancy Consequences",
  },

  {
    Question:
      "When a collection of various computers seems a single coherent system to its client, then it is called",
    "Option A": "computer network",
    "Option B": "distributed system",
    "Option C": "both (a) and (b)",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. distributed system",
    Topic: "Computer Networks",
  },
  {
    Question: "Two devices are in a network if",
    "Option A":
      "a process in one device is able to exchange information with a process in another device",
    "Option B": "a process is running on both devices",
    "Option C":
      "pids of the processes running on different devices are the same",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer:
      "A. a process in one device is able to exchange information with a process in another device",
    Topic: "Network Devices",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which one of the following computer networks is built on the top of another network?",
    "Option A": "prior network",
    "Option B": "chief network",
    "Option C": "prime network",
    "Option D": "overlay network",
    Answer: "D. overlay network",
    Topic: "Overlay Networks",
  },
  {
    Question: "In a computer network, nodes are",
    "Option A": "the computer that originates the data",
    "Option B": "the computer that routes the data",
    "Option C": "the computer that terminates the data",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Nodes in Computer Network",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Communication channel is shared by all the machines on the network in",
    "Option A": "broadcast network",
    "Option B": "unicast network",
    "Option C": "multicast network",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. broadcast network",
    Topic: "Communication Channel Sharing",
  },
  {
    Question: "Bluetooth is an example of",
    "Option A": "personal area network",
    "Option B": "local area network",
    "Option C": "virtual private network",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. personal area network",
    Topic: "Bluetooth Example",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A _____ is a device that forwards packets between networks by processing the routing information included in the packet.",
    "Option A": "bridge",
    "Option B": "firewall",
    "Option C": "router",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. router",
    Topic: "Routing in Networks",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A list of protocols used by a system, one protocol per layer, is called",
    "Option A": "protocol architecture",
    "Option B": "protocol stack",
    "Option C": "protocol suit",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. protocol stack",
    Topic: "Protocol Stack",
  },
  {
    Question: "Network congestion occurs",
    "Option A": "in case of traffic overloading",
    "Option B": "when a system terminates",
    "Option C": "when the connection between two nodes terminates",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. in case of traffic overloading",
    Topic: "Network Congestion",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which one of the following extends a private network across public networks?",
    "Option A": "local area network",
    "Option B": "virtual private network",
    "Option C": "enterprise private network",
    "Option D": "storage area network",
    Answer: "B. virtual private network",
    Topic: "Virtual Private Network",
  },
  {
    Question: "OSI stands for",
    "Option A": "open system interconnection",
    "Option B": "operating system interface",
    "Option C": "optical service implementation",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. open system interconnection",
    Topic: "OSI Model",
  },
  {
    Question: "The OSI model has ___ layers.",
    "Option A": 4,
    "Option B": 5,
    "Option C": 6,
    "Option D": 7,
    Answer: "D. 7",
    Topic: "Number of Layers in OSI Model",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "TCP/IP model does not have ______ layer but the OSI model has this layer.",
    "Option A": "session layer",
    "Option B": "presentation layer",
    "Option C": "application layer",
    "Option D": "both (a) and (b)",
    Answer: "D. both (a) and (b)",
    Topic: "TCP/IP vs OSI Model",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which layer links the network support layers and user support layers",
    "Option A": "session layer",
    "Option B": "data link layer",
    "Option C": "transport layer",
    "Option D": "network layer",
    Answer: "C. transport layer",
    Topic: "OSI Model Layer Linking",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which address is used in an internet employing the TCP/IP protocols?",
    "Option A": "physical address and logical address",
    "Option B": "port address",
    "Option C": "specific address",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Internet Addresses",
  },
  {
    Question: "TCP/IP model was developed _____ the OSI model.",
    "Option A": "prior to",
    "Option B": "after",
    "Option C": "simultaneous to",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. prior to",
    Topic: "TCP/IP vs OSI Model Development",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which layer is responsible for process to process delivery?",
    "Option A": "network layer",
    "Option B": "transport layer",
    "Option C": "session layer",
    "Option D": "data link layer",
    Answer: "B. transport layer",
    Topic: "Process to Process Delivery",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which address identifies a process on a host?",
    "Option A": "physical address",
    "Option B": "logical address",
    "Option C": "port address",
    "Option D": "specific address",
    Answer: "C. port address",
    Topic: "Process Identification",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which layer provides the services to the user?",
    "Option A": "application layer",
    "Option B": "session layer",
    "Option C": "presentation layer",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. application layer",
    Topic: "User Services",
  },
  {
    Question: "Transmission data rate is decided by",
    "Option A": "network layer",
    "Option B": "physical layer",
    "Option C": "data link layer",
    "Option D": "transport layer",
    Answer: "B. physical layer",
    Topic: "Transmission Data Rate",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which transmission media has the highest transmission speed in a network?",
    "Option A": "coaxial cable",
    "Option B": "twisted pair cable",
    "Option C": "optical fiber",
    "Option D": "electrical cable",
    Answer: "C. optical fiber",
    Topic: "Fastest Transmission Speed",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Bits can be sent over guided and unguided media as an analog signal by",
    "Option A": "digital modulation",
    "Option B": "amplitude modulation",
    "Option C": "frequency modulation",
    "Option D": "phase modulation",
    Answer: "A. digital modulation",
    Topic: "Bits Transmission via Media",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The portion of the physical layer that interfaces with the media access control sublayer is called",
    "Option A": "physical signalling sublayer",
    "Option B": "physical data sublayer",
    "Option C": "physical address sublayer",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. physical signalling sublayer",
    Topic: "Interface with Media Access Control",
  },
  {
    Question: "Physical layer provides",
    "Option A": "mechanical specifications of electrical connectors and cables",
    "Option B": "electrical specification of transmission line signal level",
    "Option C": "specification for ir over optical fiber",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Physical Layer Functions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In asynchronous serial communication, the physical layer provides",
    "Option A": "start and stop signalling",
    "Option B": "flow control",
    "Option C": "both (a) and (b)",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. both (a) and (b)",
    Topic: "Asynchronous Serial Communication",
  },
  {
    Question: "The physical layer is responsible for",
    "Option A": "line coding",
    "Option B": "channel coding",
    "Option C": "modulation",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Physical Layer Responsibilities",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The physical layer translates logical communication requests from the ______ into hardware-specific operations.",
    "Option A": "data link layer",
    "Option B": "network layer",
    "Option C": "transport layer",
    "Option D": "application layer",
    Answer: "A. data link layer",
    Topic: "Logical Communication Requests Translation",
  },
  {
    Question: "A single channel is shared by multiple signals by",
    "Option A": "analog modulation",
    "Option B": "digital modulation",
    "Option C": "multiplexing",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. multiplexing",
    Topic: "Signal Sharing",
  },
  {
    Question: "Wireless transmission can be done via",
    "Option A": "radio waves",
    "Option B": "microwaves",
    "Option C": "infrared",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Wireless Transmission",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The data link layer takes the packets from _____ and encapsulates them into frames for transmission.",
    "Option A": "network layer",
    "Option B": "physical layer",
    "Option C": "transport layer",
    "Option D": "application layer",
    Answer: "A. network layer",
    Topic: "Data Encapsulation for Transmission",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which one of the following tasks is not done by the data link layer?",
    "Option A": "framing",
    "Option B": "error control",
    "Option C": "flow control",
    "Option D": "channel coding",
    Answer: "D. channel coding",
    Topic: "Data Link Layer Tasks",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which sublayer of the data link layer performs data link functions that depend upon the type of medium?",
    "Option A": "logical link control sublayer",
    "Option B": "media access control sublayer",
    "Option C": "network interface control sublayer",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. media access control sublayer",
    Topic: "Data Link Layer Sublayers",
  },
  {
    Question: "Header of a frame generally contains",
    "Option A": "synchronization bytes",
    "Option B": "addresses",
    "Option C": "frame identifier",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Frame Header Contents",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Automatic repeat request error management mechanism is provided by",
    "Option A": "logical link control sublayer",
    "Option B": "media access control sublayer",
    "Option C": "network interface control sublayer",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. logical link control sublayer",
    Topic: "Error Management Mechanism",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "When 2 or more bits in a data unit have been changed during the transmission, the error is called",
    "Option A": "random error",
    "Option B": "burst error",
    "Option C": "inverted error",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. burst error",
    Topic: "Types of Transmission Errors",
  },
  {
    Question: "CRC stands for",
    "Option A": "cyclic redundancy check",
    "Option B": "code repeat check",
    "Option C": "code redundancy check",
    "Option D": "cyclic repeat check",
    Answer: "A. cyclic redundancy check",
    Topic: "CRC in Data Communication",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which one of the following is a data link protocol?",
    "Option A": "ethernet",
    "Option B": "point to point protocol",
    "Option C": "hdlc",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Data Link Protocols",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which one of the following is the multiple access protocol for channel access control?",
    "Option A": "csma/cd",
    "Option B": "csma/ca",
    "Option C": "both (a) and (b)",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. both (a) and (b)",
    Topic: "Multiple Access Protocol",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The technique of temporarily delaying outgoing acknowledgments so that they can be hooked onto the next outgoing data frame is called",
    "Option A": "piggybacking",
    "Option B": "cyclic redundancy check",
    "Option C": "fletcher’s checksum",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. piggybacking",
    Topic: "Delayed Acknowledgements Technique",
  },
  {
    Question: "The network layer concerns with",
    "Option A": "bits",
    "Option B": "frames",
    "Option C": "packets",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. packets",
    Topic: "Network Layer Concerns",
  },
  {
    Question: "A DNS client is called",
    "Option A": "dns updater",
    "Option B": "dns resolver",
    "Option C": "dns handler",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. dns resolver",
    Topic: "DNS Client",
  },
  {
    Question: "Servers handle requests for other domains",
    "Option A": "directly",
    "Option B": "by contacting remote dns server",
    "Option C": "it is not possible",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. by contacting remote dns server",
    Topic: "DNS Server Requests",
  },
  {
    Question: "DNS database contains",
    "Option A": "name server records",
    "Option B": "hostname-to-address records",
    "Option C": "hostname aliases",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "DNS Database",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If a server has no clue about where to find the address for a hostname then",
    "Option A": "server asks to the root server",
    "Option B": "server asks to its adjacent server",
    "Option C": "request is not processed",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. server asks to the root server",
    Topic: "DNS Query Resolution",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which one of the following allows clients to update their DNS entry as their IP address changes?",
    "Option A": "dynamic dns",
    "Option B": "mail transfer agent",
    "Option C": "authoritative name server",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. dynamic dns",
    Topic: "DNS Entry Update",
  },
  {
    Question: "Wildcard domain names start with label",
    "Option A": "@",
    "Option B": "*",
    "Option C": "&",
    "Option D": "#",
    Answer: "B. *",
    Topic: "Wildcard Domain Names",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The right to use a domain name is delegated by domain name registers which are accredited by",
    "Option A": "internet architecture board",
    "Option B": "internet society",
    "Option C": "internet research task force",
    "Option D": "internet corporation for assigned names and numbers",
    Answer: "D. internet corporation for assigned names and numbers",
    Topic: "Domain Name Delegation",
  },
  {
    Question: "The domain name system is maintained by",
    "Option A": "distributed database system",
    "Option B": "a single server",
    "Option C": "a single computer",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. distributed database system",
    Topic: "Domain Name System Maintenance",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which one of the following is not true?",
    "Option A": "multiple hostnames may correspond to a single IP address",
    "Option B": "a single hostname may correspond to many IP addresses",
    "Option C": "a single hostname may correspond to a single IP address",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. a single hostname may correspond to a single IP address",
    Topic: "DNS Facts",
  },
  {
    Question: "Telnet protocol is used to establish a connection to",
    "Option A": "TCP port number 21",
    "Option B": "TCP port number 22",
    "Option C": "TCP port number 23",
    "Option D": "TCP port number 24",
    Answer: "C. TCP port number 23",
    Topic: "Telnet Protocol",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which one of the following is not true?",
    "Option A": "telnet defines a network virtual terminal (NVT) standard",
    "Option B": "client programs interact with NVT",
    "Option C": "server translates NVT operations",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. none of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Telnet Facts",
  },
  {
    Question: "All telnet operations are sent as",
    "Option A": "4 bytes",
    "Option B": "8 bytes",
    "Option C": "16 bytes",
    "Option D": "32 bytes",
    Answer: "B. 8 bytes",
    Topic: "Telnet Operations Length",
  },
  {
    Question: "AbsoluteTelnet is a telnet client for",
    "Option A": "windows",
    "Option B": "Linux",
    "Option C": "Mac",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. windows",
    Topic: "AbsoluteTelnet",
  },
  {
    Question: "The decimal code of interpret as command (IAC) character is",
    "Option A": 252,
    "Option B": 253,
    "Option C": 254,
    "Option D": 255,
    Answer: "D. 255",
    Topic: "Interpret as Command (IAC) Character Decimal Code",
  },
  {
    Question: "In character mode operation of telnet implementation",
    "Option A": "each character typed is sent by the client to the server",
    "Option B": "each character typed is discarded by the server",
    "Option C": "both (a) and (b)",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. each character typed is sent by the client to the server",
    Topic: "Telnet Character Mode",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which one of the following is not correct?",
    "Option A": "telnet is a general-purpose client-server program",
    "Option B":
      "telnet lets the user access an application on a remote computer",
    "Option C": "telnet can also be used for file transfer",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. telnet can also be used for file transfer",
    Topic: "Telnet Misconceptions",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which operating mode of telnet is full duplex?",
    "Option A": "default mode",
    "Option B": "server mode",
    "Option C": "line mode",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. line mode",
    Topic: "Telnet Operating Modes",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If we want that a character be interpreted by the client instead of the server",
    "Option A": "escape character has to be used",
    "Option B": "control functions have to be disabled",
    "Option C": "it is not possible",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. escape character has to be used",
    Topic: "Telnet Character Interpretation",
  },
  {
    Question: "Dynamic web page",
    "Option A": "is same every time whenever it displays",
    "Option B":
      "generates on demand by a program or a request from the browser",
    "Option C": "both (a) and (b)",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. generates on demand by a program or a request from the browser",
    Topic: "Dynamic Web Page",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is a web browser?",
    "Option A": "a program that can display a web page",
    "Option B": "a program used to view HTML documents",
    "Option C": "it enables the user to access the resources of the internet",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Web Browser",
  },
  {
    Question: "Common Gateway Interface is used to",
    "Option A": "generate executable files from web content by the web server",
    "Option B": "generate web pages",
    "Option C": "stream videos",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. generate executable files from web content by the web server",
    Topic: "Common Gateway Interface (CGI)",
  },
  {
    Question: "URL stands for",
    "Option A": "unique reference label",
    "Option B": "uniform reference label",
    "Option C": "uniform resource locator",
    "Option D": "unique resource locator",
    Answer: "C. uniform resource locator",
    Topic: "URL",
  },
  {
    Question: "A web cookie is a small piece of data",
    "Option A":
      "sent from a website and stored in the user’s web browser while a user is browsing a website",
    "Option B":
      "sent from the user and stored in the server while a user is browsing a website",
    "Option C": "sent from the root server to all servers",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer:
      "A. sent from a website and stored in the user’s web browser while a user is browsing a website",
    Topic: "Web Cookie",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which one of the following is not used to generate dynamic web pages?",
    "Option A": "PHP",
    "Option B": "ASP.NET",
    "Option C": "JSP",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. none of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Dynamic Web Pages Generation",
  },
  {
    Question: "An alternative to JavaScript on the Windows platform is",
    "Option A": "VBScript",
    "Option B": "ASP.NET",
    "Option C": "JSP",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. VBScript",
    Topic: "Alternative to JavaScript on Windows",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is Document Object Model (DOM)?",
    "Option A":
      "convention for representing and interacting with objects in HTML documents",
    "Option B": "application programming interface",
    "Option C": "hierarchy of objects in ASP.NET",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer:
      "A. convention for representing and interacting with objects in HTML documents",
    Topic: "Document Object Model (DOM)",
  },
  {
    Question: "AJAX stands for",
    "Option A": "asynchronous JavaScript and XML",
    "Option B": "advanced JSP and XML",
    "Option C": "asynchronous JSP and XML",
    "Option D": "advanced JavaScript and XML",
    Answer: "A. asynchronous JavaScript and XML",
    Topic: "AJAX",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Multiple objects can be sent over a TCP connection between the client and server in",
    "Option A": "persistent HTTP",
    "Option B": "nonpersistent HTTP",
    "Option C": "both (a) and (b)",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. persistent HTTP",
    Topic: "Multiple Objects Transmission in TCP Connection",
  },
  {
    Question: "HTTP is ________ protocol.",
    "Option A": "application layer",
    "Option B": "transport layer",
    "Option C": "network layer",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. application layer",
    Topic: "HTTP Protocol",
  },
  {
    Question: "In the network, HTTP resources are located by",
    "Option A": "uniform resource identifier",
    "Option B": "unique resource locator",
    "Option C": "unique resource identifier",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. uniform resource identifier",
    Topic: "Locating HTTP Resources",
  },
  {
    Question: "To join the internet, the computer has to be connected to a",
    "Option A": "internet architecture board",
    "Option B": "internet society",
    "Option C": "internet service provider",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. internet service provider",
    Topic: "Internet Connection",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Internet access by transmitting digital data over the wires of a local telephone network is provided by",
    "Option A": "leased line",
    "Option B": "digital subscriber line",
    "Option C": "digital signal line",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. digital subscriber line",
    Topic: "Internet Access via Telephone Network",
  },
  {
    Question: "ISP exchanges internet traffic between their networks by",
    "Option A": "internet exchange point",
    "Option B": "subscriber end point",
    "Option C": "isp end point",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. internet exchange point",
    Topic: "ISP Internet Traffic Exchange",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which one of the following protocols is not used on the internet?",
    "Option A": "http",
    "Option B": "dhcp",
    "Option C": "dns",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. none of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Internet Protocols",
  },
  {
    Question: "IPv6 addresses have a size of",
    "Option A": "32 bits",
    "Option B": "64 bits",
    "Option C": "128 bits",
    "Option D": "265 bits",
    Answer: "C. 128 bits",
    Topic: "IPv6 Address Size",
  },
  {
    Question: "Internet works on",
    "Option A": "packet switching",
    "Option B": "circuit switching",
    "Option C": "both (a) and (b)",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. packet switching",
    Topic: "Internet Working Principle",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which one of the following is not an application layer protocol used on the internet?",
    "Option A": "remote procedure call",
    "Option B": "internet relay chat",
    "Option C": "resource reservation protocol",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. resource reservation protocol",
    Topic: "Application Layer Protocols",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which protocol assigns IP addresses to clients connected to the internet?",
    "Option A": "dhcp",
    "Option B": "ip",
    "Option C": "rpc",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. dhcp",
    Topic: "IP Address Assignment",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which one of the following is not used in media access control?",
    "Option A": "ethernet",
    "Option B": "digital subscriber line",
    "Option C": "fiber distributed data interface",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. none of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Media Access Control",
  },
  {
    Question: "In cryptography, what is a cipher?",
    "Option A": "algorithm for performing encryption and decryption",
    "Option B": "encrypted message",
    "Option C": "both (a) and (b)",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. algorithm for performing encryption and decryption",
    Topic: "Cryptography - Cipher",
  },
  {
    Question: "In asymmetric key cryptography, the private key is kept by",
    "Option A": "sender",
    "Option B": "receiver",
    "Option C": "sender and receiver",
    "Option D": "all the connected devices to the network",
    Answer: "B. receiver",
    Topic: "Asymmetric Key Cryptography",
  },
  {
    Question: "The DHCP server can provide the _______ of the IP addresses.",
    "Option A": "dynamic allocation",
    "Option B": "automatic allocation",
    "Option C": "static allocation",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "DHCP IP Address Allocation",
  },
  {
    Question: "DHCP client and servers on the same subnet communicate via",
    "Option A": "udp broadcast",
    "Option B": "udp unicast",
    "Option C": "tcp broadcast",
    "Option D": "tcp unicast",
    Answer: "A. udp broadcast",
    Topic: "DHCP Client-Server Communication",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "After obtaining the IP address, to prevent IP conflict the client may use",
    "Option A": "internet relay chat",
    "Option B": "broader gateway protocol",
    "Option C": "address resolution protocol",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. address resolution protocol",
    Topic: "DHCP IP Conflict Prevention",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is DHCP snooping?",
    "Option A":
      "techniques applied to ensure the security of an existing DHCP infrastructure",
    "Option B": "encryption of the DHCP server requests",
    "Option C": "algorithm for DHCP",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer:
      "A. techniques applied to ensure the security of an existing DHCP infrastructure",
    Topic: "DHCP Snooping",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If DHCP snooping is configured on a LAN switch, then clients having specific ______ can access the network.",
    "Option A": "mac address",
    "Option B": "ip address",
    "Option C": "both (a) and (b)",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "C. both (a) and (b)",
    Topic: "DHCP Snooping Access Control",
  },
  {
    Question: "Real-time transport protocol (RTP) is mostly used in",
    "Option A": "streaming media",
    "Option B": "video teleconference",
    "Option C": "television services",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Real-Time Transport Protocol (RTP)",
  },
  {
    Question: "RTP is used to",
    "Option A": "carry the media stream",
    "Option B": "monitor transmission statistics of streams",
    "Option C": "monitor quality of service of streams",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. carry the media stream",
    Topic: "RTP Usage",
  },
  {
    Question: "RTP provides the facility of jitter ____",
    "Option A": "compensation",
    "Option B": "expansion",
    "Option C": "both (a) and (b)",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. compensation",
    Topic: "RTP Jitter Compensation",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which protocol provides synchronization between media streams?",
    "Option A": "rtp",
    "Option B": "rtcp",
    "Option C": "rpc",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. rtcp",
    Topic: "Synchronization Between Media Streams",
  },
  {
    Question: "An RTP session is established for",
    "Option A": "each media stream",
    "Option B": "all media streams",
    "Option C": "some predefined number of media streams",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. each media stream",
    Topic: "RTP Session Establishment",
  },
  {
    Question: "RTP can use",
    "Option A": "unprivileged UDP ports",
    "Option B": "stream control transmission protocol",
    "Option C": "datagram congestion control protocol",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "RTP Port Usage",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which one of the following multimedia formats can not be supported by RTP?",
    "Option A": "mpeg-4",
    "Option B": "mjpeg",
    "Option C": "mpeg",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. none of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Multimedia Formats and RTP",
  },
  {
    Question: "An RTP header has a minimum size of",
    "Option A": "12 bytes",
    "Option B": "16 bytes",
    "Option C": "24 bytes",
    "Option D": "32 bytes",
    Answer: "A. 12 bytes",
    Topic: "RTP Header Size",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which one of the following is not correct?",
    "Option A":
      "rtcp provides canonical end-point identifiers to all session participants",
    "Option B": "rtcp reports are expected to be sent by all participants",
    "Option C": "both (a) and (b)",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. none of the mentioned",
    Topic: "RTCP Functionality",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which protocol defines a profile of RTP that provides cryptographic services for the transfer of payload data?",
    "Option A": "srtp",
    "Option B": "rtcp",
    "Option C": "rcp",
    "Option D": "none of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. srtp",
    Topic: "RTP Cryptographic Services",
  },
  {
    Question: "Ping can",
    "Option A": "measure round-trip time",
    "Option B": "report packet loss",
    "Option C": "report latency",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Ping Command",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Suppose two IPv6 nodes want to interoperate using IPv6 datagrams but are connected to each other by intervening IPv4 routers. The best solution here is",
    "Option A": "use dual-stack approach",
    "Option B": "tunneling",
    "Option C": "no solution",
    "Option D": "replace the system",
    Answer: "B. tunneling",
    Topic: "IPv6 Interoperation with IPv4 Routers",
  },
  {
    Question: "Ping sweep is a part of",
    "Option A": "traceroute",
    "Option B": "nmap",
    "Option C": "route",
    "Option D": "ipconfig",
    Answer: "B. nmap",
    Topic: "Ping Sweep",
  },
  {
    Question: "ICMP is used in",
    "Option A": "ping",
    "Option B": "traceroute",
    "Option C": "ifconfig",
    "Option D": "both a and b",
    Answer: "D. both a and b",
    Topic: "ICMP Usage",
  },
  {
    Question: "_____ command is used to manipulate TCP/IP routing table.",
    "Option A": "route",
    "Option B": "ipconfig",
    "Option C": "ifconfig",
    "Option D": "traceroute",
    Answer: "A. route",
    Topic: "TCP/IP Routing Table Manipulation",
  },
  {
    Question: "Certainly! Here's the information converted into tabular form:",
  },
  {
    Question: "Question",
    "Option A": "Option A",
    "Option B": "Option B",
    "Option C": "Option C",
    "Option D": "Option D",
    Answer: "Answer",
    Topic: "Topic",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following statements can be associated with the OSI model?",
    "Option A":
      "a structured way to discuss and easier update system components",
    "Option B": "one layer may duplicate lower layer functionality",
    "Option C":
      "functionality at one layer no way requires information from another layer",
    "Option D": "it is an application-specific network model",
    Answer:
      "C. functionality at one layer no way requires information from another layer",
    Topic: "OSI Model",
  },
  {
    Question: "OSI stands for __________",
    "Option A": "open system interconnection",
    "Option B": "operating system interface",
    "Option C": "optical service implementation",
    "Option D": "open service internet",
    Answer: "A. open system interconnection",
    Topic: "OSI Model",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The number of layers in the ISO OSI reference model is __________",
    "Option A": 4,
    "Option B": 5,
    "Option C": 6,
    "Option D": 7,
    Answer: "D. 7",
    Topic: "OSI Model",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "TCP/IP model does not have ______ layer but OSI model has this layer.",
    "Option A": "session layer",
    "Option B": "transport layer",
    "Option C": "application layer",
    "Option D": "network layer",
    Answer: "A. session layer",
    Topic: "TCP/IP vs OSI Model",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which layer is used to link the network support layers and user support layers?",
    "Option A": "session layer",
    "Option B": "data link layer",
    "Option C": "transport layer",
    "Option D": "network layer",
    Answer: "C. transport layer",
    Topic: "OSI Model Layers",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which address is used on the internet for employing the TCP/IP protocols?",
    "Option A": "physical address and logical address",
    "Option B": "port address",
    "Option C": "specific address",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "TCP/IP Protocols",
  },
  {
    Question: "TCP/IP model was developed _____ the OSI model.",
    "Option A": "prior to",
    "Option B": "after",
    "Option C": "simultaneous to",
    "Option D": "with no link to",
    Answer: "A. prior to",
    Topic: "TCP/IP Model",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which address is used to identify a process on a host by the transport layer?",
    "Option A": "physical address",
    "Option B": "logical address",
    "Option C": "port address",
    "Option D": "specific address",
    Answer: "C. port address",
    Topic: "TCP/IP Model",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which layer provides the services to the user?",
    "Option A": "application layer",
    "Option B": "session layer",
    "Option C": "presentation layer",
    "Option D": "physical layer",
    Answer: "A. application layer",
    Topic: "OSI Model",
  },
  {
    Question: "Transmission data rate is decided by ____________",
    "Option A": "network layer",
    "Option B": "physical layer",
    "Option C": "data link layer",
    "Option D": "transport layer",
    Answer: "B. physical layer",
    Topic: "OSI Model",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which transmission media provides the highest transmission speed in a network?",
    "Option A": "coaxial cable",
    "Option B": "twisted pair cable",
    "Option C": "optical fiber",
    "Option D": "electrical cable",
    Answer: "C. optical fiber",
    Topic: "Transmission Media",
  },
  {
    Question: "A single channel is shared by multiple signals by ____________",
    "Option A": "analog modulation",
    "Option B": "digital modulation",
    "Option C": "multiplexing",
    "Option D": "phase modulation",
    Answer: "C. multiplexing",
    Topic: "Multiplexing",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following tasks is not done by the data link layer?",
    "Option A": "framing",
    "Option B": "error control",
    "Option C": "flow control",
    "Option D": "channel coding",
    Answer: "D. channel coding",
    Topic: "Data Link Layer Tasks",
  },
  {
    Question: "Header of a frame generally contains ______________",
    "Option A": "synchronization bytes",
    "Option B": "addresses",
    "Option C": "frame identifier",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Frame Header Content",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Automatic repeat request error management mechanism is provided by ________",
    "Option A": "logical link control sublayer",
    "Option B": "media access control sublayer",
    "Option C": "network interface control sublayer",
    "Option D": "application access control sublayer",
    Answer: "A. logical link control sublayer",
    Topic: "Error Management in Data Link Layer",
  },
  {
    Question: "CRC stands for __________",
    "Option A": "cyclic redundancy check",
    "Option B": "code repeat check",
    "Option C": "code redundancy check",
    "Option D": "cyclic repeat check",
    Answer: "A. cyclic redundancy check",
    Topic: "CRC in Networking",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is a data link protocol?",
    "Option A": "ethernet",
    "Option B": "point to point protocol",
    "Option C": "HDLC",
    "Option D": "all of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. all of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Data Link Protocols",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is the multiple access protocol for channel access control?",
    "Option A": "CSMA/CD",
    "Option B": "CSMA/CA",
    "Option C": "both CSMA/CD & CSMA/CA",
    "Option D": "HDLC",
    Answer: "C. both CSMA/CD & CSMA/CA",
    Topic: "Channel Access Control",
  },
  {
    Question: "A 4-byte IP address consists of __________",
    "Option A": "only network address",
    "Option B": "only host address",
    "Option C": "network address & host address",
    "Option D": "network address & MAC address",
    Answer: "C. network address & host address",
    Topic: "IP Address Components",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "User Datagram Protocol is called connectionless because _____________",
    "Option A":
      "all UDP packets are treated independently by the transport layer",
    "Option B": "it sends data as a stream of related packets",
    "Option C": "it is received in the same order as sent order",
    "Option D": "it sends data very quickly",
    Answer:
      "A. all UDP packets are treated independently by the transport layer",
    Topic: "UDP Connectionless Protocol",
  },
  {
    Question: "Socket-style API for Windows is called ____________",
    "Option A": "wsock",
    "Option B": "winsock",
    "Option C": "wins",
    "Option D": "sockwi",
    Answer: "B. winsock",
    Topic: "Windows Socket API",
  },
  {
    Question: "_______ topology requires a multipoint connection.",
    "Option A": "star",
    "Option B": "mesh",
    "Option C": "ring",
    "Option D": "bus",
    Answer: "D. bus",
    Topic: "Network Topology",
  },
  {
    Question: "WAN stands for __________",
    "Option A": "World Area Network",
    "Option B": "Wide Area Network",
    "Option C": "Web Area Network",
    "Option D": "Web Access Network",
    Answer: "B. Wide Area Network",
    Topic: "WAN Acronym",
  },
  {
    Question: "In TDM, slots are further divided into __________",
    "Option A": "seconds",
    "Option B": "frames",
    "Option C": "packets",
    "Option D": "bits",
    Answer: "B. frames",
    Topic: "TDM Slots Division",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The sharing of a medium and its link by two or more devices is called _________",
    "Option A": "full duplexing",
    "Option B": "multiplexing",
    "Option C": "microplexing",
    "Option D": "duplexing",
    Answer: "B. multiplexing",
    Topic: "Multiplexing Definition",
  },
  {
    Question: "Multiplexing is used in _______",
    "Option A": "packet switching",
    "Option B": "circuit switching",
    "Option C": "data switching",
    "Option D": "packet & circuit switching",
    Answer: "B. circuit switching",
    Topic: "Multiplexing Usage",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which multiplexing technique used to transmit digital signals?",
    "Option A": "FDM",
    "Option B": "TDM",
    "Option C": "WDM",
    "Option D": "FDM & WDM",
    Answer: "B. TDM",
    Topic: "TDM in Networking",
  },
  {
    Question: "The state when dedicated signals are idle is called __________",
    "Option A": "death period",
    "Option B": "poison period",
    "Option C": "silent period",
    "Option D": "stop period",
    Answer: "C. silent period",
    Topic: "Multiplexing State",
  },
  {
    Question: "Multiplexing provides _________",
    "Option A": "efficiency",
    "Option B": "privacy",
    "Option C": "anti-jamming",
    "Option D": "both efficiency & privacy",
    Answer: "D. both efficiency & privacy",
    Topic: "Multiplexing Advantages",
  },
  {
    Question: "In TDM, slots are further divided into _________",
    "Option A": "seconds",
    "Option B": "frames",
    "Option C": "packets",
    "Option D": "bits",
    Answer: "B. frames",
    Topic: "TDM Slots Division",
  },
  {
    Question: "The total nodal delay is given by ____________",
    "Option A": "dnodal = dproc – dqueue + dtrans + dprop",
    "Option B": "dnodal = dproc + dtrans – dqueue",
    "Option C": "dnodal = dproc + dqueue + dtrans + dprop",
    "Option D": "dnodal = dproc + dqueue – dtrans – dprop",
    Answer: "C. dnodal = dproc + dqueue + dtrans + dprop",
    Topic: "Nodal Delay Calculation",
  },
  {
    Question: "Transmission delay does not depend on _____________",
    "Option A": "packet length",
    "Option B": "distance between the routers",
    "Option C": "transmission rate",
    "Option D": "bandwidth of the medium",
    Answer: "B. distance between the routers",
    Topic: "Transmission Delay Factors",
  },
  {
    Question: "Propagation delay depends on ___________",
    "Option A": "packet length",
    "Option B": "transmission rate",
    "Option C": "distance between the routers",
    "Option D": "speed of the CPU",
    Answer: "C. distance between the routers",
    Topic: "Propagation Delay Factors",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "_____________ allows LAN users to share computer programs and data.",
    "Option A": "communication server",
    "Option B": "print server",
    "Option C": "file server",
    "Option D": "network",
    Answer: "C. file server",
    Topic: "File Server in Networking",
  },
  {
    Question: "With respect to physical media, STP cables stand for _________",
    "Option A": "Shielded Twisted Pair Cable",
    "Option B": "Spanning Tree Protocol Cable",
    "Option C": "Static Transport Protocol Cable",
    "Option D": "Shielded Two Power Cable",
    Answer: "A. Shielded Twisted Pair Cable",
    Topic: "STP Cable",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the max length of the Shielded twisted pair cable?",
    "Option A": "100 ft",
    "Option B": "200 ft",
    "Option C": "100 m",
    "Option D": "200 m",
    Answer: "C. 100 m",
    Topic: "Maximum Length of STP Cable",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the max data transfer rate of STP cables?",
    "Option A": "10 Mbps",
    "Option B": "100 Mbps",
    "Option C": "1000 Mbps",
    "Option D": "10000 Mbps",
    Answer: "B. 100 Mbps",
    Topic: "Max Data Transfer Rate of STP Cable",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which connector does the STP cable use?",
    "Option A": "BNC",
    "Option B": "RJ-11",
    "Option C": "RJ-45",
    "Option D": "RJ-69",
    Answer: "C. RJ-45",
    Topic: "Connector Used by STP Cable",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the central device in star topology?",
    "Option A": "STP server",
    "Option B": "Hub/Switch",
    "Option C": "PDC",
    "Option D": "Router",
    Answer: "B. Hub/Switch",
    Topic: "Central Device in Star Topology",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the max data transfer rate for optical fiber cable?",
    "Option A": "10 Mbps",
    "Option B": "100 Mbps",
    "Option C": "1000 Mbps",
    "Option D": "10000 Mbps",
    Answer: "D. 10000 Mbps",
    Topic: "Max Data Transfer Rate for Optical Fiber Cable",
  },
  {
    Question: "SMTP uses which of the following TCP port?",
    "Option A": 22,
    "Option B": 23,
    "Option C": 21,
    "Option D": 25,
    Answer: "D. 25",
    Topic: "SMTP TCP Port",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which one of the following protocol is used to receive mail messages?",
    "Option A": "SMTP",
    "Option B": "Post Office Protocol (POP)",
    "Option C": "Internet Message Access Protocol (IMAP)",
    "Option D": "FTP",
    Answer: "B. FTP",
    Topic: "Email Protocols",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is on-demand mail relay (ODMR)?",
    "Option A": "Protocol for SMTP Security",
    "Option B": "An SMTP Extension",
    "Option C": "Protocol for Web Pages",
    "Option D": "Protocol for Faster Mail Transfer",
    Answer: "B. An SMTP Extension",
    Topic: "ODMR in Email",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "An email client needs to know the _________ of its initial SMTP server.",
    "Option A": "IP Address",
    "Option B": "MAC Address",
    "Option C": "URL",
    "Option D": "Name",
    Answer: "A. IP Address",
    Topic: "Email Client and SMTP Server",
  },
  {
    Question: "An SMTP session may not include _______",
    "Option A": "Zero SMTP Transaction",
    "Option B": "One SMTP Transaction",
    "Option C": "More Than One SMTP Transaction",
    "Option D": "One HTTP Transaction",
    Answer: "D. One HTTP Transaction",
    Topic: "SMTP Session",
  },
  {
    Question: "SMTP defines _______",
    "Option A": "Message Transport",
    "Option B": "Message Encryption",
    "Option C": "Message Content",
    "Option D": "Message Password",
    Answer: "A. Message Transport",
    Topic: "SMTP Definitions",
  },
  {
    Question: "SMTP is not used to deliver messages to ______",
    "Option A": "User’s Terminal",
    "Option B": "User’s Mailbox",
    "Option C": "User’s Word Processor",
    "Option D": "User’s Email Client",
    Answer: "C. User’s Word Processor",
    Topic: "SMTP Message Delivery",
  },
  {
    Question: "The entire hostname has a maximum of ___________",
    "Option A": "255 Characters",
    "Option B": "127 Characters",
    "Option C": "63 Characters",
    "Option D": "31 Characters",
    Answer: "A. 255 Characters",
    Topic: "Hostname Maximum Length",
  },
  {
    Question: "A DNS client is called _________",
    "Option A": "DNS Updater",
    "Option B": "DNS Resolver",
    "Option C": "DNS Handler",
    "Option D": "None of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "B. DNS Resolver",
    Topic: "DNS Client",
  },
  {
    Question: "Servers handle requests for other domains _______",
    "Option A": "Directly",
    "Option B": "By Contacting Remote DNS Server",
    "Option C": "It is Not Possible",
    "Option D": "None of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "B. By Contacting Remote DNS Server",
    Topic: "Servers Handling Requests",
  },
  {
    Question: "DNS database contains _______",
    "Option A": "Name Server Records",
    "Option B": "Hostname-to-Address Records",
    "Option C": "Hostname Aliases",
    "Option D": "All of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "D. All of the Mentioned",
    Topic: "DNS Database Content",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If a server has no clue about where to find the address for a hostname then _______",
    "Option A": "Server Asks to the Root Server",
    "Option B": "Server Asks to Its Adjacent Server",
    "Option C": "Request is Not Processed",
    "Option D": "None of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "A. Server Asks to the Root Server",
    Topic: "DNS Address Resolution",
  },
  {
    Question: "Wildcard domain names start with label _______",
    "Option A": "@",
    "Option B": "*",
    "Option C": "&",
    "Option D": "#",
    Answer: "B. *",
    Topic: "Wildcard Domain Names",
  },
  {
    Question: "The domain name system is maintained by _______",
    "Option A": "Distributed Database System",
    "Option B": "A Single Server",
    "Option C": "A Single Computer",
    "Option D": "None of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "A. Distributed Database System",
    Topic: "DNS Maintenance",
  },
  {
    Question: "Secure shell (SSH) network protocol is used for __________",
    "Option A": "Secure Shell (SSH)",
    "Option B": "Secure Data Communication",
    "Option C": "Remote Command-Line Login",
    "Option D": "Remote Command Execution",
    Answer: "D. All of the Mentioned",
    Topic: "SSH Protocol",
  },
  {
    Question: "SSH can be used in only _____________",
    "Option A": "Unix-Like Operating Systems",
    "Option B": "Windows",
    "Option C": "Both Unix-Like and Windows Systems",
    "Option D": "None of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "C. Both Unix-Like and Windows Systems",
    Topic: "SSH Usage",
  },
  {
    Question: "SSH uses ___________ to authenticate the remote computer.",
    "Option A": "Public-Key Cryptography",
    "Option B": "Private-Key Cryptography",
    "Option C": "Any of Public-Key or Private-Key",
    "Option D": "Both Public-Key & Private-Key",
    Answer: "A. Public-Key Cryptography",
    Topic: "SSH Authentication",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which standard TCP port is assigned for contacting SSH servers?",
    "Option A": "Port 21",
    "Option B": "Port 22",
    "Option C": "Port 23",
    "Option D": "Port 24",
    Answer: "B. Port 22",
    Topic: "SSH Server Port",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which one of the following is a file transfer protocol using SSH?",
    "Option A": "SCP",
    "Option B": "SFTP",
    "Option C": "Rsync",
    "Option D": "All of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "D. All of the Mentioned",
    Topic: "File Transfer Protocols over SSH",
  },
  {
    Question: "SSH-2 does not contain ______________",
    "Option A": "Transport Layer",
    "Option B": "User Authentication Layer",
    "Option C": "Physical Layer",
    "Option D": "Connection Layer",
    Answer: "C. Physical Layer",
    Topic: "SSH-2 Components",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which one of the following feature was present in SSH protocol, version 1?",
    "Option A": "Password Changing",
    "Option B": "Periodic Replacement of Session Keys",
    "Option C": "Support for Public-Key Certificates",
    "Option D": "None of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "D. None of the Mentioned",
    Topic: "SSH Protocol Version 1 Features",
  },
  {
    Question: "SCP protocol is evolved from __________ over SSH.",
    "Option A": "RCP Protocol",
    "Option B": "DHCP Protocol",
    "Option C": "MGCP Protocol",
    "Option D": "GCP Protocol",
    Answer: "A. RCP Protocol",
    Topic: "SCP Evolution",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which one of the following authentication method is used by SSH?",
    "Option A": "Public-Key",
    "Option B": "Host Based",
    "Option C": "Password",
    "Option D": "All of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "D. All of the Mentioned",
    Topic: "SSH Authentication Methods",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "DHCP (dynamic host configuration protocol) provides __________ to the client.",
    "Option A": "IP Address",
    "Option B": "MAC Address",
    "Option C": "URL",
    "Option D": "None of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "A. IP Address",
    Topic: "DHCP Service to Client",
  },
  {
    Question: "DHCP is used for ________",
    "Option A": "IPv6",
    "Option B": "IPv4",
    "Option C": "Both IPv6 and IPv4",
    "Option D": "None of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "C. Both IPv6 and IPv4",
    Topic: "DHCP Usage",
  },
  {
    Question: "The DHCP server _________",
    "Option A": "Maintains a Database of Available IP Addresses",
    "Option B": "Maintains Information About Client Configuration Parameters",
    "Option C": "Grants an IP Address When Receives a Request from a Client",
    "Option D": "All of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "D. All of the Mentioned",
    Topic: "DHCP Server Functions",
  },
  {
    Question: "IP assigned for a client by DHCP server is",
    "Option A": "For a Limited Period",
    "Option B": "For an Unlimited Period",
    "Option C": "Not Time Dependent",
    "Option D": "None of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "A. For a Limited Period",
    Topic: "DHCP IP Lease Duration",
  },
  {
    Question: "DHCP uses UDP port _________ for sending data to the server.",
    "Option A": 66,
    "Option B": 67,
    "Option C": 68,
    "Option D": 69,
    Answer: "B. 67",
    Topic: "DHCP Server UDP Port",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "DHCP client and servers on the same subnet communicate via _________",
    "Option A": "UDP Broadcast",
    "Option B": "UDP Unicast",
    "Option C": "TCP Broadcast",
    "Option D": "TCP Unicast",
    Answer: "A. UDP Broadcast",
    Topic: "DHCP Communication Mode",
  },
  {
    Question: "WPA2 is used for security in _______",
    "Option A": "Ethernet",
    "Option B": "Bluetooth",
    "Option C": "Wi-Fi",
    "Option D": "Email",
    Answer: "C. Wi-Fi",
    Topic: "WPA2 Usage",
  },
  {
    Question: "VPNs are financially speaking __________",
    "Option A": "Always More Expensive Than Leased Lines",
    "Option B": "Always Cheaper Than Leased Lines",
    "Option C": "Usually Cheaper Than Leased Lines",
    "Option D": "Usually More Expensive Than Leased Lines",
    Answer: "C. Usually Cheaper Than Leased Lines",
    Topic: "VPNs Financial Comparison",
  },
  {
    Question: "Storage management comprises of _______________",
    "Option A": "SAN Management",
    "Option B": "Data Protection",
    "Option C": "Disk Operation",
    "Option D": "All of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "D. All of the Mentioned",
    Topic: "Storage Management Components",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is not a storage device?",
    "Option A": "Switch",
    "Option B": "RAID Arrays",
    "Option C": "Tape Drives",
    "Option D": "Hub",
    Answer: "D. Hub",
    Topic: "Storage Devices",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which protocols are used for Storage management?",
    "Option A": "SNMP",
    "Option B": "LDAP",
    "Option C": "POP3",
    "Option D": "MIB",
    Answer: "A. SNMP",
    Topic: "Storage Management Protocols",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "How do Storage administrators ensure secure access to storage devices?",
    "Option A": "By Using Zoning",
    "Option B": "By Putting a Physical Lock on the Storage Device",
    "Option C": "By Keeping Devices Shutdown When Not in Use",
    "Option D": "By Keeping Devices When Used",
    Answer: "A. By Using Zoning",
    Topic: "Secure Access to Storage Devices",
  },
  {
    Question: "Effective Storage management does not include __________",
    "Option A": "Security",
    "Option B": "Backups",
    "Option C": "Reporting",
    "Option D": "Connection",
    Answer: "D. Connection",
    Topic: "Effective Storage Management Components",
  },
  {
    Question: "SMI-S Standard uses which of the following?",
    "Option A": "Java RMI",
    "Option B": "CIM-XML/HTTP",
    "Option C": "CORBA",
    "Option D": ".NET",
    Answer: "B. CIM-XML/HTTP",
    Topic: "SMI-S Standard Usage",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Full duplex mode increases the capacity of each domain by ________",
    "Option A": "10 to 20 Mbps",
    "Option B": "20 to 30 Mbps",
    "Option C": "30 to 40 Mbps",
    "Option D": "40 to 50 Mbps",
    Answer: "A. 10 to 20 Mbps",
    Topic: "Full Duplex Mode Increase",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Configuration management can be divided into which two subsystems?",
    "Option A": "Reconfiguration and Documentation",
    "Option B": "Management and Configuration",
    "Option C": "Documentation and Dialing Up",
    "Option D": "Configuration and Dialing Up",
    Answer: "A. Reconfiguration and Documentation",
    Topic: "Configuration Management Subsystems",
  },
  {
    Question: "To use a Simple Network Management System, we need _______",
    "Option A": "Servers",
    "Option B": "IP",
    "Option C": "Protocols",
    "Option D": "Rules",
    Answer: "D. Rules",
    Topic: "SNMP Usage",
  },
  {
    Question: "The main difference between SNMPv3 and SNMPv2 is _______",
    "Option A": "Management",
    "Option B": "Integration",
    "Option C": "Classification",
    "Option D": "Enhanced Security",
    Answer: "D. Enhanced Security",
    Topic: "SNMPv3 vs SNMPv2",
  },
  {
    Question: "BER stands for ________",
    "Option A": "Basic Encoding Rules",
    "Option B": "Basic Encoding Resolver",
    "Option C": "Basic Encoding Rotator",
    "Option D": "Basic Encoding Router",
    Answer: "A. Basic Encoding Rules",
    Topic: "BER in Networking",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "SNMP is the framework for managing devices in an internet using the ______",
    "Option A": "TCP/IP Protocol",
    "Option B": "UDP",
    "Option C": "SMTP",
    "Option D": "None",
    Answer: "A. TCP/IP Protocol",
    Topic: "SNMP Framework",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Structure of Management Information (SMI), is the guideline of ________",
    "Option A": "HTTP",
    "Option B": "SNMP",
    "Option C": "URL",
    "Option D": "MIB",
    Answer: "B. SNMP",
    Topic: "Structure of Management Information",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The application layer protocol used by a Telnet application is ________",
    "Option A": "Telnet",
    "Option B": "FTP",
    "Option C": "HTTP",
    "Option D": "SMTP",
    Answer: "A. Telnet",
    Topic: "Telnet Application Protocol",
  },
  {
    Question: "_______ allows you to connect and login to a remote computer",
    "Option A": "Telnet",
    "Option B": "FTP",
    "Option C": "HTTP",
    "Option D": "SMTP",
    Answer: "A. Telnet",
    Topic: "Telnet Connectivity",
  },
  {
    Question: "Telnet is used for _______",
    "Option A": "Television on Net",
    "Option B": "Network of Telephones",
    "Option C": "Remote Login",
    "Option D": "Teleshopping Site",
    Answer: "C. Remote Login",
    Topic: "Telnet Usage",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which one of the following is not correct?",
    "Option A": "Telnet is a General Purpose Client-Server Program",
    "Option B": "Telnet Lets User Access an Application on a Remote Computer",
    "Option C": "Telnet Can Also Be Used for File Transfer",
    "Option D": "Telnet Can Be Used for Remote Login",
    Answer: "C. Telnet Can Also Be Used for File Transfer",
    Topic: "Telnet Features",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which operating mode of telnet is full duplex?",
    "Option A": "Default Mode",
    "Option B": "Server Mode",
    "Option C": "Line Mode",
    "Option D": "Character Mode",
    Answer: "C. Line Mode",
    Topic: "Telnet Operating Mode",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which protocol should you select if the network diameter is more than 17 hops?",
    "Option A": "ripv1",
    "Option B": "ripv2",
    "Option C": "eigrp",
    "Option D": "both ripv1 and ripv2",
    Answer: "A. ripv1",
    Topic: "Routing Protocol for Large Network Diameter",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "How often does a RIPv1 router broadcast its routing table by default?",
    "Option A": "every 30 seconds",
    "Option B": "every 60 seconds",
    "Option C": "every 90 seconds",
    "Option D": "ripv1 does not broadcast periodically",
    Answer: "A. every 30 seconds",
    Topic: "RIPv1 Default Broadcasting Interval",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command displays RIP routing updates?",
    "Option A": "show ip route",
    "Option B": "debug ip rip",
    "Option C": "show protocols",
    "Option D": "debug ip route",
    Answer: "B. debug ip rip",
    Topic: "Displaying RIP Routing Updates",
  },
  {
    Question: "Default administrative distance of a static route is ________",
    "Option A": 0,
    "Option B": 90,
    "Option C": 100,
    "Option D": 1,
    Answer: "D. 1",
    Topic: "Default Administrative Distance of Static Route",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which protocol gives a full route table update every 30 seconds?",
    "Option A": "iegrp",
    "Option B": "rip",
    "Option C": "icmp",
    "Option D": "ip",
    Answer: "B. rip",
    Topic: "Full Route Table Update Every 30 Seconds",
  },
  {
    Question: "_________ is the default administrative distance of RIP.",
    "Option A": 0,
    "Option B": 90,
    "Option C": 120,
    "Option D": 130,
    Answer: "C. 120",
    Topic: "Default Administrative Distance of RIP",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which statement is true regarding classless routing protocol?",
    "Option A": "The use of discontinuous networks is not allowed",
    "Option B": "Use of variable length subnet masks is permitted",
    "Option C": "RIPv1 is a classless routing protocol",
    "Option D":
      "IGRP supports classful routing within the same autonomous system",
    Answer: "B. Use of variable length subnet masks is permitted",
    Topic: "Classless Routing Protocol",
  },
  {
    Question: "Where should we use default routing?",
    "Option A":
      "On stub networks - which have only one exit path out of the network",
    "Option B": "Which have more than one exit path out of the network",
    "Option C": "Minimum five exit paths out of the network",
    "Option D": "Maximum five exit paths out of the network",
    Answer:
      "A. On stub networks - which have only one exit path out of the network",
    Topic: "Use of Default Routing",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which statement is true regarding classless routing protocols?",
    "Option A": "The use of discontinuous networks is not allowed",
    "Option B": "Use of variable length subnet masks is permitted",
    "Option C": "RIPv1 is a classless routing protocol",
    "Option D": "RIPv2 supports classless routing",
    Answer: "B. Use of variable length subnet masks is permitted",
    Topic: "Classless Routing Protocols",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is true regarding RIPv2?",
    "Option A": "It has a lower administrative distance than RIPv1",
    "Option B": "It converges faster than RIPv1",
    "Option C": "It has the same timers as RIPv1",
    "Option D": "It is harder to configure than RIPv1",
    Answer: "C. It has the same timers as RIPv1",
    Topic: "RIPv2 Characteristics",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the situations might not require multiple routing protocols in a network?",
    "Option A": "When a new layer 2-only switch is added to the network",
    "Option B": "When migrating from one routing protocol to another",
    "Option C": "When using routers from multiple vendors",
    "Option D": "When there are host-based routers from multiple vendors",
    Answer: "A. When a new layer 2-only switch is added to the network",
    Topic: "Need for Multiple Routing Protocols",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which two routing protocols can be redistributed into OSPF by a Cisco router?",
    "Option A": "IP EIGRP and AppleTalk EIGRP",
    "Option B": "AppleTalk EIGRP and RIPv2",
    "Option C": "RIPv2 and IP EIGRP",
    "Option D": "IPX RIP & AppleTalk EIGRP",
    Answer: "C. RIPv2 and IP EIGRP",
    Topic: "Redistributing into OSPF by a Cisco Router",
  },
  {
    Question: "What does administrative distance rank?",
    "Option A": "Metrics",
    "Option B": "Sources of routing information",
    "Option C": "Router reliability",
    "Option D": "Best paths",
    Answer: "B. Sources of routing information",
    Topic: "Administrative Distance Ranking",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which protocol maintains neighbor adjacencies?",
    "Option A": "RIPv2 and EIGRP",
    "Option B": "IGRP and EIGRP",
    "Option C": "RIPv2",
    "Option D": "EIGRP",
    Answer: "C. RIPv2",
    Topic: "Protocols Maintaining Neighbor Adjacencies",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which routing protocol implements the diffusing update algorithm?",
    "Option A": "IS-IS",
    "Option B": "IGRP",
    "Option C": "EIGRP",
    "Option D": "OSPF",
    Answer: "C. EIGRP",
    Topic: "Diffusing Update Algorithm Implementation",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which protocol should you select if the network diameter is more than 17 hops?",
    "Option A": "ripv1",
    "Option B": "ripv2",
    "Option C": "eigrp",
    "Option D": "ospf",
    Answer: "B. ripv2",
    Topic: "Routing Protocol for Large Network Diameter (Corrected Answer)",
  },
  {
    Question: "In the network HTTP resources are located by __________",
    "Option A": "Uniform Resource Identifier",
    "Option B": "Unique Resource Locator",
    "Option C": "Unique Resource Identifier",
    "Option D": "Union Resource Locator",
    Answer: "A. Uniform Resource Identifier",
    Topic: "Locating HTTP Resources",
  },
  {
    Question: "FTP server listens for connection on which port number?",
    "Option A": 20,
    "Option B": 21,
    "Option C": 22,
    "Option D": 23,
    Answer: "B. 21",
    Topic: "FTP Server Listening Port",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In FTP protocol, a client contacts a server using ______ as the transport protocol.",
    "Option A": "Transmission Control Protocol",
    "Option B": "User Datagram Protocol",
    "Option C": "Datagram Congestion Control Protocol",
    "Option D": "Stream Control Transmission Protocol",
    Answer: "A. Transmission Control Protocol",
    Topic: "FTP Protocol Transport",
  },
  {
    Question: "The File Transfer Protocol is built on __________",
    "Option A": "Data Centric Architecture",
    "Option B": "Service Oriented Architecture",
    "Option C": "Client Server Architecture",
    "Option D": "Connection Oriented Architecture",
    Answer: "C. Client Server Architecture",
    Topic: "FTP Architecture",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In File Transfer Protocol, data transfer cannot be done in __________",
    "Option A": "Stream Mode",
    "Option B": "Block Mode",
    "Option C": "Compressed Mode",
    "Option D": "Message Mode",
    Answer: "D. Message Mode",
    Topic: "FTP Data Transfer Modes",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which methods are commonly used in Server Socket class?",
    "Option A": "Public Output Stream get Output Stream()",
    "Option B": "Public Socket accept()",
    "Option C": "Public Synchronized void close()",
    "Option D": "Public void connect()",
    Answer: "B. Public Socket accept()",
    Topic: "Server Socket Class Methods",
  },
  {
    Question: "The client in socket programming must know which information?",
    "Option A": "IP address of server",
    "Option B": "Port number",
    "Option C": "Both IP address of server & Port number",
    "Option D": "Only its own IP address",
    Answer: "C. Both IP address of server & Port number",
    Topic: "Client in Socket Programming Information",
  },
  {
    Question: "TCP, FTP, Telnet, SMTP, POP etc. are examples of ___________",
    "Option A": "Protocol",
    "Option B": "IP Address",
    "Option C": "Connection",
    "Option D": "MAC Address",
    Answer: "B. IP Address",
    Topic: "java.net.InetAddress Class Representation",
  },
  {
    Question: "What does the java.net.InetAddress class represent?",
    "Option A": "Datagram Socket",
    "Option B": "Datagram Packet",
    "Option C": "Both Datagram Socket & Datagram Packet",
    "Option D": "Server Socket",
    Answer: "C. Both Datagram Socket & Datagram Packet",
    Topic: "Connection-Less Socket Programming Classes",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which classes are used for connection-less socket programming?",
    "Option A": "Public String get Hostname()",
    "Option B": "Public String get Hostaddress()",
    "Option C": "Public Static InetAddress get Localhost()",
    "Option D": "Public Getbyname()",
    Answer: "A. Public String get Hostname()",
    Topic: "Inet Address Class Method for Hostname",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In Inet Address class, which method returns the host name of the IP Address?",
    "Option A": "Server Side Programming",
    "Option B": "Client Side Programming",
    "Option C": "Both Client Side Programming and Server Side Programming",
    "Option D": "Socket Programming",
    Answer: "B. Server Side Programming",
    Topic: "Cookies Original Design Purpose",
  },
  {
    Question: "Cookies were originally designed for ____________",
    "Option A": "Cookie",
    "Option B": "Cookies",
    "Option C": "Manipulate",
    "Option D": "Manipulate Cookie",
    Answer: "A. Cookie",
    Topic: "Cookie Manipulation Property",
  },
  {
    Question: "The Cookie manipulation is done using which property?",
    "Option A": "Non-Volatile",
    "Option B": "Volatile",
    "Option C": "Intransient",
    "Option D": "Transient",
    Answer: "D. Transient",
    Topic: "Cookies Nature",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following explains Cookies nature?",
    "Option A": "Higher-Age",
    "Option B": "Increase-Age",
    "Option C": "Max-Age",
    "Option D": "Lifetime",
    Answer: "C. Max-Age",
    Topic: "Extending Cookie Lifetime Attribute",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which attribute is used to extend the lifetime of a cookie?",
    "Option A": "Document Path",
    "Option B": "LocalStorage",
    "Option C": "SessionStorage",
    "Option D": "All of the Mentioned",
    Answer: "D. All of the Mentioned",
    Topic: "Cookie Visibility Definitions",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following defines the Cookie visibility?",
    "Option A": "Path",
    "Option B": "Domain",
    "Option C": "Both Path and Domain",
    "Option D": "Server",
    Answer: "A. Path",
    Topic: "Configuring Cookie Visibility Scope to Local Storage",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following can be used to configure the scope of the Cookie visibility?",
    "Option A": "2 kb",
    "Option B": "1 kb",
    "Option C": "4 kb",
    "Option D": "3 kb",
    Answer: "C. 4 kb",
    Topic: "Constraint on Data per Cookie",
  },
  {
    Question: "How can you set a Cookie visibility scope to local Storage?",
    "Option A": "Represent State Transfer",
    "Option B": "Representational State Transfer",
    "Option C": "Representing State Transfer",
    "Option D": "Representation State Transfer",
    Answer: "B. Representational State Transfer",
    Topic: "REST Acronym Explanation",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is a Boolean cookie attribute?",
    "Option A": "Options",
    "Option B": "Delete",
    "Option C": "Post",
    "Option D": "Head",
    Answer: "B. Delete",
    Topic: "Idempotent HTTP Methods",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the constraint on the data per cookie?",
    "Option A": "Revolving Table",
    "Option B": "Rotating Table",
    "Option C": "Routing Table",
    "Option D": "Re-allocate Table",
    Answer: "C. Routing Table",
    Topic: "Next-Hop Method Usage",
  },
  {
    Question: "What does REST stand for?",
    "Option A": "Graph",
    "Option B": "Tree",
    "Option C": "Network",
    "Option D": "Link",
    Answer: "A. Graph",
    Topic: "Unicast Routing with Dijkstra Algorithm",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following HTTP methods should be idempotent in nature?",
    "Option A": "ripv1",
    "Option B": "ripv2",
    "Option C": "eigrp",
    "Option D": "ospf",
    Answer: "B. ripv2",
    Topic: "Routing Protocol for Large Network Diameter (Corrected Answer)",
  },
  {
    Question: "Next-Hop Method is used to reduce contents of a _________",
    "Option A": "Uniform Resource Identifier",
    "Option B": "Unique Resource Locator",
    "Option C": "Unique Resource Identifier",
    "Option D": "Union Resource Locator",
    Answer: "A. Uniform Resource Identifier",
    Topic: "Locating HTTP Resources",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In Unicast Routing, Dijkstra algorithm creates a shortest path tree from a ________",
    "Option A": "Options",
    "Option B": "Delete",
    "Option C": "Post",
    "Option D": "Head",
    Answer: "B. Delete",
    Topic: "Idempotent HTTP Methods",
  },
  {
    Question: "The functionalities of the presentation layer include",
    "Option A": "Data compression",
    "Option B": "Data encryption",
    "Option C": "Data description",
    "Option D": "All of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. All of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Presentation Layer Functionalities",
  },
  {
    Question: "Delimiting and synchronization of data exchange is provided by",
    "Option A": "Application layer",
    "Option B": "Session layer",
    "Option C": "Transport layer",
    "Option D": "Link layer",
    Answer: "B. Session layer",
    Topic: "Delimiting and Synchronization of Data Exchange",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In OSI model, when data is sent from device A to device B, the 5th layer to receive data at B is",
    "Option A": "Application layer",
    "Option B": "Transport layer",
    "Option C": "Link layer",
    "Option D": "Session layer",
    Answer: "D. Session layer",
    Topic: "OSI Model Data Reception Layer",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In TCP IP Model, when data is sent from device A to device B, the 5th layer to receive data at B is",
    "Option A": "Application layer",
    "Option B": "Transport layer",
    "Option C": "Link layer",
    "Option D": "Session layer",
    Answer: "A. Application layer",
    Topic: "TCP/IP Model Data Reception Layer",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which layer is used to link the network support layers and user support layers?",
    "Option A": "Session layer",
    "Option B": "Data link layer",
    "Option C": "Transport layer",
    "Option D": "Network layer",
    Answer: "C. Transport layer",
    Topic: "Linking Network Support and User Support Layers",
  },
  {
    Question: "OSI stands for",
    "Option A": "Open system interconnection",
    "Option B": "Operating system interface",
    "Option C": "Optical service implementation",
    "Option D": "Open service Internet",
    Answer: "A. Open system interconnection",
    Topic: "OSI Model Definition",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which Project 802 standard provides for a collision-free protocol?",
    "Option A": 802.2,
    "Option B": 802.3,
    "Option C": 802.5,
    "Option D": 802.6,
    Answer: "C. 802.5",
    Topic: "Collision-Free Protocol in Project 802",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The protocol data unit (PDU) for the application layer in the Internet stack is",
    "Option A": "Segment",
    "Option B": "Datagram",
    "Option C": "Message",
    "Option D": "Frame",
    Answer: "C. Message",
    Topic: "PDU for Application Layer in Internet Stack",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is a Firewall in Computer Network?",
    "Option A": "The physical boundary of the network",
    "Option B": "An operating system of the computer network",
    "Option C": "A system designed to prevent unauthorized access",
    "Option D": "A web browsing software",
    Answer: "C. A system designed to prevent unauthorized access",
    Topic: "Firewall in Computer Network",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following services is not provided by wireless access point in 802.11 WLAN?",
    "Option A": "Association",
    "Option B": "Disassociation",
    "Option C": "Error correction",
    "Option D": "Integration",
    Answer: "C. Error correction",
    Topic: "Services provided by Wireless Access Point in 802.11 WLAN",
  },
  {
    Question: "Bridge works in which layer of the OSI model?",
    "Option A": "Application layer",
    "Option B": "Transport layer",
    "Option C": "Network layer",
    "Option D": "Data link layer",
    Answer: "D. Data link layer",
    Topic: "OSI Model Layer of Bridge",
  },
  {
    Question: "Why IP Protocol is considered as unreliable?",
    "Option A": "A packet may be lost",
    "Option B": "Packets may arrive out of order",
    "Option C": "Duplicate packets may be generated",
    "Option D": "All of the above",
    Answer: "D. All of the above",
    Topic: "Why IP Protocol is Considered Unreliable?",
  },
  {
    Question: "What are the uses of subnetting?",
    "Option A": "It divides one large network into several smaller ones",
    "Option B": "It divides the network into network classes",
    "Option C": "It speeds up the speed of the network",
    "Option D": "None of the above",
    Answer: "A. It divides one large network into several smaller ones",
    Topic: "Uses of Subnetting",
  },
  {
    Question: "The Internet is an example of",
    "Option A": "Cell-switched network",
    "Option B": "Circuit-switched network",
    "Option C": "Packet-switched network",
    "Option D": "All of the above",
    Answer: "C. Packet-switched network",
    Topic: "The Internet Example",
  },
  {
    Question: "What does protocol define?",
    "Option A": "Protocol defines what data is communicated",
    "Option B": "Protocol defines how data is communicated",
    "Option C": "Protocol defines when data is communicated",
    "Option D": "All of the above",
    Answer: "D. All of the above",
    Topic: "What Does Protocol Define?",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the use of Ping command?",
    "Option A": "To test a device on the network is reachable",
    "Option B": "To test a hard disk fault",
    "Option C": "To test a bug in an application",
    "Option D": "To test printer quality",
    Answer: "A. To test a device on the network is reachable",
    Topic: "Use of Ping Command",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the Demilitarized Zone?",
    "Option A":
      "The area between the firewall & connection to an external network",
    "Option B": "The area between ISP to the military area",
    "Option C": "The area surrounded by secured servers",
    "Option D": "The area surrounded by the military",
    Answer:
      "A. The area between the firewall & connection to an external network",
    Topic: "Demilitarized Zone",
  },
  {
    Question: "The combination of an IP address and a port number is known as.",
    "Option A": "Network number",
    "Option B": "Socket address",
    "Option C": "Subnet mask number",
    "Option D": "MAC address",
    Answer: "B. Socket address",
    Topic: "Combination of IP Address and Port Number",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is reliable communication?",
    "Option A": "TCP",
    "Option B": "IP",
    "Option C": "UPD",
    "Option D": "All of them",
    Answer: "A. TCP",
    Topic: "Reliable Communication",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the size of Host bits in Class B of IP address?",
    "Option A": 4,
    "Option B": 8,
    "Option C": 16,
    "Option D": 32,
    Answer: "C. 16",
    Topic: "Size of Host Bits in Class B IP Address",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is not associated with the session layer?",
    "Option A": "Dialog control",
    "Option B": "Token management",
    "Option C": "Semantics of the information transmitted",
    "Option D": "Synchronization",
    Answer: "C. Semantics of the information transmitted",
    Topic: "Session Layer Association",
  },
  {
    Question: "The Internet Control Message Protocol (ICMP)",
    "Option A":
      "Allows gateways to send error & control messages to other gateways or hosts",
    "Option B":
      "Provides communication between the Internet Protocol Software on one machine and the Internet Protocol Software on another",
    "Option C": "Reports error conditions to the original source",
    "Option D": "All of the above",
    Answer:
      "A. Allows gateways to send error & control messages to other gateways or hosts",
    Topic: "ICMP Purpose",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Your company has a LAN in its downtown office and has now set up a LAN in the manufacturing plant in the suburbs. To enable everyone to share data and resources between the two LANs, what type of device(s) are needed to connect them? Choose the most correct answer.",
    "Option A": "Modem",
    "Option B": "Cable",
    "Option C": "Hub",
    "Option D": "Router",
    Answer: "D. Router",
    Topic: "Devices Needed to Connect Two LANs",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following TCP/IP protocol is used for transferring electronic mail messages from one machine to another?",
    "Option A": "FTP",
    "Option B": "SNMP",
    "Option C": "SMTP",
    "Option D": "RPC",
    Answer: "C. SMTP",
    Topic: "TCP/IP Protocol for Electronic Mail Messages",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following device is used to connect two systems, especially if the systems use different protocols?",
    "Option A": "Hub",
    "Option B": "Bridge",
    "Option C": "Gateway",
    "Option D": "Repeater",
    Answer: "C. Gateway",
    Topic: "Device for Connecting Systems with Different Protocols",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Can detect burst error of length less than or equal to degree of the polynomial and detects burst errors that affect an odd number of bits.",
    "Option A": "Hamming Code",
    "Option B": "CRC",
    "Option C": "VRC",
    "Option D": "None of the above",
    Answer: "B. CRC",
    Topic: "Detection of Burst Errors",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The PSTN is an example of a............................. network.",
    "Option A": "Packet-switched",
    "Option B": "Circuit-switched",
    "Option C": "Message-switched",
    "Option D": "None of these",
    Answer: "B. Circuit-switched",
    Topic: "PSTN Example",
  },
  {
    Question: "When and where RARP is used intentionally or effectively?",
    "Option A":
      "At the time of network booting where no space to store IP address (or diskless network) for address resolution",
    "Option B": "In broadcasting to get IP address of Network",
    "Option C": "To get access in a private network whenever it is required",
    "Option D": "None of the above",
    Answer:
      "A. At the time of network booting where no space to store IP address (or diskless network) for address resolution",
    Topic: "Intentional/Effective Use of RARP",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which one of the following routing algorithms can be used for network layer design?",
    "Option A": "Shortest path algorithm",
    "Option B": "Distance vector routing",
    "Option C": "Link state routing",
    "Option D": "All of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. All of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Routing Algorithm for Network Layer Design",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A subset of a network that includes all the routers but contains no loops is called:",
    "Option A": "Spanning tree",
    "Option B": "Spider structure",
    "Option C": "Spider tree",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. Spanning tree",
    Topic: "Subset of a Network without Loops",
  },
  {
    Question: "ICMP is primarily used for:",
    "Option A": "Error and diagnostic functions",
    "Option B": "Addressing",
    "Option C": "Forwarding",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. Error and diagnostic functions",
    Topic: "ICMP Purpose",
  },
  {
    Question: "User datagram protocol is called connectionless because:",
    "Option A":
      "All UDP packets are treated independently by the transport layer",
    "Option B": "It sends data as a stream of related packets",
    "Option C": "Both (a) and (b)",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer:
      "A. All UDP packets are treated independently by the transport layer",
    Topic: "UDP Connectionless Nature",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "An endpoint of an inter-process communication flow across a computer network is called:",
    "Option A": "Socket",
    "Option B": "Pipe",
    "Option C": "Port",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. Socket",
    Topic: "Endpoint of Inter-Process Communication Flow",
  },
  {
    Question: "A is a TCP name for a transport service access point.",
    "Option A": "Port",
    "Option B": "Pipe",
    "Option C": "Node",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. Port",
    Topic: "TCP Name for Transport Service Access Point",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which one of the following is a transport layer protocol?",
    "Option A": "Stream Control Transmission Protocol",
    "Option B": "Internet Control Message Protocol",
    "Option C": "Neighbour Discovery Protocol",
    "Option D": "Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol",
    Answer: "A. Stream Control Transmission Protocol",
    Topic: "Transport Layer Protocol",
  },
  {
    Question: "Physical layer provides:",
    "Option A": "Mechanical specifications of electrical connectors and cables",
    "Option B": "Electrical specification of transmission line signal level",
    "Option C": "Specification for IR over optical fiber",
    "Option D": "All of the mentioned",
    Answer: "D. All of the mentioned",
    Topic: "Physical Layer Function",
  },
  {
    Question: "The translates internet domain and host names to IP address.",
    "Option A": "Domain Name System",
    "Option B": "Routing Information Protocol",
    "Option C": "Network Time Protocol",
    "Option D": "Internet Relay Chat",
    Answer: "A. Domain Name System",
    Topic: "IP Address Translation",
  },
  {
    Question: "When displaying a web page, the application layer uses the:",
    "Option A": "HTTP protocol",
    "Option B": "FTP protocol",
    "Option C": "SMTP protocol",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. HTTP protocol",
    Topic: "Displaying Web Page in Application Layer",
  },
  {
    Question: "This is a time-sensitive service:",
    "Option A": "File transfer",
    "Option B": "File download",
    "Option C": "E-mail",
    "Option D": "Internet telephony",
    Answer: "D. Internet telephony",
    Topic: "Time-Sensitive Service",
  },
  {
    Question: "Packet sniffers involve:",
    "Option A": "Active receiver",
    "Option B": "Passive receiver",
    "Option C": "Both of the mentioned",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "B. Passive receiver",
    Topic: "Packet Sniffers",
  },
  {
    Question: "Identify the incorrect statement:",
    "Option A": "FTP stands for File Transfer Protocol",
    "Option B": "FTP uses two parallel TCP connections",
    "Option C": "FTP sends its control information in-band",
    "Option D": "FTP sends exactly one file over the data connection",
    Answer: "C. FTP sends its control information in-band",
    Topic: "Incorrect FTP Reply Message Matching",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If 5 files are transferred from server A to client B in the same session. The number of TCP connection between A and B is:",
    "Option A": 5,
    "Option B": 10,
    "Option C": 2,
    "Option D": 6,
    Answer: "D. 6",
    Topic: "TCP Connections Between A and B",
  },
  {
    Question: "Find the FTP reply whose message is wrongly matched:",
    "Option A": "331 – Username OK, password required",
    "Option B": "425 – Can’t open data connection",
    "Option C": "452 – Error writing file",
    "Option D": "452 – Can’t open data connection",
    Answer: "D. 452 – Can’t open data connection",
    Topic: "Incorrectly Matched FTP Reply Messages",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In an Ethernet local area network, which one of the following statements is TRUE?",
    "Option A":
      "A station stops to sense the channel once it starts transmitting a frame",
    "Option B":
      "The purpose of the jamming signal is to pad the frames smaller than the minimum frame size",
    "Option C":
      "A station continues to transmit the packet even after the collision is detected",
    "Option D":
      "The exponential back off mechanism reduces the probability of collision on retransmissions",
    Answer:
      "D. The exponential back off mechanism reduces the probability of collision on retransmissions",
    Topic: "True Statement in Ethernet LAN",
  },
  {
    Question: "The first Network:",
    "Option A": "CNNET",
    "Option B": "NSFNET",
    "Option C": "ASAPNET",
    "Option D": "ARPANET",
    Answer: "D. ARPANET",
    Topic: "First Network",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which organization has authority over interstate and international commerce in the communications field?",
    "Option A": "ITU-T",
    "Option B": "IEEE",
    "Option C": "FCC",
    "Option D": "ISOC",
    Answer: "C. FCC",
    Topic:
      "Authority Over Interstate and International Commerce in Communications Field",
  },
  {
    Question: "Baud rate is:",
    "Option A": "Number of signal changes per second",
    "Option B": "Number of bits per second",
    "Option C": "Number of bytes per second",
    "Option D": "Number of ASCII characters per second",
    Answer: "A. Number of signal changes per second",
    Topic: "Baud Rate",
  },
  {
    Question: "The slowest transmission speeds are those of",
    "Option A": "Coaxial cable",
    "Option B": "Twisted pair wire",
    "Option C": "Fiber-optic cable",
    "Option D": "Microwave",
    Answer: "B. Twisted pair wire",
    Topic: "Slowest Transmission Speeds",
  },
  {
    Question: "The performance of a data communication network depends on",
    "Option A": "The number of users",
    "Option B": "The transmission media",
    "Option C": "The hardware and software",
    "Option D": "All of the above",
    Answer: "D. All of the above",
    Topic: "Performance of a Data Communication Network",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following to keep track of the individual units of data (called packets) that a message is divided into for efficient routing through the Internet.",
    "Option A": "Address Resolution Protocol (ARP)",
    "Option B": "Internet Protocol (IP)",
    "Option C": "Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP)",
    "Option D": "Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol (TCP/IP)",
    Answer: "D. Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol (TCP/IP)",
    Topic: "Tracking Packets in Data Communication Network",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the main function of the process scheduler in an operating system?",
    "Option A": "Manage user interface",
    "Option B": "Allocate memory to processes",
    "Option C": "Determine the sequence of process execution",
    "Option D": "Handle system calls",
    Answer: "C. Determine the sequence of process execution",
    Topic: "Process Scheduler in OS",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is NOT a typical state of a process in an operating system?",
    "Option A": "Running",
    "Option B": "Ready",
    "Option C": "Blocked",
    "Option D": "Merged",
    Answer: "D. Merged",
    Topic: "Process States in OS",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the purpose of a Process Control Block (PCB)?",
    "Option A": "To store the architecture of the system",
    "Option B": "To maintain process scheduling",
    "Option C": "To store all information about a process",
    "Option D": "To manage user permissions",
    Answer: "C. To store all information about a process",
    Topic: "Purpose of Process Control Block (PCB)",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In operating systems, what is fragmentation primarily concerned with?",
    "Option A": "Internet fragmentation",
    "Option B": "Process fragmentation",
    "Option C": "Memory fragmentation",
    "Option D": "File fragmentation",
    Answer: "C. Memory fragmentation",
    Topic: "Concerns of Fragmentation in OS",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which scheduling algorithm is non-preemptive?",
    "Option A": "Round Robin",
    "Option B": "Shortest Job First",
    "Option C": "Priority Scheduling",
    "Option D": "Multilevel Queue Scheduling",
    Answer: "B. Shortest Job First",
    Topic: "Non-preemptive Scheduling Algorithms",
  },
  {
    Question: "What does thrashing in an operating system signify?",
    "Option A": "Efficient memory usage",
    "Option B": "High system call frequency",
    "Option C": "Excessive paging leading to reduced performance",
    "Option D": "Optimal CPU utilization",
    Answer: "C. Excessive paging leading to reduced performance",
    Topic: "Significance of 'Thrashing'",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is NOT a type of file system?",
    "Option A": "FAT",
    "Option B": "NTFS",
    "Option C": "EXT",
    "Option D": "QFS",
    Answer: "D. QFS",
    Topic: "Types of File Systems",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is a deadlock in operating systems?",
    "Option A": "When the system crashes",
    "Option B": "When two or more processes are unable to proceed",
    "Option C": "A security breach in the system",
    "Option D": "An efficient process scheduling technique",
    Answer: "B. When two or more processes are unable to proceed",
    Topic: "Deadlock in OS",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the main advantage of using threads over processes?",
    "Option A": "Threads require more resources",
    "Option B": "Threads enhance security",
    "Option C": "Threads improve performance due to lower overhead",
    "Option D": "Threads are easier to create",
    Answer: "C. Threads improve performance due to lower overhead",
    Topic: "Advantages of Threads over Processes",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is a feature of virtual memory?",
    "Option A": "It only uses the hard disk space",
    "Option B":
      "It allows execution of processes that may not be completely in memory",
    "Option C": "It increases the physical memory size",
    "Option D": "It replaces the need for RAM",
    Answer:
      "B. It allows execution of processes that may not be completely in memory",
    Topic: "Feature of Virtual Memory",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the purpose of demand paging in virtual memory systems?",
    "Option A": "To reduce the process execution time",
    "Option B": "To increase the hard disk space",
    "Option C": "To load pages into memory only when they are needed",
    "Option D": "To eliminate the need for secondary storage",
    Answer: "C. To load pages into memory only when they are needed",
    Topic: "Purpose of Demand Paging",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which page replacement algorithm replaces the page that will not be used for the longest period in the future?",
    "Option A": "FIFO (First In First Out)",
    "Option B": "LRU (Least Recently Used)",
    "Option C": "Optimal Page Replacement",
    "Option D": "MRU (Most Recently Used)",
    Answer: "C. Optimal Page Replacement",
    Topic: "Page Replacement Algorithms",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the function of the kernel?",
    "Option A": "Providing a user interface",
    "Option B": "Word processing",
    "Option C": "Managing system resources",
    "Option D": "Internet browsing",
    Answer: "C. Managing system resources",
    Topic: "Function of the Kernel",
  },
  {
    Question: "In a paging system, what is a page table used for?",
    "Option A": "To hold user data",
    "Option B": "To queue up processes for execution",
    "Option C": "To map virtual addresses to physical addresses",
    "Option D": "To prioritize CPU requests",
    Answer: "C. To map virtual addresses to physical addresses",
    Topic: "Purpose of Page Table in Paging System",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following best describes the concept of 'Swapping'?",
    "Option A": "Exchanging data between RAM and the CPU",
    "Option B": "Exchanging data between processes",
    "Option C": "Moving processes in and out of the main memory",
    "Option D": "Swapping data between different storage devices",
    Answer: "C. Moving processes in and out of the main memory",
    Topic: "Concept of 'Swapping'",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is a semaphore in the context of operating systems?",
    "Option A": "A memory segment",
    "Option B":
      "A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system",
    "Option C": "A type of scheduling algorithm",
    "Option D": "A signal for process communication",
    Answer:
      "B. A variable used to control access to a common resource in a concurrent system",
    Topic: "Semaphore in OS",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is NOT a goal of file management in operating systems?",
    "Option A": "Ensuring data consistency",
    "Option B": "Maximizing network throughput",
    "Option C": "Providing security and access rights",
    "Option D": "Organizing storage space efficiently",
    Answer: "B. Maximizing network throughput",
    Topic: "Goals of File Management in OS",
  },
  {
    Question: "In the context of CPU scheduling, what does SJF stand for?",
    "Option A": "System Job First",
    "Option B": "Shortest Job First",
    "Option C": "Sequential Job Filing",
    "Option D": "Shortest Journey First",
    Answer: "B. Shortest Job First",
    Topic: "SJF in CPU Scheduling",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which allocation method is used in file systems for large files to minimize fragmentation?",
    "Option A": "Linked allocation",
    "Option B": "Contiguous allocation",
    "Option C": "Indexed allocation",
    "Option D": "Stack allocation",
    Answer: "C. Indexed allocation",
    Topic: "Allocation Methods for Large Files",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the primary role of the session layer in the OSI model?",
    "Option A": "Encrypting data",
    "Option B": "Establishing, managing, and terminating sessions",
    "Option C": "Routing data between nodes",
    "Option D": "Data compression",
    Answer: "B. Establishing, managing, and terminating sessions",
    Topic: "Role of Session Layer in OSI Model",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following is a characteristic of preemptive scheduling?",
    "Option A": "The CPU is allocated to the process for a limited time",
    "Option B": "Processes are executed on a first-come, first-serve basis",
    "Option C": "Once a process starts, it runs to completion",
    "Option D": "The user manually switches between processes",
    Answer: "A. The CPU is allocated to the process for a limited time",
    Topic: "Preemptive Scheduling Characteristics",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What does the term 'Thrashing' refer to in the context of virtual memory management?",
    "Option A": "Efficient use of cache",
    "Option B": "Constantly swapping pages in and out of memory",
    "Option C": "Reducing the number of page faults",
    "Option D": "Compressing data to fit more in memory",
    Answer: "B. Constantly swapping pages in and out of memory",
    Topic: "'Thrashing' in Virtual Memory",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which layer of the OSI model is responsible for error detection and correction in the data link layer?",
    "Option A": "Physical Layer",
    "Option B": "Data Link Layer",
    "Option C": "Network Layer",
    "Option D": "Transport Layer",
    Answer: "B. Data Link Layer",
    Topic: "Error Detection and Correction in Data Link Layer",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is an IP address primarily used for in network communications?",
    "Option A": "Identifying the type of data being sent",
    "Option B": "Identifying the physical location of the network device",
    "Option C": "Identifying the unique network device on the internet",
    "Option D": "Encrypting data for secure transmission",
    Answer: "C. Identifying the unique network device on the internet",
    Topic: "Purpose of IP Address in Network Communications",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is a deadlock in operating systems?",
    "Option A": "When the system crashes",
    "Option B": "When two or more processes are unable to proceed",
    "Option C": "A security breach in the system",
    "Option D": "An efficient process scheduling technique",
    Answer: "B. When two or more processes are unable to proceed",
    Topic: "Deadlock in OS",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the main advantage of using threads over processes?",
    "Option A": "Threads require more resources",
    "Option B": "Threads enhance security",
    "Option C": "Threads improve performance due to lower overhead",
    "Option D": "Threads are easier to create",
    Answer: "C. Threads improve performance due to lower overhead",
    Topic: "Advantages of Threads over Processes",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which of the following is a feature of virtual memory?",
    "Option A": "It only uses the hard disk space",
    "Option B":
      "It allows execution of processes that may not be completely in memory",
    "Option C": "It increases the physical memory size",
    "Option D": "It replaces the need for RAM",
    Answer:
      "B. It allows execution of processes that may not be completely in memory",
    Topic: "Feature of Virtual Memory",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the purpose of demand paging in virtual memory systems?",
    "Option A": "To reduce the process execution time",
    "Option B": "To increase the hard disk space",
    "Option C": "To load pages into memory only when they are needed",
    "Option D": "To eliminate the need for secondary storage",
    Answer: "C. To load pages into memory only when they are needed",
    Topic: "Purpose of Demand Paging",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which page replacement algorithm replaces the page that will not be used for the longest period in the future?",
    "Option A": "FIFO (First In First Out)",
    "Option B": "LRU (Least Recently Used)",
    "Option C": "Optimal Page Replacement",
    "Option D": "MRU (Most Recently Used)",
    Answer: "C. Optimal Page Replacement",
    Topic: "Page Replacement Algorithms",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following best describes the concept of 'Swapping'?",
    "Option A": "Exchanging data between RAM and the CPU",
    "Option B": "Exchanging data between processes",
    "Option C": "Moving processes in and out of the main memory",
    "Option D": "Swapping data between different storage devices",
    Answer: "C. Moving processes in and out of the main memory",
    Topic: "Concept of 'Swapping'",
  },
  {
    Question: "What does the acronym ISDN stand for?",
    "Option A": "Indian Standard Digital Network",
    "Option B": "Integrated Services Digital Network",
    "Option C": "Intelligent Services Digital Network",
    "Option D": "Integrated Services Data Network",
    Answer: "B. Integrated Services Digital Network",
    Topic: "Network Topology",
  },
  {
    Question: "ASK, PSK, FSK, and QAM are examples of encoding.",
    "Option A": "Digital-to-digital",
    "Option B": "Digital-to-analog",
    "Option C": "Analog-to-analog",
    "Option D": "Analog-to-digital",
    Answer: "B. Digital-to-analog",
    Topic: "Examples of Encoding: ASK, PSK, FSK, QAM",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which utility is an all-purpose tool for troubleshooting TCP/IP problems?",
    "Option A": "NBTSTAT",
    "Option B": "Netstat",
    "Option C": "PING",
    "Option D": "Hostname",
    Answer: "C. PING",
    Topic: "TCP/IP",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Your company has a LAN in its downtown office and has now set up a LAN in the manufacturing plant in the suburbs. To enable everyone to share data and resources between the two LANs, what type of device(s) are needed to connect them? Choose the most correct answer.",
    "Option A": "Modem",
    "Option B": "Cable",
    "Option C": "Hub",
    "Option D": "Router",
    Answer: "D. Router",
    Topic: "LAN Connection",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following TCP/IP protocol is used for transferring electronic mail messages from one machine to another?",
    "Option A": "FTP",
    "Option B": "SNMP",
    "Option C": "SMTP",
    "Option D": "RPC",
    Answer: "C. SMTP",
    Topic: "TCP/IP Protocol for Email",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following device is used to connect two systems, especially if the systems use different protocols?",
    "Option A": "Hub",
    "Option B": "Bridge",
    "Option C": "Gateway",
    "Option D": "Repeater",
    Answer: "C. Gateway",
    Topic: "Connecting Systems with Different Protocols",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "_______ can detect burst error of length less than or equal to degree of the polynomial and detects burst errors that affect an odd number of bits.",
    "Option A": "Hamming Code",
    "Option B": "CRC",
    "Option C": "VRC",
    "Option D": "None of the above",
    Answer: "B. CRC",
    Topic: "Burst Error Detection",
  },
  {
    Question: "The PSTN is an example of a ………………… network.",
    "Option A": "Packet Switched",
    "Option B": "Circuit Switched",
    "Option C": "Message Switched",
    "Option D": "None of these",
    Answer: "B. Circuit Switched",
    Topic: "PSTN Example",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A subset of a network that includes all the routers but contains no loops is called:",
    "Option A": "Spanning Tree",
    "Option B": "Spider Structure",
    "Option C": "Spider Tree",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. Spanning Tree",
    Topic: "Network Subset without Loops",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "An endpoint of an inter-process communication flow across a computer network is called:",
    "Option A": "Socket",
    "Option B": "Pipe",
    "Option C": "Port",
    "Option D": "None of the mentioned",
    Answer: "A. Socket",
    Topic: "Endpoint of Inter-process Communication Flow",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In an Ethernet local area network, which one of the following statements is TRUE?",
    "Option A":
      "A station stops to sense the channel once it starts transmitting a frame.",
    "Option B":
      "The purpose of the jamming signal is to pad the frames that are smaller than the minimum frame size.",
    "Option C":
      "A station continues to transmit the packet even after the collision is detected.",
    "Option D":
      "The exponential back-off mechanism reduces the probability of collision on retransmissions",
    Answer:
      "D. The exponential back-off mechanism reduces the probability of collision on retransmissions",
    Topic: "Ethernet LAN",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "A small network making up the Internet and also having a small number of computers within it is called",
    "Option A": "Host",
    "Option B": "Address",
    "Option C": "Subdomain",
    "Option D": "None of the above",
    Answer: "C. Subdomain",
    Topic: "Small Network in the Internet",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If a file consisting of 50,000 characters takes 40 seconds to send, then the data rate is __________.",
    "Option A": "1 kbps",
    "Option B": "1.25 kbps",
    "Option C": "2 kbps",
    "Option D": "10 kbps",
    Answer: "D. 10 kbps",
    Topic: "Data Rate Calculation",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In CRC there is no error if the remainder at the receiver is _____.",
    "Option A": "Equal to the remainder at the sender",
    "Option B": "Zero",
    "Option C": "Nonzero",
    "Option D": "The quotient at the sender",
    Answer: "B. Zero",
    Topic: "CRC and Error Detection",
  },
  {
    Question: "A modulator converts a _____ signal to a(n) _____ signal.",
    "Option A": "FSK; PSK",
    "Option B": "PSK; FSK",
    "Option C": "Analog; Digital",
    "Option D": "Digital; Analog",
    Answer: "C. Analog; Digital",
    Topic: "Modulator Conversion",
  },
  {
    Question: "ASK, PSK, FSK, and QAM are examples of _____ encoding.",
    "Option A": "Digital-to-digital",
    "Option B": "Digital-to-analog",
    "Option C": "Analog-to-analog",
    "Option D": "Analog-to-digital",
    Answer: "B. Digital-to-analog",
    Topic: "Encoding Examples",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "With an IP address of 201.142.23.12, what is your default subnet mask?",
    "Option A": "0.0.0.0",
    "Option B": "255.0.0.0",
    "Option C": "255.255.0.0",
    "Option D": "255.255.255.0",
    Answer: "D. 255.255.255.0",
    Topic: "Default Subnet Mask",
  },
  {
    Question: "DSL stands for ------------------------",
    "Option A": "Data Subscriber Lines",
    "Option B": "Dual Subscriber Lines",
    "Option C": "Delay Subscriber Lines",
    "Option D": "Digital Subscriber Lines",
    Answer: "D. Digital Subscriber Lines",
    Topic: "DSL Abbreviation",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "The 802.5 standard implements a way for preventing collisions on the network. How are collisions prevented when using this standard?",
    "Option A": "CSMA/CD",
    "Option B": "Token Passing",
    "Option C": "Collision Detection",
    "Option D": "Time Sharing",
    Answer: "B. Token Passing",
    Topic: "Collision Prevention in 802.5 Standard",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "One of the header fields in an IP datagram is the Time to Live (TTL) field. Which of the following statements best explains the need for this field?",
    "Option A": "It can be used to prioritize packets",
    "Option B": "It can be used to reduce delays",
    "Option C": "It can be used to optimize throughput",
    "Option D": "It can be used to prevent packet looping",
    Answer: "D. It can be used to prevent packet looping",
    Topic: "Time to Live (TTL) Field in IP Datagram",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following system calls results in the sending of SYN packets?",
    "Option A": "Socket",
    "Option B": "Bind",
    "Option C": "Listen",
    "Option D": "Connect",
    Answer: "D. Connect",
    Topic: "SYN Packets Sending System Call",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the maximum size of data that the application layer can pass on to the TCP layer below?",
    "Option A": "Any size",
    "Option B": "2^16 bytes-size of TCP header",
    "Option C": "2^16 bytes",
    "Option D": "1500 bytes",
    Answer: "A. Any size",
    Topic: "Maximum Size Passed to TCP Layer",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Station A needs to send a message consisting of 9 packets to Station B using a sliding window (window size 3) and go-back-n error control strategy. All packets are ready and immediately available for transmission. If every 5th packet that A transmits gets lost (but no acks from B ever get lost), then what is the number of packets that A will transmit for sending the message to B?",
    "Option A": 12,
    "Option B": 14,
    "Option C": 16,
    "Option D": 18,
    Answer: "C. 16",
    Topic: "Sliding Window and Go-Back-N Strategy",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which one of the following statements is FALSE?",
    "Option A":
      "Packet switching leads to better utilization of bandwidth resources than circuit switching.",
    "Option B":
      "Packet switching results in less variation in delay than circuit switching.",
    "Option C":
      "Packet switching requires more per-packet processing than circuit switching",
    "Option D":
      "Packet switching can lead to reordering unlike in circuit switching",
    Answer:
      "B. Packet switching results in less variation in delay than circuit switching.",
    Topic: "False Statement",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In a packet switching network, if the message size is 48 bytes and each packet contains a header of 3 bytes. If 24 packets are required to transmit the message, the packet size is ________.",
    "Option A": "2 bytes",
    "Option B": "1 byte",
    "Option C": "4 bytes",
    "Option D": "5 bytes",
    Answer: "D. 5 bytes",
    Topic: "Packet Size Calculation",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In Ethernet CSMA/CD, the special bit sequence transmitted by media access management to handle a collision is called",
    "Option A": "Preamble",
    "Option B": "Postamble",
    "Option C": "Jam",
    "Option D": "None of the above",
    Answer: "C. Jam",
    Topic: "Special Bit Sequence for Collisions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "How many digits of the DNIC (Data Network Identification Code) identify the country?",
    "Option A": "First three",
    "Option B": "First four",
    "Option C": "First five",
    "Option D": "First six",
    Answer: "A. First three",
    Topic: "DNIC (Data Network Identification Code)",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following TCP/IP protocol is used for transferring electronic mail messages from one machine to another?",
    "Option A": "FTP",
    "Option B": "SNMP",
    "Option C": "SMTP",
    "Option D": "RPC",
    Answer: "C. SMTP",
    Topic: "TCP/IP Protocol for Email",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following device is used to connect two systems, especially if the systems use different protocols?",
    "Option A": "Hub",
    "Option B": "Bridge",
    "Option C": "Gateway",
    "Option D": "Repeater",
    Answer: "C. Gateway",
    Topic: "Connecting Systems with Different Protocols",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "_______ can detect burst error of length less than or equal to the degree of the polynomial and detects burst errors that affect an odd number of bits.",
    "Option A": "Hamming Code",
    "Option B": "CRC",
    "Option C": "VRC",
    "Option D": "None of the above",
    Answer: "B. CRC",
    Topic: "Burst Error Detection",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "If 5 files are transferred from server A to client B in the same session. The number of TCP connection between A and B is:",
    "Option A": 5,
    "Option B": 10,
    "Option C": 2,
    "Option D": 6,
    Answer: "D. 6",
    Topic: "TCP Connections",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "In an Ethernet local area network, which one of the following statements is TRUE?",
    "Option A":
      "A station stops to sense the channel once it starts transmitting a frame.",
    "Option B":
      "The purpose of the jamming signal is to pad the frames that are smaller than the minimum frame size.",
    "Option C":
      "A station continues to transmit the packet even after the collision is detected.",
    "Option D":
      "The exponential back-off mechanism reduces the probability of collision on retransmissions",
    Answer:
      "A. A station stops to sense the channel once it starts transmitting a frame.",
    Topic: "Ethernet LAN",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which of the following to keep track of the individual units of data (called packets) that a message is divided into for efficient routing through the Internet.",
    "Option A": "Address Resolution Protocol (ARP)",
    "Option B": "Internet Protocol (IP)",
    "Option C": "Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP)",
    "Option D": "Tr",
    Answer: "C. Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP)",
    Topic: "Efficient Routing through the Internet",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT DISTINCT country FROM customers ORDER BY country; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      ' Retrieves all distinct countries from the "customers" table and sorts them in alphabetical order. ',
    "Option B":
      " Retrieves customers from a specific country and orders them by their names. ",
    "Option C":
      ' Updates the country names in the "customers" table and removes duplicates. ',
    "Option D":
      ' Retrieves the total number of distinct countries in the "customers" table. ',
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  UPDATE products SET price = price * 1.1; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A": " Retrieves the products with a price increase of 10%. ",
    "Option B": " Updates the product price to be 110% of its current price. ",
    "Option C": " Retrieves the products with a price decrease of 10%. ",
    "Option D": " Inserts new products with prices increased by 10%. ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT supplier_name, COUNT(product_id) FROM suppliers JOIN products ON suppliers.supplier_id = products.supplier_id GROUP BY supplier_name; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves supplier names and counts of products for each supplier. ",
    "Option B":
      " Retrieves all suppliers and products from the products table. ",
    "Option C":
      " Updates supplier names and counts of products for each supplier. ",
    "Option D": " Deletes suppliers and products with matching IDs. ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT customer_id, COUNT(order_id) FROM orders GROUP BY customer_id ORDER BY COUNT(order_id) DESC LIMIT 3; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves the customer IDs and counts of orders, sorted by the count in descending order, and limits the result to 3 rows. ",
    "Option B": " Retrieves all customers and orders, sorted by the order I",
    "Option C":
      " Updates customer IDs and counts of orders in descending order. ",
    "Option D": " Deletes customers with at least 3 orders. ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT department_name, COUNT(employee_id) FROM departments LEFT JOIN employees ON departments.department_id = employees.department_id GROUP BY department_name; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves department names and counts of employees for each department. ",
    "Option B":
      " Retrieves all departments and employees from the employees table. ",
    "Option C":
      " Updates department names and counts of employees for each department. ",
    "Option D": " Deletes departments with no employees. ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  UPDATE employees SET manager_id = NULL WHERE department_id = 5; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves employees from department 5 and sets their manager IDs to NULL. ",
    "Option B":
      " Updates the manager ID for employees in department 5 to NULL. ",
    "Option C": " Retrieves employees from department 5 and deletes them. ",
    "Option D":
      " Inserts new employees into department 5 and sets their manager IDs to NULL. ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  INSERT INTO employees (first_name, last_name) VALUES ('John', 'Doe'); What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A": " Deletes an employee named John Doe. ",
    "Option B":
      " Inserts a new employee named John Doe into the employees table. ",
    "Option C":
      " Updates the first and last names of an employee to John and Doe. ",
    "Option D": " Retrieves employee information for John Doe. ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  DELETE FROM suppliers WHERE supplier_name LIKE '%Limited'; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves suppliers with names that contain the word 'Limited' and deletes them. ",
    "Option B":
      " Updates the supplier name to include the word 'Limited' for certain suppliers. ",
    "Option C":
      " Deletes all suppliers with names that do not contain the word 'Limited'. ",
    "Option D":
      " Inserts new suppliers with names containing the word 'Limited'. ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  UPDATE products SET stock_quantity = stock_quantity - 20 WHERE stock_quantity >= 20; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves products with a stock quantity of 20 and updates their stock quantity. ",
    "Option B":
      " Updates the stock quantity for products with a stock quantity of 20 or more. ",
    "Option C":
      " Retrieves products with a stock quantity of 20 or more and updates their stock quantity. ",
    "Option D": " Deletes products with a stock quantity of 20. ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT category, MAX(price) FROM products GROUP BY category HAVING MAX(price) < 500; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves the maximum price of each product category and filters results where the maximum price is less than 500. ",
    "Option B":
      " Retrieves all product categories and their corresponding maximum prices. ",
    "Option C":
      " Updates the category names to have a maximum price of less than 500. ",
    "Option D":
      " Retrieves category names where the maximum price is exactly 500. ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  DELETE FROM orders WHERE customer_id IN (SELECT customer_id FROM customers WHERE country = 'France'); What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A": " Retrieves orders for customers in France and deletes them. ",
    "Option B": " Updates the country for customers in France. ",
    "Option C": " Deletes orders for customers not in France. ",
    "Option D": " Deletes customers from France. ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  UPDATE products SET price = price - 10 WHERE category = 'Books'; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves products with a price of 10 and updates their price. ",
    "Option B":
      " Updates the price for products in the Books category by subtracting 10. ",
    "Option C":
      " Retrieves products in the Books category and updates their price. ",
    "Option D": " Deletes products in the Books category with a price of 10. ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT customer_id, COUNT(order_id) FROM orders GROUP BY customer_id HAVING COUNT(order_id) < 5; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves the customer IDs and counts of orders, sorted by the count in ascending order, and limits the result to 5 rows. ",
    "Option B": " Retrieves all customers and orders, sorted by the order I",
    "Option C":
      " Updates customer IDs and counts of orders in ascending order. ",
    "Option D": " Deletes customers with less than 5 orders. ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  DELETE FROM employees WHERE hire_date BETWEEN '2022-01-01' AND '2022-12-31'; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves employees hired between January 1, 2022, and December 31, 2022, and deletes them. ",
    "Option B":
      " Updates the hire date to be between January 1, 2022, and December 31, 2022. ",
    "Option C":
      " Deletes employees hired outside of the specified date range. ",
    "Option D":
      " Deletes employees hired between January 1, 2022, and December 31, 2022. ",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT department_name, MAX(salary) FROM employees JOIN departments ON employees.department_id = departments.department_id GROUP BY department_name; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves department names and counts of employees for each department. ",
    "Option B":
      " Retrieves all departments and employees from the departments table. ",
    "Option C":
      " Updates department names and counts of employees for each department. ",
    "Option D": " Deletes departments and employees with matching IDs. ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  UPDATE orders SET total_amount = total_amount * 0.9 WHERE order_date < '2023-03-01'; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves orders placed before March 1, 2023, and updates their total amounts. ",
    "Option B":
      " Updates the order date to March 1, 2023, for certain orders. ",
    "Option C":
      " Retrieves orders with a total amount of 0.9 and updates their order date. ",
    "Option D": " Deletes orders placed after March 1, 2023. ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT category, COUNT() FROM products GROUP BY category HAVING COUNT() > 10; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A": " Retrieves the total number of products in each category. ",
    "Option B":
      " Retrieves all product categories and their corresponding counts where count is greater than 10. ",
    "Option C": " Updates the product categories to have a count of 10. ",
    "Option D":
      " Retrieves the product categories and the count of products where the count is exactly 10. ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  DELETE FROM orders WHERE order_status = 'Shipped'; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A": ' Retrieves orders with a status of "Shipped". ',
    "Option B": ' Updates the order status to "Shipped". ',
    "Option C":
      ' Deletes orders with a status of "Shipped" from the "orders" table. ',
    "Option D": ' Inserts new orders with a status of "Shipped". ',
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT department_name, AVG(salary) FROM employees JOIN departments ON employees.department_id = departments.department_id GROUP BY department_name HAVING AVG(salary) > 55000; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves the average salary for each department and filters results where the average salary is over 55000. ",
    "Option B":
      " Retrieves all departments and employees from the departments table. ",
    "Option C":
      " Updates department names and average salaries for departments with salaries over 55000. ",
    "Option D": " Deletes departments and employees with matching IDs. ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  UPDATE customers SET contact_name = 'New Contact' WHERE city = 'London'; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves contacts in London and sets their contact names to 'New Contact'. ",
    "Option B":
      " Updates the contact name for customers in London to 'New Contact'. ",
    "Option C": " Deletes contacts in London. ",
    "Option D":
      " Inserts new customers into London with contact name 'New Contact'. ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT supplier_name, COUNT(product_id) FROM suppliers LEFT JOIN products ON suppliers.supplier_id = products.supplier_id GROUP BY supplier_name HAVING COUNT(product_id) < 3; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves the supplier names and counts of products for each supplier, including those with no products, and filters results where the count is less than 3. ",
    "Option B":
      " Retrieves all suppliers and products from the products table. ",
    "Option C":
      " Updates supplier names and counts of products for suppliers with fewer than 3 products. ",
    "Option D": " Deletes suppliers with at least 3 products. ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  DELETE FROM employees WHERE employee_id NOT IN (SELECT manager_id FROM employees WHERE manager_id IS NOT NULL); What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A": " Deletes employees who are not managers. ",
    "Option B": " Updates the manager ID for employees who are not managers. ",
    "Option C": " Retrieves employees who are not managers. ",
    "Option D": " Deletes employees who are managers. ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  UPDATE products SET price = price + 5 WHERE category = 'Toys'; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves products with a price of 5 and updates their price. ",
    "Option B":
      " Updates the price for products in the Toys category by adding 5. ",
    "Option C":
      " Retrieves products in the Toys category and updates their price. ",
    "Option D": " Deletes products in the Toys category with a price of 5. ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  DELETE FROM orders WHERE order_date BETWEEN '2023-01-01' AND '2023-12-31'; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves orders placed between January 1, 2023, and December 31, 2023, and deletes them. ",
    "Option B":
      " Updates the order date to be between January 1, 2023, and December 31, 2023. ",
    "Option C": " Deletes orders placed outside of the specified date range. ",
    "Option D":
      " Deletes orders placed between January 1, 2023, and December 31, 2023. ",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT department_name, MIN(salary) FROM employees JOIN departments ON employees.department_id = departments.department_id GROUP BY department_name HAVING MIN(salary) < 40000; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves the minimum salary for each department and filters results where the minimum salary is less than 40000. ",
    "Option B":
      " Retrieves all departments and employees from the departments table. ",
    "Option C":
      " Updates department names and minimum salaries for departments with salaries less than 40000. ",
    "Option D": " Deletes departments and employees with matching IDs. ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  UPDATE suppliers SET contact_name = 'Updated Contact' WHERE supplier_id IN (SELECT supplier_id FROM products WHERE category = 'Electronics'); What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves contacts for suppliers in the Electronics category and updates their contact names. ",
    "Option B":
      " Updates the contact name for suppliers in the Electronics category to 'Updated Contact'. ",
    "Option C": " Deletes contacts for suppliers in the Electronics category. ",
    "Option D":
      " Inserts new suppliers into the Electronics category with contact name 'Updated Contact'. ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT product_name, price FROM products ORDER BY price DESC LIMIT 5; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves the product names and prices of the top 5 expensive products ",
    "Option B":
      " Retrieves the product names and prices of the cheapest products ",
    "Option C": " Updates the product prices to be in descending order ",
    "Option D": " Retrieves all product names and prices ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  DELETE FROM orders WHERE order_date < '2023-06-01'; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A": " Retrieves orders placed before June 1, 2023 ",
    "Option B": " Updates the order date to be June 1, 2023, for some orders ",
    "Option C": " Deletes orders placed after June 1, 2023 ",
    "Option D": " Deletes orders placed before June 1, 2023 ",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT first_name, last_name, birth_date FROM employees WHERE birth_date BETWEEN '1990-01-01' AND '2000-12-31'; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves employees with birth dates between January 1, 1990, and December 31, 2000 ",
    "Option B":
      " Updates employees' birth dates to be between the specified range ",
    "Option C": " Deletes employees born between 1990 and 2000 ",
    "Option D":
      " Retrieves employees with birth dates outside the specified range ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT customer_id, COUNT(order_id) FROM orders GROUP BY customer_id HAVING COUNT(order_id) >= 3; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A": " Retrieves the total count of orders for each customer ",
    "Option B":
      " Retrieves customer IDs and the count of orders where the count is at least 3 ",
    "Option C": " Updates the customer IDs to have a count of 3 ",
    "Option D":
      " Retrieves the customer IDs and the count of orders where the count is less than 3 ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  UPDATE suppliers SET contact_name = 'New Contact' WHERE supplier_id = 123; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A": " Retrieves contact names for supplier with ID 123 ",
    "Option B":
      " Updates the contact name for supplier with ID 123 to 'New Contact' ",
    "Option C": " Deletes the contact name for supplier with ID 123 ",
    "Option D":
      " Inserts a new supplier with contact name 'New Contact' and ID 123 ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  DELETE FROM orders WHERE order_status = 'Canceled'; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A": ' Retrieves orders with a status of "Canceled" ',
    "Option B": ' Updates the order status to "Canceled" ',
    "Option C":
      ' Deletes orders with a status of "Canceled" from the "orders" table ',
    "Option D": ' Inserts new orders with a status of "Canceled" ',
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  DELETE FROM employees WHERE hire_date < '2022-01-01'; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A": " Retrieves employees hired before January 1, 2022 ",
    "Option B":
      " Updates the hire date to January 1, 2022, for some employees ",
    "Option C": " Deletes employees hired after January 1, 2022 ",
    "Option D": " Deletes employees hired before January 1, 2022 ",
    Answer: 4,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT product_name, SUM(quantity) FROM order_details GROUP BY product_name HAVING SUM(quantity) > 100; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A": " Retrieves the total quantity of each product sold ",
    "Option B":
      " Retrieves product names and their corresponding quantities where quantity is greater than 100 ",
    "Option C": " Updates the product names to have a quantity of 100 ",
    "Option D": " Retrieves product names where the quantity is exactly 100 ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  DELETE FROM customers WHERE age < 18; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A": " Retrieves customers who are under 18 years old ",
    "Option B": " Updates the age of customers under 18 years old ",
    "Option C":
      ' Deletes customers under 18 years old from the "customers" table ',
    "Option D":
      ' Inserts new customers into the "customers" table who are under 18 years old ',
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT employee_id, MAX(salary) FROM employees GROUP BY employee_id; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A": " Retrieves the maximum salary for each employee ",
    "Option B":
      " Retrieves employee IDs and the maximum salary for each employee ",
    "Option C": " Updates employee IDs to have the maximum salary value ",
    "Option D": " Retrieves the maximum salary from the employees table ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  UPDATE customers SET city = 'New City' WHERE state = 'CA'; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A": ' Retrieves customers in the "New City" ',
    "Option B":
      " Updates the city for customers in California to be 'New City' ",
    "Option C": ' Deletes customers in the "New City" ',
    "Option D": ' Inserts new customers from the "New City" ',
    Answer: 4,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  SELECT department, AVG(salary) FROM employees GROUP BY department HAVING AVG(salary) > 50000; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves the average salary of all employees in each department ",
    "Option B":
      " Retrieves department names and their corresponding average salaries where average salary is greater than 50000 ",
    "Option C":
      " Updates the department names to have an average salary of 50000 ",
    "Option D":
      " Retrieves the average salary of employees with an average salary of 50000 ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the following SQL code snippet:  DELETE FROM orders WHERE order_date BETWEEN '2023-01-01' AND '2023-07-31'; What does this code snippet do? ",
    "Option A":
      " Retrieves orders placed between January 1, 2023, and July 31, 2023 ",
    "Option B":
      " Updates the order date to be between January 1, 2023, and July 31, 2023 ",
    "Option C": " Deletes orders placed after July 31, 2023 ",
    "Option D":
      " Deletes orders placed between January 1, 2023, and July 31, 2023 ",
    Answer: 4,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      'Conside the Following Functional Dependency Patient_id → First_name, Last_name, Gender, Birth_date, City, Province_id, Allergies, Height, Weight  Write an SQL query to retrieve the first name, last name, and age of male patients from the "patients" table who have allergies and weigh between 70 and 90 kg. Calculate age based on the current date and the patient\'s birth date.',
    "Option A":
      "SELECT first_name, last_name, YEAR(CURDATE()) - YEAR(birth_date) - DATE_FORMAT(CURDATE(), '%m%d') < DATE_FORMAT(birth_date, '%m%d')) AS age FROM patients WHERE gender = 'M' AND allergies IS NOT NULL AND weight BETWEEN 70 AND 90;",
    "Option B":
      "SELECT first_name, last_name, DATEDIFF(CURDATE(), birth_date) / 365 AS age FROM patients WHERE gender = 'M' AND allergies IS NOT NULL AND weight BETWEEN 70 AND 90;",
    "Option C":
      "SELECT first_name, last_name, YEAR(CURRENT_TIMESTAMP) - YEAR(birth_date) - DATE_FORMAT(CURRENT_TIMESTAMP, '%m%d') < DATE_FORMAT(birth_date, '%m%d')) AS age FROM patients WHERE gender = 'M' AND allergies IS NOT NULL AND weight BETWEEN 70 AND 90;",
    "Option D":
      "SELECT first_name, last_name, DATEDIFF(CURRENT_TIMESTAMP, birth_date) / 365 AS age FROM patients WHERE gender = 'M' AND allergies IS NOT NULL AND weight BETWEEN 70 AND 90;",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      'Conside the Following Functional Dependency Patient_id → First_name, Last_name, Gender, Birth_date, City, Province_id, Allergies, Height, Weight  Write an SQL query to find the cities that have the highest average weight among female patients in the "patients" table. Include the city name and the computed average weight. ',
    "Option A":
      "SELECT city, AVG(weight) AS avg_weight FROM patients WHERE gender = 'F' GROUP BY city ORDER BY  avg_weight ASC LIMIT 1;",
    "Option B":
      "SELECT city, AVG(weight) AS avg_weight FROM patients WHERE gender = 'F' GROUP BY city HAVING avg_weight = MAX(avg_weight);",
    "Option C":
      "SELECT city, AVG(weight) AS avg_weight FROM patients WHERE gender = 'F' GROUP BY city ORDER BY avg_weight DESC LIMIT 1;",
    "Option D":
      "SELECT city, AVG(weight) AS avg_weight FROM patients WHERE gender = 'F' GROUP BY city ORDER BY avg_weight DESC;",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      'Conside the Following Functional Dependency Patient_id → First_name, Last_name, Gender, Birth_date, City, Province_id, Allergies, Height, Weight  Write an SQL query to identify the patient with the highest Body Mass Index (BMI) from each province in the "patients" table. Include the patient\'s first name, last name, province ID, and calculated BMI. The BMI is calculated as weight (kg) divided by height squared (m^2).',
    "Option A":
      "SELECT p1.first_name, p1.last_name, p1.province_id, (p1.weight / (p1.height * p1.height)) AS bmi FROM patients p1 WHERE (p1.province_id, p1.weight / (p1.height * p1.height)) IN ( SELECT province_id, MAX(weight / (height * height)) AS max_bmi FROM patients GROUP BY province_id);",
    "Option B":
      "SELECT p1.first_name, p1.last_name, p1.province_id, (p1.weight * p1.weight) / (p1.height * p1.height) AS bmi FROM patients p1 WHERE (p1.province_id, (p1.weight * p1.weight) / (p1.height * p1.height)) IN ( SELECT province_id, MAX((weight * weight) / (height * height)) AS max_bmi FROM patients GROUP BY province_id);",
    "Option C":
      "SELECT p1.first_name, p1.last_name, p1.province_id, (p1.weight / POWER(p1.height, 2)) AS bmi FROM patients p1 WHERE (p1.province_id, p1.weight / POWER(p1.height, 2)) IN ( SELECT province_id, MAX(weight / POWER(height, 2)) AS max_bmi FROM patients GROUP BY province_id );",
    "Option D":
      "SELECT p1.first_name, p1.last_name, p1.province_id, (p1.weight * p1.weight) / POWER(p1.height, 2) AS bmi FROM patients p1 WHERE (p1.province_id, (p1.weight * p1.weight) / POWER(p1.height, 2)) IN ( SELECT province_id, MAX((weight * weight) / POWER(height, 2)) AS max_bmi FROM patients GROUP BY province_id);",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      'Conside the Following Functional Dependency Patient_id → First_name, Last_name, Gender, Birth_date, City, Province_id, Allergies, Height, Weight  Write an SQL query to find the patient with the highest number of allergies in the "patients" table. Return the patient\'s first name, last name, and the count of allergies. ',
    "Option A":
      "SELECT first_name, last_name, COUNT(allergies) AS allergy_count FROM patients WHERE allergies IS NOT NULL GROUP BY first_name, last_name ORDER BY allergy_count ASC LIMIT 1;",
    "Option B":
      "SELECT first_name, last_name, COUNT(allergies) AS allergy_count FROM patients WHERE allergies IS NOT NULL GROUP BY first_name, last_name HAVING allergy_count = MAX(allergy_count);",
    "Option C":
      "SELECT first_name, last_name, COUNT(allergies) AS allergy_count FROM patients WHERE allergies IS NOT NULL GROUP BY first_name, last_name ORDER BY allergy_count DESC LIMIT 1;",
    "Option D":
      "SELECT first_name, last_name, COUNT(allergies) AS allergy_count FROM patients WHERE allergies IS NOT NULL GROUP BY first_name, last_name ORDER BY allergy_count DESC;",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      'Conside the Following Functional Dependency Patient_id → First_name, Last_name, Gender, Birth_date, City, Province_id, Allergies, Height, Weight  Write an SQL query to determine the percentage of female patients in each city of the "patients" table. Calculate the percentage based on the total number of patients in the city. ',
    "Option A":
      "SELECT city, (COUNT() * 100 / (SELECT COUNT() FROM patients WHERE city = p.city)) AS female_percentage FROM patients p WHERE gender = 'F' ORDER BY female_percentage DESC; ",
    "Option B":
      "SELECT city, (COUNT() * 100 / (SELECT COUNT() FROM patients WHERE city = p.city)) AS female_percentage FROM patients p GROUP BY city; ",
    "Option C":
      "SELECT city, (COUNT() * 100 / (SELECT COUNT() FROM patients WHERE city = p.city)) AS female_percentage FROM patients p GROUP BY city ORDER BY female_percentage DESC;",
    "Option D":
      "SELECT city, (COUNT() * 100 / (SELECT COUNT() FROM patients WHERE city = p.city)) AS female_percentage FROM patients p WHERE gender = 'F' GROUP BY city;",
    Answer: 4,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      'Conside the Following Functional Dependency Patient_id → First_name, Last_name, Gender, Birth_date, City, Province_id, Allergies, Height, Weight  Write an SQL query to identify the province that has the highest average height among patients who do not have any allergies in the "patients" table. Include the province ID and the computed average height. ',
    "Option A":
      "SELECT province_id, AVG(height) AS avg_height FROM patients WHERE allergies IS NULL GROUP BY province_id ORDER BY avg_height DESC LIMIT 1;",
    "Option B":
      "SELECT province_id, AVG(height) AS avg_height FROM patients WHERE allergies IS NULL GROUP BY province_id ORDER BY avg_height ASC LIMIT 1;",
    "Option C":
      "SELECT province_id, AVG(height) AS avg_height FROM patients WHERE allergies IS NULL GROUP BY province_id HAVING avg_height = MAX(avg_height);",
    "Option D":
      "SELECT province_id, AVG(height) AS avg_height FROM patients WHERE allergies IS NULL GROUP BY province_id ORDER BY avg_height DESC;",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Retrieve the names of authors who have written books with more available copies than the average available copies of all books in the library.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id = (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies > (SELECT AVG(available_copies) FROM Books))",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies > (SELECT AVG(available_copies) FROM Books))",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies >= (SELECT AVG(available_copies) FROM Books))",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id = (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies >= (SELECT AVG(available_copies) FROM Books))",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Find the titles of books that were borrowed before any book by a specific author.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id = (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrow_date < ALL (SELECT borrow_date FROM Borrowers WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id])))",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrow_date < ALL (SELECT borrow_date FROM Borrowers WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id])))",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id = (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrow_date < ANY (SELECT borrow_date FROM Borrowers WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id])))",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrow_date < ANY (SELECT borrow_date FROM Borrowers WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id])))",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    List the authors who have written books that were never borrowed.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books)",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Borrowers WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books))",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Borrowers WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books))",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers))",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Find the titles of books borrowed by a borrower named 'John' on the same day they were borrowed.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id = (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_id = (SELECT borrower_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'John') AND borrow_date = return_date)",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_id = (SELECT borrower_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'John') AND borrow_date = return_date)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id = (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_id = (SELECT borrower_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'John') AND borrow_date = borrow_date)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_id = (SELECT borrower_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'John') AND borrow_date = borrow_date)",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Get the titles of books borrowed by a borrower whose name contains 'Smith'.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT B.title FROM Books AS B JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id WHERE Br.borrower_name = 'Smith'",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT B.title FROM Books AS B JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id WHERE Br.borrower_name LIKE '%Smith%'",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT B.title FROM Books AS B JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id WHERE Br.borrower_name = '%Smith%'",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT B.title FROM Books AS B JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id WHERE Br.borrower_name = 'Smith%'",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Retrieve the names of authors and the titles of their books.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT A.author_name, B.title FROM Authors AS A JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT A.author_name, B.title FROM Authors AS A LEFT JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT A.author_name, B.title FROM Authors AS A RIGHT JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT A.author_name, B.title FROM Authors AS A FULL JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    List the borrowers who borrowed books and include the author's name for each borrowed book.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name, B.title, A.author_name FROM Borrowers AS Br JOIN Books AS B ON Br.book_id = B.book_id LEFT JOIN Authors AS A ON B.author_id = A.author_id",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name, B.title, A.author_name FROM Borrowers AS Br JOIN Books AS B ON Br.book_id = B.book_id",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name, B.title, A.author_name FROM Borrowers AS Br LEFT JOIN Books AS B ON Br.book_id = B.book_id JOIN Authors AS A ON B.author_id = A.author_id",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name, B.title, A.author_name FROM Borrowers AS Br FULL JOIN Books AS B ON Br.book_id = B.book_id JOIN Authors AS A ON B.author_id = A.author_id",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Find the titles of books borrowed by borrowers with a specific name.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT B.title FROM Books AS B JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id WHERE Br.borrower_name = 'John'",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT B.title FROM Books AS B JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id WHERE Br.borrower_name LIKE 'John'",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT B.title FROM Books AS B JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id WHERE Br.borrower_name = '%John%'",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT B.title FROM Books AS B JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id WHERE Br.borrower_name LIKE '%John%'",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Retrieve the authors and the total number of copies of their books available in the library.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT A.author_name, COUNT(B.available_copies) AS total_available_copies FROM Authors AS A JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id GROUP BY A.author_name",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT A.author_name, SUM(B.available_copies) AS total_available_copies FROM Authors AS A JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id GROUP BY A.author_name",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT A.author_name, AVG(B.available_copies) AS total_available_copies FROM Authors AS A JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id GROUP BY A.author_name",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT A.author_name, MAX(B.available_copies) AS total_available_copies FROM Authors AS A JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id GROUP BY A.author_name",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    List the borrowers who have borrowed multiple books, along with the titles of those books.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name, B.title FROM Borrowers AS Br JOIN Books AS B ON Br.book_id = B.book_id GROUP BY Br.borrower_name, B.title HAVING COUNT(B.book_id) = 1",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name, B.title FROM Borrowers AS Br JOIN Books AS B ON Br.book_id = B.book_id GROUP BY Br.borrower_name, B.title HAVING COUNT(B.book_id) > 1",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name, B.title FROM Borrowers AS Br JOIN Books AS B ON Br.book_id = B.book_id GROUP BY Br.borrower_name, B.title",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name, B.title FROM Borrowers AS Br JOIN Books AS B ON Br.book_id = B.book_id GROUP BY Br.borrower_name HAVING COUNT(B.book_id) > 1",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Find the titles of books that were borrowed and returned.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NULL)",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NOT NULL)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NULL)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NOT NULL)",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    List the books that have never been borrowed.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT DISTINCT book_id FROM Borrowers)",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NULL)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT DISTINCT book_id FROM Borrowers)",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Retrieve the authors who have books available in the library and books that have been borrowed.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id IN (SELECT B.author_id FROM Books AS B)",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id IN (SELECT B.author_id FROM Borrowers AS Br JOIN Books AS B ON Br.book_id = B.book_id)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id IN (SELECT B.author_id FROM Books AS B) AND A.author_id IN (SELECT B.author_id FROM Borrowers AS Br JOIN Books AS B ON Br.book_id = B.book_id)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id NOT IN (SELECT B.author_id FROM Books AS B) AND A.author_id NOT IN (SELECT B.author_id FROM Borrowers AS Br JOIN Books AS B ON Br.book_id = B.book_id)",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Get the titles of books that were borrowed by more than one borrower.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers GROUP BY book_id HAVING COUNT(borrower_id) = 1)",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers GROUP BY book_id HAVING COUNT(borrower_id) > 1)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers GROUP BY book_id HAVING COUNT(*) = 1)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers GROUP BY book_id HAVING COUNT(*) > 1)",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Find the names of borrowers who have borrowed books written by specific authors.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT DISTINCT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id])",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT DISTINCT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id]) AND Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NOT NULL)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT DISTINCT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id]) OR Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NULL)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT DISTINCT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id]) OR Br.borrower_name IN (SELECT DISTINCT borrower_name FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NULL)",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Retrieve the authors who have books available in the library and books that have been borrowed but are not written by the same author.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id IN (SELECT B.author_id FROM Books AS B)",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id IN (SELECT B.author_id FROM Borrowers AS Br JOIN Books AS B ON Br.book_id = B.book_id)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id IN (SELECT B.author_id FROM Books AS B) AND A.author_id IN (SELECT B.author_id FROM Borrowers AS Br JOIN Books AS B ON Br.book_id = B.book_id)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id NOT IN (SELECT B.author_id FROM Books AS B) AND A.author_id NOT IN (SELECT B.author_id FROM Borrowers AS Br JOIN Books AS B ON Br.book_id = B.book_id)",
    Answer: 4,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    List the books that are either available in the library or were borrowed by a borrower named 'Alice.'",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Alice') OR book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books)",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Alice') AND book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name <> 'Alice') OR book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Alice') OR book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books)",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Find the borrowers who borrowed books with a specific title or borrowed books from a specific author.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT DISTINCT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE title = 'Specific Title') OR Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id])",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT DISTINCT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE title = 'Specific Title') AND Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id])",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT DISTINCT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE title <> 'Specific Title') OR Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id <> [author_id])",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT DISTINCT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE title = 'Specific Title') AND Br.borrower_name NOT IN (SELECT DISTINCT borrower_name FROM Borrowers WHERE author_id = [author_id])",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Get the titles of books that were borrowed and returned, or have more available copies than the average.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NULL) OR available_copies > (SELECT AVG(available_copies) FROM Books)",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NOT NULL) AND available_copies > (SELECT AVG(available_copies) FROM Books)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NULL) OR available_copies > (SELECT AVG(available_copies) FROM Books)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NOT NULL) AND available_copies > (SELECT AVG(available_copies) FROM Books)",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    List the borrowers who borrowed books but have not yet returned them and were not written by a specific author.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id <> [author_id]) AND Br.book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NOT NULL)",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id]) AND Br.borrower_name NOT IN (SELECT DISTINCT borrower_name FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NOT NULL)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id]) AND Br.borrower_name NOT IN (SELECT DISTINCT borrower_name FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NOT NULL)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id <> [author_id]) OR Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE return_date IS NOT NULL)",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Retrieve the authors who have never written a book with more than 10 available copies in the library.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies > 10)",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies > 10)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies <= 10)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies <= 10)",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Find the titles of books that have been borrowed by the same borrower more than once on different dates.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers GROUP BY book_id, borrower_id HAVING COUNT(borrower_id) > 1)",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers GROUP BY book_id, borrower_id HAVING COUNT(DISTINCT borrow_date) > 1)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers GROUP BY book_id HAVING COUNT(DISTINCT borrower_id) > 1)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers GROUP BY book_id, borrower_id HAVING COUNT(borrow_date) > 1)",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    List the authors who have written books that were borrowed by more than one borrower, and the total number of borrowers for each book.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT A.author_name, B.title, COUNT(DISTINCT Br.borrower_id) AS total_borrowers FROM Authors AS A JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id GROUP BY A.author_name, B.title HAVING COUNT(DISTINCT Br.borrower_id) > 1",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT A.author_name, B.title, COUNT(DISTINCT Br.borrower_id) AS total_borrowers FROM Authors AS A JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id GROUP BY A.author_name, B.title HAVING COUNT(DISTINCT Br.borrower_id) = 1",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT A.author_name, B.title, COUNT(DISTINCT Br.borrower_id) AS total_borrowers FROM Authors AS A JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id GROUP BY A.author_name, B.title",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT A.author_name, B.title, COUNT(DISTINCT Br.borrower_id) AS total_borrowers FROM Authors AS A JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id GROUP BY A.author_name, B.title HAVING COUNT(DISTINCT Br.borrower_id) > 1",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Find the titles of books that were borrowed by more than one borrower with the same name.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers GROUP BY book_id, borrower_name HAVING COUNT(borrower_name) > 1)",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers GROUP BY book_id, borrower_name HAVING COUNT(borrower_name) = 1)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers GROUP BY book_id, borrower_name HAVING COUNT(DISTINCT borrower_id) > 1)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers GROUP BY book_id, borrower_name HAVING COUNT(DISTINCT borrower_id) = 1)",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Retrieve the names of authors who have written books borrowed by a borrower named 'Alice' but not by a borrower named 'Bob.'",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Alice')) AND author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Bob'))",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Alice')) AND author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Bob'))",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Alice')) AND author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Bob'))",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Alice')) OR author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Bob'))",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    List the borrowers who borrowed books that have more available copies than the average available copies of books written by their corresponding authors.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies > (SELECT AVG(B1.available_copies) FROM Books AS B1 WHERE B1.author_id = (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id = Br.book_id)))",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies > (SELECT AVG(available_copies) FROM Books))",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies > (SELECT AVG(B1.available_copies) FROM Books AS B1 WHERE B1.author_id = (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id = Br.book_id)))",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies > (SELECT AVG(available_copies) FROM Books))",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Retrieve the names of borrowers who have borrowed the same book more than once with a different return date.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_id = Br.borrower_id GROUP BY book_id HAVING COUNT(DISTINCT return_date) > 1)",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_id = Br.borrower_id GROUP BY book_id HAVING COUNT(return_date) > 1)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_id = Br.borrower_id GROUP BY book_id HAVING COUNT(DISTINCT return_date) > 1)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_id = Br.borrower_id GROUP BY book_id HAVING COUNT(return_date) > 1)",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    List the authors who have written books that have never been borrowed by a borrower with the name 'David.'",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'David'))",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'David'))",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'David'))",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'David'))",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Find the names of borrowers who have borrowed books on a date that is earlier than the date any book was published by a specific author.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.borrow_date < (SELECT MIN(publish_date) FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id])",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.borrow_date < (SELECT MAX(publish_date) FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id])",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.borrow_date < (SELECT AVG(publish_date) FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id])",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.borrow_date < (SELECT publish_date FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id] LIMIT 1)",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Get the names of borrowers who have borrowed more books than the average number of books borrowed by all borrowers.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br GROUP BY Br.borrower_name HAVING COUNT(Br.book_id) > (SELECT AVG(book_count) FROM (SELECT COUNT(book_id) AS book_count FROM Borrowers GROUP BY borrower_name) AS AvgCount)",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br GROUP BY Br.borrower_name HAVING COUNT(Br.book_id) < (SELECT AVG(book_count) FROM (SELECT COUNT(book_id) AS book_count FROM Borrowers GROUP BY borrower_name) AS AvgCount)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br GROUP BY Br.borrower_name HAVING COUNT(Br.book_id) = (SELECT AVG(book_count) FROM (SELECT COUNT(book_id) AS book_count FROM Borrowers GROUP BY borrower_name) AS AvgCount)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br GROUP BY Br.borrower_name HAVING COUNT(Br.book_id) > (SELECT AVG(book_count) FROM (SELECT COUNT(book_id) AS book_count FROM Borrowers GROUP BY borrower_name) AS AvgCount)",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Retrieve the titles of books that have been borrowed and returned more than once, along with the total number of times they were borrowed and returned.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT title, COUNT(Br.book_id) AS total_borrow_return FROM Books AS B JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id WHERE Br.return_date IS NOT NULL GROUP BY B.title HAVING COUNT(Br.book_id) > 1",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT title, COUNT(Br.book_id) AS total_borrow_return FROM Books AS B JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id WHERE Br.return_date IS NOT NULL GROUP BY B.title HAVING COUNT(Br.book_id) = 1",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT title, COUNT(Br.book_id) AS total_borrow_return FROM Books AS B JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id WHERE Br.return_date IS NOT NULL GROUP BY B.title",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT title, COUNT(Br.book_id) AS total_borrow_return FROM Books AS B JOIN Borrowers AS Br ON B.book_id = Br.book_id WHERE Br.return_date IS NULL GROUP BY B.title HAVING COUNT(Br.book_id) > 1",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    List the authors who have not written any books that have been borrowed by borrowers with the name 'Mary' on the same day.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Mary' AND borrow_date = [specific_date]))",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Mary' AND borrow_date = [specific_date]))",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Mary' AND borrow_date = [specific_date]))",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Mary' AND borrow_date = [specific_date]))",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Find the authors who have written books borrowed by borrowers with names that contain the letter 'Z,' and display the titles of those books.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT A.author_name, B.title FROM Authors AS A JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id WHERE B.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name LIKE '%Z%')",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT A.author_name, B.title FROM Authors AS A JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id WHERE B.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Z')",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT A.author_name, B.title FROM Authors AS A JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id WHERE B.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name LIKE 'Z')",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT A.author_name, B.title FROM Authors AS A JOIN Books AS B ON A.author_id = B.author_id WHERE B.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Z')",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Retrieve the titles of books that have been borrowed by borrowers who have also borrowed books by a specific author.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_id IN (SELECT borrower_id FROM Borrowers WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id])))",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_id IN (SELECT borrower_id FROM Borrowers WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id <> [author_id])))",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_id NOT IN (SELECT borrower_id FROM Borrowers WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id])))",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_id NOT IN (SELECT borrower_id FROM Borrowers WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id <> [author_id])))",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    List the borrowers who have borrowed books from authors who have not written any books with more than 5 available copies.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies > 5))",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies <= 5))",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies > 5))",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies <= 5))",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Retrieve the names of borrowers who have borrowed books with titles that contain the word 'Database' and were published in the same year as a book written by a specific author.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE title LIKE '%Database%' AND EXTRACT(YEAR FROM publish_date) = (SELECT EXTRACT(YEAR FROM publish_date) FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id]))",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE title LIKE '%Database%' AND EXTRACT(YEAR FROM publish_date) = (SELECT EXTRACT(YEAR FROM publish_date) FROM Books WHERE author_id <> [author_id]))",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE title LIKE '%Database%' AND EXTRACT(YEAR FROM publish_date) = (SELECT EXTRACT(YEAR FROM publish_date) FROM Books WHERE author_id = [author_id]))",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE title LIKE '%Database%' AND EXTRACT(YEAR FROM publish_date) = (SELECT EXTRACT(YEAR FROM publish_date) FROM Books WHERE author_id <> [author_id]))",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Find the authors who have written books that have never been borrowed by any borrower.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers))",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers))",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers))",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT author_name FROM Authors WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers))",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Retrieve the titles of books that have been borrowed by all borrowers.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers GROUP BY book_id HAVING COUNT(DISTINCT borrower_id) = (SELECT COUNT(DISTINCT borrower_id) FROM Borrowers))",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers)",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers GROUP BY book_id HAVING COUNT(DISTINCT borrower_id) > 1)",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT title FROM Books WHERE book_id NOT IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers GROUP BY book_id HAVING COUNT(DISTINCT borrower_id) = (SELECT COUNT(DISTINCT borrower_id) FROM Borrowers))",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    List the authors who have written books borrowed by borrowers named 'John' and 'Jane,' but not borrowed by 'Alice' or 'Bob.'",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'John')) AND A.author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Jane')) AND A.author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Alice')) AND A.author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Bob'))",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'John')) AND A.author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Jane')) OR A.author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Alice')) OR A.author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Bob'))",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'John')) OR A.author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Jane')) OR A.author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Alice')) OR A.author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Bob'))",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT A.author_name FROM Authors AS A WHERE A.author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'John')) OR A.author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Jane')) AND A.author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Alice')) AND A.author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Borrowers WHERE borrower_name = 'Bob'))",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Consider the Library Database with Following tables\n\nBooks (book_id: Numeric PK, title: String, author_id: Numeric FK to Authors, available_copies: Numeric)\nAuthors (author_id: Numeric PK, author_name: String)\nBorrowers (borrower_id: Numeric PK, borrower_name: String, book_id: Numeric FK to Books, borrow_date: Date, return_date: Date)    Retrieve the names of borrowers who have borrowed books by an author who has never written a book with more than 3 available copies in the library.",
    "Option A":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies > 3)))",
    "Option B":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies <= 3)))",
    "Option C":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies > 3)))",
    "Option D":
      " SELECT Br.borrower_name FROM Borrowers AS Br WHERE Br.book_id IN (SELECT book_id FROM Books WHERE author_id IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE author_id NOT IN (SELECT author_id FROM Books WHERE available_copies <= 3)))",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL CONCEPT",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " A company wants to secure its sensitive customer data. Which of the following mechanisms is most appropriate for data encryption at rest in a relational database?",
    "Option A": " TLS/SSL",
    "Option B": " Data masking",
    "Option C": " Transparent Data Encryption (TDE)",
    "Option D": " Row-level security",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "Database Security",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " An organization needs to ensure that only authorized users can access the database. Which of the following authentication methods provides the highest level of security?",
    "Option A": " Using weak passwords",
    "Option B": " Multi-factor authentication (MFA)",
    "Option C": " No authentication",
    "Option D": " Single sign-on (SSO)",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "Database Security",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " In a scenario where a database administrator is configuring user access, what principle of least privilege refers to?",
    "Option A": " Granting users the maximum possible permissions",
    "Option B":
      " Assigning users the minimum permissions necessary to perform their job",
    "Option C": " Using the same password for all users",
    "Option D": " Storing passwords in plain text",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "Database Security",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " A database stores credit card information, and the organization must comply with PCI DSS (Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard). What is the best practice for handling credit card data in the database?",
    "Option A": " Store full credit card numbers with no encryption",
    "Option B": " Avoid storing credit card data entirely",
    "Option C": " Store hashed or tokenized credit card data",
    "Option D": " Share credit card data openly within the organization",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "Database Security",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " In a large organization, the database administrator needs to track all changes to sensitive tables. What database security feature provides this capability by recording who accessed the data and when?",
    "Option A": " Access Control Lists (ACL)",
    "Option B": " Auditing and Database Activity Monitoring",
    "Option C": " Role-based access control",
    "Option D": " Public keys",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "Database Security",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " An organization is concerned about SQL injection attacks on their database-driven web applications. Which practice can help prevent SQL injection?",
    "Option A": " Disable all security features",
    "Option B": " Use prepared statements or parameterized queries",
    "Option C": " Store database credentials in plain text",
    "Option D": " Share the same database user account for all applications",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "Database Security",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " A database administrator is implementing data classification for the organization's sensitive information. Which classification level involves data that is highly confidential and requires the strictest access controls?",
    "Option A": " Public data",
    "Option B": " Private data",
    "Option C": " Sensitive data",
    "Option D": " Unclassified data",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "Database Security",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " In a scenario where a company has a disaster recovery site for its database, what type of security mechanism ensures that data is secure during replication and transfer between sites?",
    "Option A": " Firewalls",
    "Option B": " Virtual Private Networks (VPNs)",
    "Option C": " Secure Socket Layer (SSL)",
    "Option D": " Data encryption in transit",
    Answer: 4,
    Topic: "Database Security",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " You are developing an e-commerce application. A customer adds items to their shopping cart, and you want to ensure that their cart data is consistent throughout the shopping process. Which SQL transaction isolation level should you use to prevent other users from seeing the customer's cart contents during the transaction?",
    "Option A": "READ UNCOMMITTED",
    "Option B": "READ COMMITTED",
    "Option C": "SERIALIZABLE",
    "Option D": "REPEATABLE READ",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "SQL Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " In a banking system, a customer is transferring money from their checking account to a savings account. During the transaction, the customer's balance should be updated atomically. Which SQL statement should be used to ensure the integrity of this operation?",
    "Option A": "INSERT",
    "Option B": "UPDATE",
    "Option C": "COMMIT",
    "Option D": "BEGIN TRANSACTION",
    Answer: 4,
    Topic: "SQL Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " You are working on an inventory management system. A user is trying to update the quantity of a product in the database while another user is simultaneously trying to delete the same product. What transaction isolation level can prevent this scenario?",
    "Option A": "READ UNCOMMITTED",
    "Option B": "READ COMMITTED",
    "Option C": "SERIALIZABLE",
    "Option D": "REPEATABLE READ",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "SQL Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " A database system uses the Two-Phase Commit (2PC) protocol to manage distributed transactions. What is the purpose of the first phase in 2PC?",
    "Option A": "To obtain locks on the participating data",
    "Option B": "To prepare all participants to commit the transaction",
    "Option C": "To roll back the transaction if any participant cannot commit",
    "Option D": "To release locks and finalize the transaction",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " In a banking application, a user is transferring money from their account to another user's account. During the transaction, you want to ensure that either both the debit and credit operations succeed or both fail. Which SQL transaction command should be used to wrap these operations in a transaction?",
    "Option A": "COMMIT",
    "Option B": "ROLLBACK",
    "Option C": "SAVEPOINT",
    "Option D": "BEGIN TRANSACTION",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " In a reservation system, a user is booking tickets for an event, and you want to ensure that no other user can book the same seats while this transaction is in progress. What SQL command should you use to lock the selected seats?",
    "Option A": "LOCK TABLE",
    "Option B": "BEGIN TRANSACTION",
    "Option C": "SET TRANSACTION ISOLATION LEVEL",
    "Option D": "SELECT ... FOR UPDATE",
    Answer: 4,
    Topic: "SQL Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " In a forum application, users are posting comments on a thread. You want to ensure that comments posted by one user are displayed together and don't interleave with comments from other users. What SQL transaction isolation level should you use in this case?",
    "Option A": "READ UNCOMMITTED",
    "Option B": "READ COMMITTED",
    "Option C": "SERIALIZABLE",
    "Option D": "REPEATABLE READ",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " A user is submitting a purchase order in an e-commerce system. You want to ensure that the order is processed entirely, including payment, and that nothing is left in an inconsistent state. What SQL transaction command should you use?",
    "Option A": "BEGIN TRANSACTION",
    "Option B": "LOCK TABLE",
    "Option C": "SAVEPOINT",
    "Option D": "CHECKPOINT",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "SQL Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " You are developing a real-time messaging application. When a user sends a message, you want to ensure that it appears immediately to the recipient but remains invisible to others until the transaction is complete. What SQL transaction isolation level should be used for this operation?",
    "Option A": "READ UNCOMMITTED",
    "Option B": "READ COMMITTED",
    "Option C": "SERIALIZABLE",
    "Option D": "REPEATABLE READ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " In a library management system, a user is borrowing multiple books. You want to ensure that all books are successfully borrowed or none at all. What SQL transaction command should be used to achieve this?",
    "Option A": "COMMIT",
    "Option B": "ROLLBACK",
    "Option C": "SAVEPOINT",
    "Option D": "BEGIN TRANSACTION",
    Answer: 4,
    Topic: "SQL Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " A user is trying to update their profile information in a CRM system. You want to ensure that the user's information remains consistent and locked during the update. What SQL transaction isolation level should be used for this operation?",
    "Option A": "READ UNCOMMITTED",
    "Option B": "READ COMMITTED",
    "Option C": "SERIALIZABLE",
    "Option D": "REPEATABLE READ",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "SQL Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " You are implementing a point-of-sale system for a retail store. During a sales transaction, you need to ensure that both the deduction from the inventory and the charging of the customer's account occur successfully. What SQL transaction command should you use to achieve this?",
    "Option A": "COMMIT",
    "Option B": "ROLLBACK",
    "Option C": "SAVEPOINT",
    "Option D": "BEGIN TRANSACTION",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " You are developing a reservation system for booking airline tickets. During the reservation process, you want to ensure that the seats being reserved are locked and unavailable for other users. What SQL command should you use to achieve this?",
    "Option A": "LOCK TABLE",
    "Option B": "BEGIN TRANSACTION",
    "Option C": "SET TRANSACTION ISOLATION LEVEL",
    "Option D": "SELECT ... FOR UPDATE",
    Answer: 4,
    Topic: "SQL Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " In a stock trading system, a user is placing an order to buy a certain number of shares at a specific price. You want to ensure that no other user can execute an order for the same shares simultaneously. What kind of lock or constraint should be used in this scenario?",
    "Option A": "Shared lock",
    "Option B": "Exclusive lock",
    "Option C": "Unique constraint",
    "Option D": "Check constraint",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " You are building a real-time messaging application. When a user sends a message, you want to ensure that it appears immediately to the recipient but remains invisible to others until the transaction is complete. What SQL transaction isolation level should be used for this operation?",
    "Option A": "READ UNCOMMITTED",
    "Option B": "READ COMMITTED",
    "Option C": "SERIALIZABLE",
    "Option D": "REPEATABLE READ",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "SQL Transactions",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " In a database system, what is the primary goal of recovery management?",
    "Option A": " Data encryption",
    "Option B": " Data security",
    "Option C": " Data availability",
    "Option D": " Data replication",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " After a system crash, a database needs to be restored to its previous state using transaction logs. What is the term for this process?",
    "Option A": " Backup",
    "Option B": " Rollback",
    "Option C": " Recovery",
    "Option D": " Replication",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " In database recovery, what does the term Point-in-Time Recovery refer to?",
    "Option A": " Recovering to the current time",
    "Option B": " Recovering to the last backup",
    "Option C": " Recovering to a specific time in the past",
    "Option D": " Recovering without logs",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " During a recovery process, a database administrator needs to identify the transactions that were in progress when a failure occurred. What is this step called?",
    "Option A": " Rollback",
    "Option B": " Redo",
    "Option C": " Undo",
    "Option D": " Checkpoint",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " When restoring a database, what does the term Full Recovery Model mean in the context of Microsoft SQL Server?",
    "Option A": " Only full backups are used for recovery",
    "Option B": " All transaction logs are retained for recovery",
    "Option C": " Only specific tables are recovered",
    "Option D": " No recovery options are available",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " In a database recovery scenario, what is the purpose of a checkpoint?",
    "Option A": " To undo changes made by transactions",
    "Option B": " To ensure data integrity during recovery",
    "Option C": " To record transactions for future recovery",
    "Option D": " To mark a point in the log from which recovery can start",
    Answer: 4,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " A database system uses a physical backup of the database files for recovery. What is the term for this type of backup?",
    "Option A": " Logical backup",
    "Option B": " Differential backup",
    "Option C": " Incremental backup",
    "Option D": " Full backup",
    Answer: 4,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " After a power outage, a database needs to be restored to its previous state. What type of recovery is typically required in this scenario?",
    "Option A": " Point-in-Time Recovery",
    "Option B": " Full Recovery",
    "Option C": " Crash Recovery",
    "Option D": " Partial Recovery",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question: " In a disaster recovery plan, what does RTO stand for?",
    "Option A": " Recovery Time Objective",
    "Option B": " Recovery Test Operation",
    "Option C": " Recovery Technical Overview",
    "Option D": " Recovery Tracking Order",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " During database recovery, what is the purpose of the redo log or roll-forward phase?",
    "Option A": " To undo transactions that were incomplete",
    "Option B": " To apply committed transactions to restore the database",
    "Option C": " To roll back the database to a previous state",
    "Option D": " To validate user privileges",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question: " In a disaster recovery scenario, what does RPO stand for?",
    "Option A": " Recovery Plan Outline",
    "Option B": " Recovery Point Objective",
    "Option C": " Recovery Process Overview",
    "Option D": " Recovery Performance Optimization",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " In a database recovery process, what is the primary role of a shadow copy or snapshot?",
    "Option A": " To create a physical backup",
    "Option B": " To provide a read-only copy of the database",
    "Option C": " To store transaction logs",
    "Option D": " To recover to a specific point in time",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " What recovery method would you use if you need to restore a database to a specific date and time in the past?",
    "Option A": " Full Recovery",
    "Option B": " Crash Recovery",
    "Option C": " Point-in-Time Recovery",
    "Option D": " Rollback Recovery",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " In the context of database recovery, what is the purpose of a redo log or transaction log?",
    "Option A": " To track user logins and logouts",
    "Option B": " To store the current state of the database",
    "Option C": " To record all committed changes made to the database",
    "Option D": " To recover lost data from backups",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " During database recovery, what is the undo log or rollback phase used for?",
    "Option A": " To recover the database to a specific point in time",
    "Option B": " To apply committed transactions to restore the database",
    "Option C":
      " To undo incomplete transactions and restore the previous state",
    "Option D": " To make the database read-only",
    Answer: 3,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " What is the primary goal of a recovery plan in the context of database recovery?",
    "Option A": " To prevent data loss",
    "Option B": " To create backups",
    "Option C": " To improve database performance",
    "Option D": " To create new tables",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question: " In a database recovery scenario, what does MTTR stand for?",
    "Option A": " Mean Time to Recovery",
    "Option B": " Maximum Time to Recovery",
    "Option C": " Minimum Time to Recovery",
    "Option D": " Master Time to Recovery",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question: " What is the role of a data backup in database recovery?",
    "Option A": " To restore the database to a previous state",
    "Option B": " To provide a read-only copy of the database",
    "Option C": " To store transaction logs",
    "Option D": " To recover data lost due to user errors",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question:
      " After a database failure, which type of recovery process is needed when you have a full backup and all transaction logs since the backup?",
    "Option A": " Point-in-Time Recovery",
    "Option B": " Full Recovery",
    "Option C": " Crash Recovery",
    "Option D": " Rollback Recovery",
    Answer: 2,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
  {
    Question: " In a database recovery scenario, what does MTBF stand for?",
    "Option A": " Mean Time Between Failures",
    "Option B": " Maximum Time Before Failure",
    "Option C": " Minimum Time for Backup",
    "Option D": " Master Time for Full Recovery",
    Answer: 1,
    Topic: "Database Recovery",
  },
];
